Hey,
Heat.
Good evening and good day everybody and
welcome to this emergency episode of the
Ask Abijit Show. Uh this was supposed to
be uh an episode in which I take
questions from the comments but uh well
the war has begun. The war that everyone
was anticipating but we didn't know when
it will happen. The Iran war the
American and Israeli attack on Iran
that's happened. It's started sometime
early in earlier in the day and uh yeah
the war is progressing now. So um and
it's it's actually a very very important
event. It's uh one of the events that's
possibly going to define the history of
the world going forward. Yeah. And it's
going to have an effect on everything.
It's going to have an effect on the
United States, on on West Asia. It's
going to have an effect on the Russia
Ukraine conflict. It's going to have an
effect on China. It's going to have a
big effect on India. And there's another
war going on which is Pakistan,
Afghanistan. So this is a time for war.
And now the US and Israel and the US
have attacked Iran today morning. So a
lot is happening and we're going to
discuss that and we're going to keep an
eye on the evolving situation together
for the next uh few hours and I'll take
I'll take questions only about Iran and
the surrounding situation the
geopolitical situation. I will not take
questions about history or or any other
thing today or science or whatever else.
Only questions about Iran and and
geopolitics. So let let's see who all is
there on the live stream. Let's see u
who all is there with us. I can see a
lot of people. Rahul Dunak Achara
Chanaka Kanesh Kakosh Kanesh Koshik Shri
Achandra
Vision VB Sumit Agarwal Mi Rao Manhattan
Lazy Gamer Mac 4 Janu Rahul Dunak Han
Sharma Canel Geopolitical Dubai is here
from Indor. Good evening. Shivasai says
full support to Israel. I know I know I
know what you mean. Raika Jash Ramit Raj
Singh Chadasuma
uh Adit Ashwinir Arasho
okay mystic skayush
Singh is here. Pranam G Rushab T uh
really now Miss Patel hello Balki Balki
today Ashish Tabra Shivasai Somi Karan
Nalawad Jashir Drama Boy
SJ SHSJ who supports Israel Dakwora is
here from Gujarat Rav light Apurva
Anupama Apurva Anupama
Tamo Biswas good evening Swami is here
from Jaipur Patadana Amisha Misha good
evening chat DSP
uh Hensy Penguin good to see you sir
good to see you after a while is back
from future I think uh Mac 4 chat DSP
podcast Punjabi is here online hello
it's me Sean
um who else SJ chat DSP and so many
other people I will not be able to greet
you all individually but uh thank you so
much for being on this live stream love
Achara Aditya Kumar Ram Ashish Vandit
wandit sorry wandit not vand
And yeah, many Israel supporters here.
HCN says Pet Nil DH
um Shank Shank Z says yo Vince Smoke
and everybody else. Okay. Okay. Ka
Mlevin is also here. So what's going on
is the question. I'll take your
questions of course, but let's first
establish what's happened thus far.
Let's take a look at Twitter, shall we?
uh let's take a I've been primarily
looking at what's happening on Twitter
because you get a real time u
information about what's happening if
you if you look at Twitter Twitter seems
to be you know really useful and helpful
in that in that sense uh give me a
second can I can I do it like this I
think yeah this is kind of more useful
perhaps
um okay so or is it is this better
Maybe this is better. Is this better? Is
this better? I think uh we'll do it this
way. How about that? Okay. So, um
Twitter Twitter. Okay. So,
this happened around 11 around
early noon India time just before 12.
Israel says it has launched a preemptive
attack on Iran. Explosions are being
reported in Thran with red alerts
triggered in Israel. Right. So this is
where it began around that time is when
we started getting the news that
something has happened, something has
happened, something is going down. Then
we have Donald Trump and Trump gave out
uh this message this this speech. He
gave an address to the nation and to his
nation and to the world. So let's ask
Grock to Okay, what do we have? What
does Grock have to say about this uh
strong support etc etc.
Transcribe the video content. So, let's
let's see the transcript of this, shall
we? If Grock can do it, I'm sure Grock
can do it. Grock is very capable. Um,
it's searching the web and whatnot. So,
Trump essentially has announced
uh that the the war has begun. So,
here's the full transcription, shall we?
Where is it?
Okay, here's what Trump said. A short
time ago, the United States military
began major combat operations in Iran.
Our objective is to defend the American
people by eliminating imminent threats
from the Iranian regime. A vicious group
of very hard, terrible people. Its
menacing activities directly endanger
the United States, our troops, our bases
overseas, and our allies throughout the
world. For 47 years, the Iranian regime
has chanted death to America and waged
an unending campaign of bloodshed and
mass murder, targeting the United
States, our troops, and the innocent
people in many, many countries. Among
the regime's very first acts was to back
a violent takeover of the US embassy in
Thran, holding dozens of American
hostages for 444 days. In 1983, Iran's
proxies carried out the Marine Barracks
bombing in Beirut that car that killed
241 American military personnel. In
2000, they knew and were probably
involved in the attack with the attack
on the USS. Many died. Iranian forces
killed and maimed hundreds of American
service members in Iraq. The regime's
proxies have continued to launch
countless attacks against American
forces stationed in the Middle East in
recent years, as well as US naval and
commercial vessels and international
shipping lanes. It's been mass terror
and we're not going to put up with it
any longer. From Lebanon to Yemen and
Syria to Iraq, the regime has fun armed,
trained, and funded terrorist militias
that have soaked the earth with blood
and guts. It was Iran's proxy Hamas that
launched the monstrous October 7th
attacks on Israel, slaughtering more
than 10,000 innocent people, including
46 Americans, while taking 12 of our
citizens hostage. It was brutal,
something like the world has never seen
before. Iran is the world's number one
state sponsor of terror, not Pakistan,
apparently. Okay. And just recently
killed tens of thousands of its own
citizens on the street as they
protested. It has always always been the
policy of the United States, in
particular my administration that this
terrorist regime can never have a
nuclear weapon. I'll say it again, they
can never have a nuclear weapon. That's
why in operation midnight hammer last
June, we obliterated the terror regime's
nuclear program at Foro Natans in its
vahan. After that attack, we warned them
never to resume their malicious pursuit
of nuclear weapons and we sought
repeatedly to make a deal. We tried. We
tried. They wanted to do it. We wanted
to do it. They didn't want to do it
again. They want We wanted to do it.
They didn't want to do it. They didn't
know what was happening. They just
wanted to practice evil. Okay. But Iran
refused just as it has for decades and
decades. They rejected every opportunity
to den to renounce their nuclear
ambitions and we can't take it anymore.
Instead, they attempted to rebuild their
nuclear program and to continue
developing long- range missiles that can
now threaten our very good friends and
allies in Europe. Our troops stationed
overseas and could soon reach the
American homeland. Just imagine how
emboldened this regime would be if they
ever had and actually were armed with
nuclear weapons as a means to deliver
their message. For these reasons, the US
military has undertaken a massive and
ongoing operation to prevent this very
wicked, radical dictatorship from
threatening America and our core
national security interests. We're going
to destroy their missiles. We're going
to raise their missile industry to the
ground. It will be totally again
obliterated. We are going to annihilate
their navy. We are going to ensure that
the region's terrorist proxies can never
can no longer destabilize the region of
the world and attack our forces and no
longer use their IEDs or roadside bombs
as they are sometimes called called to
so gravely wound and kill thousands and
thousands of people including many
Americans and we will ensure that Iran
does not obtain a nuclear weapon. It's a
very simple message. They will never
have a nuclear weapon. This regime will
soon learn that no one should challenge
the strength and might of the United
States armed forces. I built and rebuilt
our military in my first administration
and there is no military on earth even
close to its power, strength or
sophistication. My administration has
taken every possible step to minimize
the risk to US personnel in the region.
Even so, I do not make this statement
lightly. The Iranian regime seeks to
kill. The lives of courageous American
heroes may be lost and we have and we
may have casualties that of often
happens in war. But we are doing this
not for now. We are doing this for the
future and it's a noble mission. We pray
for every service member as they
selflessly risk their lives to ensure
that Americans and our children will
never be threatened by a nuclear armed
Iran. We ask God to protect all of our
heroes in harm's way. And we trust that
with this help the men and women of our
the armed forces will prevail. We have
the greatest in the world and they will
prevail. To the members of the Islamic
Revolutionary Guard, the armed forces
and all of the police, I say tonight you
must lay down. I say tonight that you
must lay down your weapons and have
complete immunity or in the alternative
face certain death. So lay down your
arms, you will be treated fairly with
total immunity or you will face certain
death. Finally, to the great proud
people of Iran, I say tonight the hour I
say tonight that the hour of your
freedom is at hand. Stay sheltered.
Don't leave your home. It's very
dangerous outside. Bombs will be
dropping everywhere. Bombs will be dro
dropping everywhere. When we are
finished dropping our bombs, you take
over your government. It will be yours
to take. This will be probably your only
chance for generations.
For many years, you have asked for
America's help, but you never got it. No
president was willing to do what I'm
willing to do tonight. Now, you have a
president who is giving you what you
want. So, let's see how you respond.
America is backing you with overwhelming
strength and devastating force. Now is
the time to seize control of your
destiny and to unleash the prosperous
and glorious future that is close within
your reach. This is the moment for
action. Do not let it pass. May God
bless the brave men and women of
America's armed forces. May God bless
the USA. May God bless you all. Thank
you. So that's Trump's address. He is
What is Trump saying? What did Trump
say? Trump said that this is a regiment
operation. very clearly when we are done
the people of Iran can take over that's
what he is saying this is a region
change operation this is some some
people were asking just now that this is
just a few a few air strikes or whatever
why are you calling this a war see what
Trump said this is the launch the
initiation the beginning of a regime
change operation and the objective is to
end this current regime the current
regime in the objective That's what the
US seeks to do. Okay. Uh so that's the
deal. This is a regime change operation
that's that's ongoing and uh it has been
initiated by Israel but the US Yeah, it
looks like it's going to be a fight to
the finish. So this is just the initial
phases of the war. Now what else do we
have? We have the US Department of War
which is saying operation epic fury. So
they have named this operation epic
fury. The US department of war. What
else do we have? We have Benjamin
Netanyahu who has uh put out a tweet a
few hours ago, four hours ago. Uh I'm
pretty sure that uh the speech is in
Hebrew. So let's see the translation of
uh Mr. Natanyahu tweet. My brothers and
sisters, citizens of Israel, just an
hour ago, Israel and the US embarked on
an operation to remove the existential
threat posed by the terrorist regime in
Iran. I thank our great friend,
President Donald Trump, for his historic
leadership. For 47 years, the
Ayatollah's regime has chanted death to
Israel and death to America. It has
spilled our blood, murdered many
Americans, and massacred its own people.
This murderous terrorist regime must not
be allowed to arm itself
with nuclear weapons that would enable
it to threaten all of humanity. Our
joint operation will create the
conditions for the brave Iranian people
to take their fate in their own own
hands. The time has come for all parts
of the Iranian people. the Persians,
Kurs, Azeris, Balo, Aawazis
to cast off the yoke of tyranny and
bring freedom and peace values to Iran.
I call on you people of Israel to heed
the instructions of the homeront
command. In the coming days during
Operation Lions Roar, we will all be
called upon to show patience and
strength of spirit. Together we will
stand. Together we will fight and
together we will ensure the eternity of
Israel. So that's the statement by Prime
Minister Nathan Yahu of Israel.
Uh that's 4 hours ago. So it's very
clear this is the beginning of a war.
The US and the and Israel are working
together. They're working together and
the objective is to end this regime. The
objective is to change the regime in
Iran. This is the beginning of a war.
It's not a few limited air strikes or
missile strikes. Uh our MEA, what does
our MEA have to say about about this?
Has our MEA made any statement? Uh this
is the official MEA account on Twitter.
Uh Dr. Jashankar is talking about some
India EU stuff.
India in Israel has put out an advisory
in view of the prevailing situation in
the region. Okay. Indian nationals are
are asked to exercise full utmost
caution and remain vigilant
and so on. So this is so if you are in
in Israel, if you're an Indian national
in Israel, take a look at the this
statement by the uh Indian embassy in
Israel.
This is an advisory
from the Indian embassy in Thran. So
once again, if you're in Thran for
whatever reason, well, please pay
attention to what the the embassy of
India has to say. Uh and uh yeah,
whatever else, not a lot happening here.
What else do we have? Syri Muhammad
Marandi uh
he says if I'm targeted please receive
your information from sources that are
follow Twitter. So yeah uh this is a
statement by the Kingdom of Saudi Arabia
the foreign ministry. The Kingdom of
Saudi Arabia condemns and denounces in
strongest terms the blatant Iranian
aggression and the flagrant violation of
the sovereignty of the UAE, Bahrain,
Qatar, Kuwait and Jordan. The kingdom
affirms its full solidarity and
unwavering support for the brotherly
countries and its readiness to place all
its capabilities at their disposal in
support of any measures they may
undertake. This also it also warns of
the grave consequences resulting from
the continued violation of the state's
sovereignty and the principles of
international law.
Um yeah, Saudi airspace may be part of
this operation. So international law.
Okay. And this is a statement from the
first statement from the Supreme
National Council of the Islamic Republic
of Iran. This statement uh h was put out
about 3 hours ago in the name of Gore
etc. This morning the courageous nation
of Iran witnessed an aerial operation
carried out by the brutal regime of the
US in collaboration with the what they
call the corrupt Zionist regime
targeting certain locations within the
country. This malicious act took place
once again during the course of
negotiations because negotiations are
ongoing in Janev in in Switzerland. uh
Geneva uh during the course of
negotiations reflecting the enemy's
mistaken belief that the steadfast
nature of Iran would surrender to their
ignorable demands through such cowardly
actions. The armed forces of the Islamic
Republic of Iran have commenced a
decisive response to these hostile acts
and will continuously keep the honorable
people informed. The following points
should be noted. According to the
information obtained regarding the plans
of these two corrupt regimes, their
operations in Thran and certain other
cities are expected to continue. Yes,
obviously if you look at the statement
of Donald Trump and if you look at the
statement of Benjamin Netanyahu, it's
clear this at the beginning of the war,
the beginning of the regime change
operation. Uh so these operations are
expected to continue. Therefore, while
maintaining calm, citizens are advised
where possible to travel to other areas
of or or cities accessible to them in
order to remain safe from the
aggressions of these two regimes.
They're saying go out of the Haram.
Essentially, that's what they're saying.
The government of the Islamic Republic
Republic of Iran has made prior
arrangements to ensure the provision of
the essential needs of society. There is
no cause for concern regarding the
supply of basic necessities. Citizens
are requested to refrain from crow
crowding shopping centers as such
gatherings may pose potential risks.
Schools and universities will remain
closed until further notice. Banks will
continue to provide services to the
noble people of Iran. Government offices
will operate at 50% capacity for the
time being. Further reports will be
announced in due course and so on. This
is uh from Iran in India.
So that's kind of where we are right
now. Now if we can continue to monitor
Twitter and and see what's happening.
Um is there any statement from China?
Uh
we'll we'll look into that. So that is
what's happening. The this is the
beginning of a regime change operation,
a joint regime change operation by the
United States and Israel. The objective
is to remove the current government that
that runs that that rules Iran. The
objective is to change the regime.
That's where we are. And this obviously
u is going to have is going to be very
consequential for India. There's also
another war going on right now in
India's backyard in India's neighborhood
that is Afghanistan and Pakistan. Right.
The Pakistan has launched an air strike,
multiple air strikes on Afghanistan and
the Afghan government is has responded.
So there is border warfare happening
between Afghanistan and Pakistan. The
Afghanistan apparently has shot down a
few Pakistani fighter planes. They've
dropped bomb bombs in Karachi and
Islamabad and whatnot. Right? So there's
escalation there.
Uh the question is uh what is Pakistan's
involvement going to be in the Iran Iran
regime change operation in the war on
Iran? Will Pakistan allow uh its
airspace to be used by by the United
States uh in the war against Iran?
Right. Um why is there a war happening
between Afghanistan and Pakistan? Is it
is it is it does it have something to do
with the American desire to regain
control of the Bram air base?
What does India have to do in in all of
this? What does what is India's role in
this? Some people are saying it's time
to resume operation Synindur 2.0. You
know, start operation Zindur 2.0. and
and you know achieve our uh military and
political objectives in Pakistan. Is
that something that's on the cards? So
these are the questions that we have
right now. Now let me see what questions
people have asked thus far. Let's see.
Hani Sharma says first US proxy Pakistan
did a brave attack on defenseless
Afghanistan and then Israel and the US
launched multiple missile strikes in
Thran including Ali Khabi's house as
well. uh why does the US regime
destabilize the region continued
uh and if they are surely going to do a
regime change in Iran then why do they
need Bram for which Pakistan is fighting
Afghanistan and if that is strategically
important why they leave it in the first
place in 2021
uh did Modi G become Imran Khan 2.0 Zero
Netanyahu did the same thing which Putin
did to Imran Khan in 2022. Cherry on top
Modi Gi said we stand with Israel and
now this conflict I sense some wasal
vibes vote. Okay. So once again let's uh
unpack this question by Hani Sharma.
Yeah Pakistan did uh the US proxy
Pakistan did a brave attack on
Afghanistan. Yes. uh air strikes which
killed Afghan civilians and that's why
that the Avad government has has
responded by launching multiple strikes
on on Pakistan on the Pakistani
military. So that's why Afghanistan and
Pakistan are at war currently. It's a
state of war. Um and now the US and
Israel have launched missile strikes etc
on Thran. Thran has responded. It has
launched strikes on on on multiple
countries right hasn't tan. So if you
look at the Saudi statement uh if you
look at the Saudi statement uh it's
denouncing
u Iranian aggression on UAE, Bahrain,
Qatar, Kuwait and Jordan, right? Because
the the Iranian government has launched
attacks on the UAE, on Bahrain, on
Qatar, on Kuwait, Jordan, you know, most
likely uh military installations most
likely. Uh I I hear that at least one
person has lost the one person has lost
his or her life in Abu Dhabi. I hear
that uh there have been there is there
have been ballistic missile strikes or
other missile strikes uh on Alud air
base in Qatar I think it is and so on.
So uh Thran has has responded for sure.
Uh it looks like the house of Ali Kamei
the supreme leader of Iran has been
targeted maybe taken out right. It looks
like that's happened. Uh the question is
is Mr. Kami still alive? Because when
you start a war of this this kind, a
regime operation, you launch
decapitation strikes. You launch strikes
at targeted at the leadership of the
nation whose regime you're trying to
change. You want to eliminate the
leadership as fast as possible. So what
is uh the status when it comes to Mr.
Kame? Is Mr. Kame safe or has he been
taken out by the Americans? the
Americans will try and take him out. So
yeah, that's that's a question that we
will have to look into. We don't know
for sure. There are all kinds of rumors
swirling around on social media. Um
so they are definitely go going after a
regime change in Iran. Why do they need
Bram is what Honey Ferma is asking,
right? Uh why do they need Bram? Well,
Bram is the well it's it's it's a very
very important air base. It it has
it has facilities that can accommodate
tens of thousands of soldiers. It has
multiple runways and so on. It's it's
like see the US has multiple massive air
bases, right? One is Guam from which it
can strike China if it needs to. Another
is Diego Garcia from which it can strike
at Iran, India, wherever it wants.
Similarly, Bagram is like Diego Garcia
plus Guam put together. That's how
massive and extensive it is. It's an
extremely sophisticated and capable air
base that can well if if you hold it,
you essentially can uh can can threaten
multiple countries from there. You can
threaten Iran, you can threaten India,
you can threaten Pakistan, you can
threaten China, you can even possibly
threaten Russia from there, right? And
just by holding Bram, you you can keep
an eye on all these countries, you can
spy on all these countries. That's why
Bagram is very very important. Now the
question the logical question Anishba is
asking now is why did they leave it in
the first place if it's so important?
Well, they made a mistake.
So uh the handover of Afghanistan to to
the Taliban happened in 2021 and I did a
bunch of live streams at that time also.
Uh and the US essentially just handed
over the country to the Taliban.
Obviously it was not done you know
randomly. the US and the Taliban had a
long uh extensive set of negotiations
um in in Qatar in DHA and eventually
they signed the DHA accord some of and
some of the text of the DHA accord
between the US and the Taliban is
classified it's secret
and based on whatever understanding they
reached they handed over power to the
Taliban including Bagram air base they
they the Americans left Bagram Haram
overnight in the middle of the night
Bram was undefended. It was empty when
the Taliban walked in.
Uh and this happened during the Biden
administration. So it looks like the US
government is now
has now come to the conclusion this was
a big mistake. We should not have left
Bagram. Bagram is just too important. So
the Americans haven't built Bagram but
they have extended it right or during
the 20-year occupation of Afghanistan.
Bagram was built by the Soviets in the
1950s or 60s or whatever. So Bram is
very important and it looks like Trump
wants it back. It looks like the US
establishment wants Bram back for which
they can use Pakistan. Yeah. Uh so yeah
that answers that question. Now what
about this? Did Modi G become Imran Khan
2.0? Netanyahu did to Modi what Putin
did to Imran Khan in 2022. So what did
Putin do to Iran Khan in 2022? Putin did
nothing. Immran Khan was in the wrong
place at the wrong time. So the day that
Vladimir Putin launched the Russian
special military operation February 20
something 22nd 2022 I think it was
that day Imran Khan was in Moscow and it
was a very bad look. I mean he's in
Moscow. He meets with Putin and right
after that happens, right after that
meeting, Putin launches the special
military operation on Ukraine.
So that's what happened to Imran Khan
and a few months later he's taken out.
He's he's ousted and put in jail, right?
So kind of similar to what happened just
now. So Mr. Modi was in Israel until
yesterday or something, right? Or day
before yesterday. He just returned from
Israel and immediately after he returns
return essentially almost immediately
after Mr. Modi returns from Israel to
India, Israel and the US launch this
joint military operation, regime change
operation on Iran.
So uh is it the same thing that's
happened to Mr. Modi uh what happened to
Imran Khan? Not quite. Not quite. See,
Iran Khan when he went to Moscow, he had
no idea was what was going to happen.
Mr. The Putin must have already decided
what date and what time this special
military operation will begin. He must
have already decided that it would have
nothing to do with Imran Khan's visit.
Or maybe it was scheduled in such a way
that once Imran Khan leaves the meeting,
that's when this happens. So Imran Khan
was not aware at all
that the special military operation is
about to be launched. Am I implying Mr.
Modi knew what was going to happen?
Am I implying that Mr. Modi knew that as
soon as he leaves Israel,
the action against Iran will be taken?
Look, I don't know. But I think it's
possible.
I think it's possible that Mr. Modi knew
exactly what was going to happen.
And it's possible that Mr. Modi
his visit to Israel
uh signals just before the operation of
the military regime in operation on
Iran. Maybe it signifies or it signals
that we are now on the side of the US
and Israel.
Maybe it signals that there have been a
lot of things happening in the past few
weeks that kind of signify that kind of
signal give small signals to the world
but if you put them all together it's a
it's a clear consistent pattern it looks
like India is now taking has now made a
choice that we are going to be in some
way or the other aligned with the US
right so I am pretty sure Mr. Modi knew
exactly what was going to happen and I
think the whole world was anticipating
that when once Mr. Modi leaves Israel
and returns to India once he touches
down in India the action will begin
almost any time.
So everyone knew as long as Mr. Modi is
in Israel
Iran won't be invaded and once Mr. Modi
is back in India the countdown begins
and anytime the invasion will happen and
that's precisely what has happened.
Essentially Mr. Modi was in Israel
and once he's back here we go. I'm
pretty sure Mr. Modi would have been
aware of what
the plans are.
Right. So yeah, that's that's definitely
the case the way I see it.
Amisha says Israel and the US have
launched a preemptive air attack on
against Iran. Iran has also retaliated.
Where are China? What is
where are Russia? China is there any
Russian or Chinese connection with Mr.
Modi's visit to Israel? Regime change
chaos in Middle East. This is a regime
change operation. Yes. If you read out
if you listen to Mr. Trump's address,
it's clear that the objective is regime
change. If you see Mr. Netanyahu's uh
statement on Twitter. Once again, it's
it's abundantly clear uh that uh this is
a regime change operation. Uh let me
once again pull this out.
Um
yeah. So uh if you look at uh
Netanyahu's statement, it's clear it's
it's a regime change operation, right?
Uh, I'll have to translate this out
again. It's clear the the Israel and the
US have embarked embarked on an
operation to remove the existential
threat posed by the terrorist regime in
Iran.
So the operation will create the
conditions for the people of Iran to
take their faiths into into their own
hands. Essentially, it's a regime in
operation. Nothing nothing less than
that. It's a regime in operation. Uh so
yes regime change yes that's the
objective
um Iran has retaliated Iran has launched
looks like missile attacks on Israel
itself hifa for sure it looks like ashod
perhaps Tel Aviv Jerusalem I'm not sure
I've seen some evidence of that I've
seen some interceptions in the air by
the Israeli uh Iron Dome defense system
it will be more visible in the night
time obviously in the daytime it's hard
to see what's happening in the sky is
Iran Iran has launched missile attacks
on other countries also Bahin Qatar
Kuwait apparently uh Abu Dhabi I mean
the UAE Abu Dhabi not Dubai Abu Dhabi
and certain other nations as well and
Israel Iran does possess very very
strong missile capabilities
um the question you're asking is what is
is was there some Russian or Chinese
connection with Mr. Modi's visit to
Israel. I don't think so. I don't think
so. Mr. Modi went to Israel on a
bilateral visit very coincidentally just
before the military operation on Iran.
There are no coincidences in
geopolitics. So uh and there's no
Russian or Chinese connection with Mr.
Modi's visit to Israel. I don't see that
at all. I don't see that at all. Even I
don't even see a Russian connection
there. We seem to be in operating
completely independently of Russia right
now.
Yeah. Um Yeah. So that's the deal. Chaos
in the Middle East. Yeah. The chaos is
going to actually most likely intensify.
Nighttime will be see it's very strange
that this uh military operation was
launched in the morning
like typically military operations
happen at night. The right time to
launch an attack on an adversary is
around 4:00 a.m. 5:00 a.m. is a little
late around 4:00 a.m. Let's that's the
date of the night, right? That's
typically when you launch an attack on
your adversaries. But this thing
happened in the morning. Uh so anyway,
that's where we are. The chaos I
expected to unfortunately intensify.
Ammon Pata says, "Is it World War II?
Should I start the preparation?" This is
not World War II.
uh it will we will be closer to World
War II if Russia and China get involved.
India is staying out of it. India is in
no position to intervene but if Russia
and China intervene well that could be
kind of something that brings us closer
to the third world war. Now now let's
take a look at the map. Okay. Uh let's
put the map on the screen and let's
understand how Russia and China may
intervene.
So look, here is Iran, okay?
Now, where is China? China is way far
away,
very far away. Uh Chinese occupied
territory over here, it's it's very far
from Iran. So there's not much China can
do over here, okay? To to intervene in
Iran. The Chinese navy, if they want to
intervene, they have to cross uh the
straight of Malaa. They have to cross
the street of Hormuz and and I mean be
in the Gulf of Oman essentially. if they
want to intervene in some way. But the
Chinese Navy is no match for the US Navy
whatsoever,
especially they can't put up the number
if they need to help Iran because most
of the Chinese Navy is is is essentially
stuck over here defending China from the
you know what China perceives as its
adversaries. South Korea, Japan, Taiwan,
uh Philippines, etc. which all are US
proxies essentially. So the Chinese Navy
can't put up ships in large numbers over
here. Whether it is ships or submarines,
it can't. So it can't do much to help
Iran militarily. China, they can't do
much. What about Russia? Well, Russia
actually isn't really far away from Iran
at all. I mean, uh, you know, if you
measure the distance from here to here,
oh, come on. Uh, let's let's measure
distance. Can we measure distance?
What on earth is happening? Can we Okay,
now we can measure distance.
So, it's about 500 kilometers away. The
the Caspian Sey, the Russians have a
presence there obviously, right? So, so
if this war goes on, Russia can if it
wants resupply Iran through the Caspian
Sea. Russia isn't physically or
geographically far away. Um, so Russia
could get involved in in that manner. So
if Russia gets involved, if China gets
involved, then you have multiple
countries getting involved and that
could bring us closer to a World War II
kind of situation, right? So that is the
is the danger. Apart from that, right
now, uh I see I don't see a World War II
kind of situation happening right now,
right? But if if Russia gets involved
and China also also possibly that can
bring multiple very powerful nations
face to face and at each other's throat
and throats and that could bring us
closer to the third world war.
Kumar Kaneska says Iran has started to
hit nearby Islamic Middle Eastern
countries. Don't you think this goes
against them making country against them
especially for PR?
Iran has started to hit middle nearby
middle
Islamic Middle Eastern countries. Don't
you think this goes against them making
country against them? I have no idea
what you're asking, sir.
PR I mean is Iran fighting with Islamic
countries. Is it this war? Islamic
countries have a history of fighting
Islamic countries.
Okay. Islamic countries have a long
history of fighting against Islamic
countries. Orang fought against the the
the uh what's the dean sultanates or
whatever right what P this is this is an
existential crisis for Iran
this is an existential crisis for Iran
it's do or die who cares about PR when
you are about to be destroyed no one
cares about PR when you're about to be
destroyed right the situation right now
is that tomorrow morning there could be
no Iranian regime left in that do or die
situation. Do you imagine they'll be
thinking about PR right now? They'll
fight their enemies. This is this is the
last throw of the dice essentially for
Iran. It's do or die.
Team talks says the US is not Russia.
Okay. I don't think this will last for
years. What are my thoughts? A school is
hit in Iran and many kids are dead. That
will will this create sympathy for the
regime? No one cares. No one cares for
human life. The US has taken out entire
countries like this in 2020 2003 they
flattened half of Iraq killed millions
possibly
the don't don't you think kids died does
anyone care doesn't anyone even remember
that it doesn't matter
so see if you look at the statement of
Trump if you see see the look at the
statement of Netanyahu they are calling
Iran a terrorist regime the first stage
is to is to is to essentially paint your
adversary as the devil.
So it's no longer a human adversary.
It's the it's this it's the devil
himself,
right? And then if something like this
happens potentially that some kids died
or whatever, they'll blame the Iranian
government for this that you have
created the conditions where this is
this is this has happened. U it's not
going to create any sympathy for the
Islamic regime for the Iranian regime. U
what are my thoughts about whether this
war will last for years? Very unlikely.
Very unlikely. See, some people will say
that look, the Ukraine war is going on
for years now. So, is it possible the
this war against Iran will go on for
years? It's highly, highly unlikely. Let
me explain why. Why is the Ukraine war
going on for years? It's because the
Ukrainian military is fighting back
against Russia, right? They're
resisting. That's why the war is going
on for years. Now, ask yourself this
very simple question.
Who is how is the Ukrainian military
able to fight for years?
Where are they getting their arms,
ammunition, supplies, money, whatever
from? They're getting it from the West.
Ukraine is fighting because they are
being resupplied
and supported by the West on a monthly,
weekly, daily basis.
If the west had not given that aid and
support to Ukraine, the war would have
been over in a matter of days or weeks.
Right? So Ukraine is fighting because it
is being constantly resupplied by the
west. Ukraine is merely a proxy of the
west.
Now can Iran go on like that fighting
against a co a combined attack from a
combined force of Israel and the US?
It can fight possibly fight back
continue fighting only if somebody
constantly resupplies it. Who is that
somebody? Who will do that? Can Russia
afford to get embroiled in this Iran war
when it's already embroiled in in in
Ukraine?
Highly unlikely.
Most likely Russia will want to stay
away from this and may who knows there
may be some back backdoor deal between
Russia and and and the US.
You know, you take Ir you take Ukraine
and allow and stay out of Iran. We'll
take Iran. That's also a possibility.
It's a possibility. I'm not saying it's
happened. It's possible. These sort of
back door back door deals are routine in
geopolitics,
right? What does Russia seek? Russia
seeks the demilitarization, de
denazification,
etc. of Ukraine and a regime change in
Ukraine and it seeks Ukraine to be
permanently
um not aligned with the west. It wants
Ukraine to remain neutral and it wants
to retake all the Russian dominated
territories in Russian majority
territories in Ukraine and possibly a
regime change in Kiev.
So if the Americans are okay with that,
then Russia gets what it wants. But
obviously this doesn't come for free.
Everything has a price. The price could
be stay out of Iran.
Um that's a possibility. I'm not saying
it's happened obviously right now. So if
Iran falls, it's going to be a disaster
for China, especially especially for
China. Yeah. because China is a nation
that has a massive Achilles heel and
that is it is not self-sufficient in
terms of energy.
Okay. Warun Bajad says is this the best
time for India to capture P while the US
is occupied with Iran and Pakistan is
occupied with Afghanistan? Uh no
no
this is not the best time for India to
capture PK. Do you think the US is
occupied with Iran which means it says
it sees nothing else?
And because Pakistan is fighting
Afghanistan on its northern frontiers,
do you think it doesn't have armed
forces deployed against India on the
eastern frontier?
Do you think so? Really?
If India gets to capture P,
I mean it's it's possible India gets to
recapture P.
It can only happen if we get American
approval for that. Without
American approval, India can't recapture
P. That is today's situation. This is
not the best time for India to capture
P.
Unless there is some kind of deal
with the US and Israel.
Mr. Bodhi was in Israel just until day
before yesterday,
right? Perhaps yesterday, I think,
whenever it was. So, is there some kind
of deal?
Have we even have we been given some
kind of permission?
Right.
Pakistan is is an American asset.
It's also
indirectly an Israeli asset.
So if if India gets to retake P, it will
only happen if there is American
approval or Israeli approval. Without
that nothing happens. Understand that.
Kumar Kanishka says what will be the
impact of this development on India and
what could India what could be India's
role in all of this and the best outcome
India can hope for well
the best outcome that India can hope for
it depends where India stands today
if India has already decided that it is
now on America's side if India has
already let's say decided it is part of
the American orbit today then it doesn't
matter anymore what happens in the rest
of the
It doesn't matter anymore. Whatever the
master says is fine.
Yeah. Um
what is what could India's role be on be
in all of this in the Iran regime change
operation? Nothing. India is going to be
a spectator.
If there is some kind of deal with the
US, India may get to retake P which I
think is unlikely. Things changed after
operation Synindur slowly gradually in
the in the months after operation
Sindor. lots of things change for India.
Um
the imp one of the impacts of this
development on India, let's say the
Americans and Israelis succeed in the
regime change operation and they do a
regime change in Iran successfully.
Well, one impact of that could be that
India now gets to acquire to buy to
purchase Iran in oil. That could be one
development for India. So it's a very
small develop thing for India. We are
now once again able to acquire to to
purchase Venezuelan oil. If the
Americans take Iran, then we may be able
to to buy Iranian oil also. Yeah, that
will be a small little nice thing for
India, but nothing major. Beyond that,
there is no Indian rule in this. What's
the best outcome India can hope for?
Well, if India is now on the American
side, the best outcome India can hope
for is an American victory. If India is
still
um multi-aligned or whatever the hell we
call it
strategic autonomy and all that in that
case an Iranian defeat is a disaster for
India.
So it depends where we are today. Where
are we today? What do you what do you
people think where does India stand
today? Is India still multi-aligned? Is
India still strategically autonomous? Or
is India now part of the American orbit?
Yeah, depending on where we stand today,
it depends.
Prattana says, "Support for those who
deliver justice to Epstein victims." Uh,
there is no there is no justice in the
world, my dear friends. Justice is
delivered. Nobody delivers justice.
You have to make your own justice for
yourselves. Nobody is going to deliver
justice to those abstaining victims.
Especially when the people who have
victimized those people are so powerful.
There's going to be no justice for the
Epstein victims. I mean, all those
Epstein files have come out, right?
They're kind of in the public domain.
Some redactions, but we kind of
understand who those people are. I mean,
some of the names are very clear. Has
any action been taken against those
people? Have there been any lawsuits?
Have there been any arrests? Nothing's
going to happen. Nothing. That is
unfortunately
the way of the world.
Kishin Burkar says Russia called
Pakistan
and launched attack on his on Ukraine.
Israel had India and now now launched
Pakistan and Afghanistan. Trump says
Pakistan has rights to protest protect
its interests during operation synindor.
His words were different hypocrite.
Indians get very upset when people
aren't consistent with their words and
actions.
Every powerful person is a hypocrite.
You know weak people, weak weak people
in weak nations can't be hypocritical.
Hypocr the right to be a hypocr to be a
hypocrite is a privilege.
Only the most powerful people in nations
are hypocritical.
So uh
like Trump says that Iran is the is the
world's biggest state sponsor of
terrorism. That's what he says. We all
know it's not true. It's Pakistan. But
Pakistan is a is a useful asset for
Trump and that's why Trump will not say
a thing about Pakistan. Is it hypocrisy?
No.
It's it's called serving your own
interests. Right. Every nation serves
its own interest and the most powerful
nations they do it openly and blatantly.
So I know Indians are very emotional
people and Indian Indians get upset when
this happens. Indians India's national
motto is satyame
and we actually Indians actually imagine
that that's the way the world should
actually work that truth should prevail.
Truth never prevails
power might prevail. Okay. Uh it is what
it is. That's the way the world works.
And the sooner we understand that, the
better equipped we will be to deal with
the changing world, evolving world.
Truth never prevails. Strength and might
prevails. And those who are strengthy
strength, mighty and strong, they will
be hypocrites at at all occasions.
That's the way it is. Okay. So let us
not not let us we Indians should not get
overly emotional about this. It is the
way it is. I mean Indian politicians are
also like that by the way. You know they
they will say one thing do another thing
and they will change change their tunes
depending on the situation. Isn't that
true about Indian politicians also?
It is it is what it is.
Ryuanchi says will Russia and China be
be getting involved? Well that remains
to be seen. China it's very unlikely for
China to get involved.
China is
mortally afraid of getting involved in
any military entanglement.
Okay,
that's why it has not invaded Taiwan
thus far. China doesn't want to get
involved in any military entanglement.
China wants to play the game of
economics and all that. They want they
their objective was to take over the
world economically.
The United States has demolished the
dream that China had. The belt and road
initiative is now a thing of the past.
Okay. Nothing. It's it's dead.
Whether it is the belt and road
initiative or the maritime silk road,
it's dead. It's over.
And uh
China can't do a thing about the
American military presence in Japan,
South Korea, whatever.
If China had the appetite for a fight,
they would have done something about it.
So when they can't do a thing, the
Chinese can't do a thing about the
American military deployment in their
own backyard in Taiwan and so on, what
do you think they'll do about the
American military action against Iran?
Nothing.
Nothing. They won't be able to do a
thing about this. China has been reduced
to a helpless spectator. The kind of
situation India is typically in. China
has been reduced by the Americans to
being a helpless spectator today.
not as helpless as India. China will
still try and do something maybe maybe
cyber warfare or whatever the other
whatever the whatever else but nothing
actually kinetic. What about Russia?
Russia also I think it's unlikely
they will get involved. They're already
bogged down in Ukraine, right? They're
already involved in that. uh they can't
afford to fight a two-front war, one in
Ukraine and one supporting Iran against
Israel and and the US. They I don't
think they have uh the resources to do
that. Doesn't make sense. They may try
and support Iran in some way, maybe
supplies, ammunition, arms or whatever,
but that increases the likelihood that
the Americans will will target the
Russian ships or Russian supplies. that
could start a direct war between the US
and Russia and that's something nobody
wants and obviously there is the very
high possibility that the Russians and
the Americans have agreed to some kind
of backroom backdoor backroom agreement
that we are not aware of some secret
agreement that Russia gets to take
Ukraine and the US gets to take Iran
that's also a possibility and there
could be many conditions in that deal
maybe the Americans you know
will will gradually take remove the the
uh sanctions they've imposed on Russia
and so on. That's a possibility. So I
think it is unlikely that Russia and
China will get involved in this matter.
China very unlikely. China it's like 99%
I'm sure China will not get involved.
Russia I'm 70% sure maybe 80% sure
Russia won't get involved. China is
almost a guarantee. Russia also very
unlikely it gets involved. Right.
Agni Varna says, "Is India now an
American vasal since India has chosen a
side?"
We'll see. Time will tell. We need some
more time to be 100% sure about this.
Yeah,
a lot has changed after Operation
Synindur. Operation Sundur was India's
last
you know attempt to
to forge its own destiny
and uh the US is just too mighty. So is
India now a US vasal? I think it's still
a little early to to say yes or no but
the way things are going it looks like
it's going in a certain direction.
India clearly has kind of decided now
that we see I think it was in 24 2024 or
something when I had said this after the
US election results and Trump had won. I
had said this that Trump is going to
give India a choice. You're either with
us or against us and obviously what I
had said at that time has obviously come
true. Trump has given India a choice.
You you choose one side. Looks like
India is now in the process of choosing
the American side.
Yeah. And once that happens properly,
you are no longer a fully sovereign
nation. Datani says, "I believe this is
just a way to force Iran to negotiate.
Iran is way more powerful than people
presume. Trump may lose midterms if the
war stretches. I don't expect this war
to last too long." Now, the question is,
why do I not expect this war to last too
long?
It's because Iran doesn't have limitless
resources like Russia does.
Iran is kind of like Ukraine, big
nation, powerful nation, but not
unlimited resources. So, Ukraine is able
to fight
because of constant
western
aid. The West is constantly resupplying
Ukraine. That's why Ukraine is able to
fight. Who's going to constantly re
resupply Iran?
H you think Iran can last 6 months
fighting the US and Israel?
You think they have unlimited missiles?
The Iranians,
they will have a limited number of
missiles and they don't have the
production lines going that can turn out
new missiles every day. The Americans
are going to hit all of those industrial
facilities, right?
Iran doesn't have great air defenses. It
It has great offense, missile offense,
but limited missiles.
Uh so I don't see this war going on for
6 months. It may go on for a week, maybe
two,
but Iran will lose this war.
Okay? The negotiations were going on.
The negotiations were a pretext for
allowing for making this war happen.
See how do you justify a war if you are
a powerful nation? You first call your
adversary for negotiations.
So there have been rounds of
negotiations happening in Geneva,
Switzerland, right? You call your enemy
for negotiations and when the guy comes
and sits at the negotiation negotiating
table with you, you present him with
maximalist demands. So what are the
demands the US has made during
negotiations against Iran? dismantle
your nuclear program entirely,
demilitarize,
destroy your missiles, become completely
helpless.
Can any nation accept those demands? The
moment you denuclearize and
demilitarize,
your enemy will just walk into your
country and take over. Right? So that's
a regime. That's a guaranteed regime
change. If you accept those demands,
it's a guaranteed regime change. And if
you don't accept your those demands then
the then the US can say look we tried to
negotiate Iran did not agree to any did
not did not was not was not cooperative.
So these negotiations that were going on
these were simply the last phase before
war can start. You use the negotiations
as as justification. You you claim that
Iran was not cooperative in the
negotiations. We gave them the chance.
We negotiated. We gave Iran so many
chances. But Iran is being obstinate. So
now we have no choice but to go to war.
War is not a means to get Iran to
negotiate. The negotiations were
the the protects for setting the stage
for war. There is no negotiation that's
going to happen now. And whatever
happens going forward, I don't see this
war lasting very long. maybe a week,
maybe two. Very unlikely that Russia
will help Iran.
Very unlikely.
China, almost impossible for them to
help Iran. Uh the only way this ends,
the way I see it, is with a regime
change in Iran. Yeah, I'll be shocked if
it is doesn't happen now.
Died with Prigoian says great
opportunity for India to bring back its
talent from the Middle East and Gulf
region, but we are sleeping as always.
Look, the best Indian talent goes to the
United States. The rest of the Indian
talent goes to Western countries,
whether it's in Europe or Australia or
wherever. And whatever is left goes to
the Middle East and Gulf,
right? And why does the Indian talent
leave India? Because there are no
opportunities in India. Because India is
not a merit merit-based system.
because of all the problems that India
has that India has not reformed in the
past 10 20 30 40 50 100 whatever years.
So yeah the Middle East is a region
that's typically in turmoil. There's
always some crisis happening in the
Middle East. Right now we have a
military region change operation that's
going on and uh it's already spilled
over beyond Iran. Abu Dhabi has been
hit. Kuwait has been hit. Qatar, Bahrain
and Israel obviously yeah all these
nations are one way or the other
involved in the war.
So uh obviously we know that there's a
big Indian population in West Asia
uh and and and when it comes to the UAE
it's like high quality Indian talent
right who who live there.
So if the region is destabilized, there
will be an incentive for those people to
get out and return to India. But will
they want to return to India long term?
No. India has nothing to offer offer to
them. Does India have jobs to offer
them? Does India have a better lifestyle
to offer them? Does India have decent
living standards to offer them? India
has nothing to offer those people.
So if they leave the Middle East,
they'll go to some other country. They
may come to India temporarily
but those who have decided to leave
India if they return to India
temporarily they will then seek some
other place to go to this is this is not
a great opportunity for India to bring
its talent back from the Middle East or
wherever to create that opportunity we
have to reform India
but we are not reforming India
so no one's going to come back to India
willingly at least
Amisha says effect on India if mullas
are
China and Russia should help Iran. Yeah,
China and Russia should help but they
can't. They are not in a position to
help. China is is frightened of a
military confrontation with the US which
will be devastating for China. Um and
Russia is already bogged down in a war
in Ukraine. So Russia will also not want
to open a new front. It's like a
two-front war, right? Two different wars
we're getting involved in and both are
against the US. I don't think Russia
also can afford that.
Um what's the effect on India if if the
regime of the ayatlas the moolas is out
the first effect is that Iran see if the
if the regime is overthrown and there's
a regime change in Iran it means that
the pro- US regime comes to power a
puppet regime of the US comes to power
like what the situation was before 1979
maybe the son of the last sha of Iran
may be reinstated or or put into place
parachuted into Iran and become the
titular sha or whatever and there'll be
a US puppet regime in Iran.
So if you if Iran becomes a US
then what's the effect on Iran or on
India? Well then America will once again
allow India to purchase Iranian oil.
That's one effect it will have on India.
Secondly,
Iran will become a pro- US nation and if
India is already aligned with the US
like it seems now, then India in Iran
will have good relations. If India
remains a nation with strategic autonomy
and multi-arignment, then Iran, this new
Iran will be anti-India and pro
Pakistan.
But if India is aligned with the US now
then this new nation of Iran, this new
regime in Iran will be mildly pro- India
and of course strongly pro Pakistan.
So it depends on a variety of factors. A
lot depends on what India's stand is.
Has India now chosen 100% to be in the
US orbit or not? Looks like India has
but we'll see.
Teen Talks says,
"You have said we have finally chosen US
plus Israel, but isn't it a good thing
because we are on the winner's side?
Is Iran capable of harming mainland of
the US? Iran is at this point in time
not capable of harming the mainland of
the US? Iranian missiles can't reach the
US. uh Iranian u
proxy operatives and guerrilla fighters
or whatever may perhaps be in a position
to perhaps do something against the US
very unlikely that too. So mostly Iran
is not capable of harming mainland US.
Now I have said that we seem to India
seems to have chosen US plus Israel.
Isn't it a good thing because we are on
the winner side? Sure.
Good for us.
Right. But the question you to ask
yourself is what
do the winners seek to do with India?
See during the first world war, second
world war, India was on the side of the
UK.
Mr. Gandhi recruited Indians to fight
for the UK during the first world war.
Mr. Gandhi who was all about nonviolence
was recruiting Indians to to to join the
British Indian army to fight for the UK
in these foreign wars.
And India was on the side of the UK and
the UK ended up on the winner side both
types. Right? So was it a good thing for
India to be on the side of the winner?
The winner who was destroying India,
the winner who was sucking the lifeblood
out of India
and engineering artificial artificial
famines and whatn not
wasn't a good thing for India. So see
being on the winner side doesn't
necessarily mean that it's a good thing
for you. Understand that. Remember that
please
Buddha goes nuclear. That's a great
Buddha goes nuclear. Buddha goes nuclear
says once again the west does whatever
it wants and gets away with it. When
will karma strike? Will global south
always be under the boots?
See the west is doing whatever it wants
and it's getting away with it. Sure. But
why is that the case?
Why is the West able to do whatever it
want and get away with it? It's because
they are so powerful.
They are way more powerful than the
so-called global south. So, don't they
deserve to win because they have made
themselves so powerful? Don't they
deserve it?
What is the biggest sin in geopolitics?
The biggest sin in geopolitics is
weakness.
If you are a sinner, you deserve what's
coming for you. If you're a sinner, you
deserve what happens to you. In
geopolitics, weakness is a sin. And
power, being powerful, is a virtue. The
west is virtuous and the global south is
a bunch of sinners from that
perspective.
Okay?
The west will always keep on getting
what it wants as long as it ensures it
remains the most powerful entity in the
world. Now when it comes to karma, do
you understand the dharmic concept of
karma?
Karma, the law of karma,
it's a philosophical spiritual thing.
It's not physics, it's not science. But
what does it say? What is it all about?
It's a conservation law. Just like the
conservation laws in physics, the
conservation of of of energy,
conservation of momentum, mass, so on
and so forth. The law of karma is a
conservation law. It's the law. the law
of conservation of the merits and
demerits of your actions over multiple
lifetimes
if you believe in that. So the law of
karma is all about the conservation of
the merits and demerits of your actions
but not in this life or multiple
lifetimes.
That's why many evil people have
wonderful lives. The the whole concept
is that they will pay for it in future
lifetimes not in this lifetime.
Okay. Indians have Indians today are not
even aware of what their culture is.
Karma is not like I do something naughty
and after 3 hours I I get to pay for it.
No, that's not what karma is. Karma is
not like I do some sin and after 6
months I pay for it. Karma is in my next
in in my future lifetimes I will pay for
misdeeds of this lifetime. That's what
karma is. Okay Indians, you are so
incredibly delinated you don't even know
your culture anymore. That's not how
karma works. And karma also doesn't say
that if I'm naughty this lifetime, next
next lifetime I'll be born as a
mosquito. That's not what karma is. It's
way more subtle than that. So first of
all, please my dear friends, learn your
own culture.
Learn your own culture.
So will the global south always be under
western boots? As long as the global
south remains weak, it will remain under
under the boots of those who are
powerful. If you are weak, you are a
sinner. Being weak is a sin in
geopolitics.
And yeah, of course, those who are
strong will not allow you to get strong
and they will want you to remain weak
forever. But don't blame them for it.
You do whatever it takes to become
powerful again. If it if you're weak,
don't blame others.
So yeah, as long as the global south is
weak, it will remain under the boots of
those who are powerful. That is the way
the universe works.
I mean that's how nature works. It's the
law of nature. If you are a weak little
animal, you will always be under the
boots of the strong predators. Right?
That's how it works.
Wun Vishal YT says, "What are the
possible implications of India getting
chummy with Israel in the west? What is
the influence of Israel in the politics
and business?
Israel is one of the most powerful
nations in the world.
Israel is in a situation where the US
gives unconditional support to Israel no
matter what happens.
Right? That's why Israel is so
incredibly powerful.
Most people disregard Israel. They they
they miss the presence of Israel or this
tiny little nation on the map. Yeah. You
have no idea how powerful Israel is. So
um what's the possible implications of
India getting chummy with Israel in the
west? India is not getting chummy with
anybody. We're not getting there are no
chums in geopolitics. There are no
friends in geopolitics.
Right? Uh you have allies and
adversaries in geopolitics and all these
situations change depending on well how
things are depending on a variety of
factors. So uh what actually is
happening is India seems to be aligning
with the US. Now
India seem the government of India seems
to have realized that the way things are
we have no choice but to align ourselves
with the we with the US we have no
choice but to pick a side now
and we can't keep on playing this game
of strategic autonomy multipolarity blah
blah vishwaguru what etc we have to pick
a side because the alternative is is we
pay a tremendous price
so Um what's the possible implications
of India getting let's say aligned with
the US?
The implications
are that India slowly gradually loses
strategic autonomy. Uh
India gets deeply penetrated
technologically and in a variety of
other ways.
Um
some good things for India that India
will have more options when it comes to
buying energy. If there's a regime in
Iran, then India gets Iranian oil too,
right? Um, India will get perhaps access
to American markets in a in a better way
like the deal that we have signed with
the US uh and so on. So in if India
becomes chummy let's say with with the
west with with with the US then India
will be like a gigantic Japan not
exactly Japan because Japan has very
high standards India does not. Um
yeah but India will get some will get
get some favorable outcomes especially
for the people of India
possibly but long term you become a
vasal
and that's never good for you
says I think India is a good boy
well see typically when you go to school
who are the good boy
in in school etc the good boys are the
ones who are weak, right? If you're
weak, you have no choice but to be a
good boy.
Um, so to be a not good boy, you have to
be really strong. But India is not.
India is neither strong economically 4
trillion 4.5 trillion dollar economy
with a with a miserable GDP per capita
similar to subsaharan African nations,
right? And from a military perspective,
yeah, we have military strength of the
fourth most powerful military or
whatever, but most much of our military
equipment comes from other countries.
We still have this incredible
neverending delays in procuring fighter
jets. We don't manufacture our own
things. We don't manufacture our own jet
engines. We have we insist on remaining
dependent dependent on other countries.
We insisting on not reforming ourselves.
So when you have all these issues, you
are destined to be a permanent good boy.
General Subutai says it's how good it is
to see racism against India come down?
Uh has racism against India come down?
I I am not aware of that. Yeah, I'm not
aware.
Uh Vun Vishal says, "Is an eternal world
government possible?" Nothing. There is
nothing in the universe is eternal.
So from that perspective, nothing is
that's not possible. But is a
longlasting world government possible?
Maybe a world one world government that
lasts let's say two centuries. Is it is
it possible? It is possible. Yeah, it is
possible.
Vaci says looks after the Epstein files,
Modi has completely surrendered to the
US. Israel visits also seems to be on
the same lines. I don't think the there
is a correlation between uh India
hypothetically surrendering to the US
and the Epstein files. I don't think
there's a correlation between these two
things.
Looks like you you you're perhaps okay I
may be wrong but looks like you are
perhaps implying that there is some
something in the Epstein files that has
caused the government of India to
surrender to the US. I don't think so at
all. I don't think so at all. I don't
think there's anything in the in the
Epson files that in any major way
compromises any Indian politician. I
don't think so. Or any or or perhaps any
anybody
like Mr. Modi. I don't think so.
What's happening is the effect of
multi-pronged US pressure on India and
the tremendous amount of leverage the US
has over India. I mean India is
compromised. India is infiltrated. Every
Indian politician has children who study
in the US or live in the US.
Every Indian bureaucrat has family in
the US. You are completely compromised
that way.
That's just one angle of compromise. The
other angle is that we are dependent on
other countries for our defense needs.
They stop it, we done. We are helpless.
Third, we are not self-sufficient in
terms of energy. If the Americans tell
the Saudis, the
Saudi Arabia, UAE and other countries to
stop supplying oil to India, which they
can, then what do we do? Nothing. We are
helpless.
We are helpless. So when you are in that
situation and there are so many other
factors, there's the Pakistan angle,
there is the Manipur angle, there there
are so many angles all bearing down on
India and that's why India has had no
choice.
I could see that coming in 2024,
right? India has had no choice. Of
course, in the past 10 years, if India
had become self-sufficient and India had
completely reformed itself, then this
would not have happened.
But this government chose not to reform
anything.
Of course, it's very difficult to reform
a country like India in 10 years. That's
also we have to understand. Okay. But
there was no attempt made to do that.
Manufacturing did not take off. the deep
problems of of reforming u the
bureaucracy, reforming the education
system, none of it was not even
attempted.
Not even attempted.
And in during operation zindur, we tried
to stand up on on our own and and fight
back against these evil forces Pakistan
and so on. But Trump was too powerful.
He made us stop operation sindur. And
after that, it's been like going
backwards, backwards, backwards.
So um
that's where India is today. That's
where India is. It's possible that the
Israel visit was about going somewhere
to kiss the ring.
Really? Now Miss Patel says we will get
exploited by the US since we are weak.
Every weaker nation gets exploited by
stronger nations. It is the way of the
world. It is the way of the world.
It's just what it is.
Yeah. Um
now you will not get exploited if you
stand up against them and you refuse to
to cave in if you refuse to bow down but
then they'll make you taste the pain
right so if we let's say we if we decide
not to give into the US demands and not
not become part of their orbit then they
will apply increasing pressure on India
they U for example see one of our major
sources of income is the export of IT
services to the US the US can stop that
that'll crash India's GDP growth rate
that's one example of what they can do
especially with AI coming becoming so
powerful so agentic today it's it's the
Indian IT services are now redundant
they're worthless essentially India
never never beca be became a producer of
of IP of international of of
intellectual property. We simply kept on
exporting our donkey donkey work
services, right? She cheap labor.
We never reformed this stuff. So now
once again the Americans can shut that
off if they want to. But as long as we
remain in their orbit, they will allow
Indian IT services to be export exported
to the US.
So that's where we are today. Um it may
be the case that there are only four
sovereign nations in the world.
Nilles Ranjan Shivasav says can India
portray to be on the US side build
itself just like China did increase its
power simultaneously preventing US
destruction mindfully? No.
The US knows what China did, right? Do
you think they'll make the same mistake
again?
If India see let's understand this let's
say India decides to align itself with
the US become part of the US orbit
then what is the benefit India gets the
benefit India gets is that the Americans
don't destroy India
don't crush India like a bug
okay and you don't need military action
to crush India like a bug they can crush
India like a bug simply through economic
action
So if India decides to align itself with
the Americans then the benefit we get is
that they don't crush us like a bug.
But beyond that
since we are aligned with the US now
let's say hypothetically does it mean
the Americans will now allow India to
rise like China? Absolutely not.
India will be allowed to remain what it
is and grow somewhat but never become a
threat ever again or ever.
Right? So that is what you get as a
vasal. You are allowed to exist and you
will be allowed to grow in whatever ways
the master allows you to grow. But you
you will never be allowed to become a
threat in any way a potential threat in
any way. Not possible.
Really now Miss Patel says it's sinking
in now. We are weak in education, so
weak in innovation and weak in defense.
Dependent for energy, technology,
forever vulnerable to the predators.
Well, I'm glad people are finally
understanding where we are.
We are
trash in education. One of the worst
education systems in the world. And some
people in India say that this is this
this is what would make us vishwa guru.
So we are terrible in education. The
education system is is terrible. It's
garbage. It is trash. This new education
policy is a waste of time. That's one
issue. We are weak in innovation. What
we India spends about 0.7% of its of its
GDP in research and development. And
that research and development is on
paper. What actual research and
development happens? I wonder what
happens. I mean that 0.7% of GDP some of
it will be the the money India India
spends on its universities and so on.
They go to the universities and see what
research and development is happening.
It's all fake. There are there's
show me one piece of worldchanging
research that's come out of India in the
past 20 years. one one piece
whether it is in physics whether it's
it's in chemistry whether it is in
biology whether it is in engineering
whether it is in high technology
AI quantum whatever show me one piece of
worldchanging
piece of innovation R&D that's come out
of India in the past 20 years zero
so even if you let's say hypothetically
spending 0.7% of a GDP into R&D. What's
the outcome of that? Nothing. Zero.
That that to to
change that you need reforms.
You need reforms. Deep reforms.
That's not even being attempted.
Yeah. So, we are trash in education. We
are zero in innovation. In defense, it's
like a a lot of our defense depends on
other countries.
Yeah,
we we are at in some things like the
Akash system and some other systems and
in ballistic missiles and and uh cruise
missiles, hypersonics and so on. But we
are dependent on the on the nations for
so many other things. We are purchasing
tanks from Russia. We had the Arjun tank
that was world world class but we killed
it more or less
submarines. One day we purchase some
submarines from Russia, one day some
from France, one day from Germany.
What?
So we are weak in defense. Our air force
is is dependent on foreign aircraft.
We dependent on energy for from other on
other nations. Now we are looking at
digging for oil and gas in the undermans
after after everything is so after it's
so late technologically. See this is the
problem
and I've been speaking about this for so
long right that we need to address these
issues. Now what's the point of
addressing it?
So if if you have a nation like this
with low standards I'm not saying you
people have low standards. It's the
people who lead you who have low
standards.
So if you have that situation, the
predators can always come and pick on
you, prey on you and take what they
want.
So says, is there any credible evidence
that Prime Minister Narendra Modi knew
in advance about any military escalation
after his Israel visit or was his
departure simply part of a presscheduled
diplomatic trip?
There is no credible evidence of
anything. Okay. His departure was simply
part of a pres-scheduled diplomatic
trip. It's simply coincidence that
whatever happened happened the way it
did. There is no credible evidence of
any such thing.
Sar Pandi says, "Is India's alignment
with the US related to Bangladesh?
What will be Pakistan India situation
then and how will it affect India Russia
relationship?"
India's alignment with the US has
nothing to do with Bangladesh.
What happened in Bangladesh, the regime
change and so on and so forth, that was
one piece of the puzzle.
It is one. See, like I said, the US the
the pressure the US is applying on India
comes from multiple angles. It's
multi-dimensional pressure. It's
multi-dimensional leverage.
Bangladesh is one component of that
leverage. The regime change in
Bangladesh, the attacks on the Hindus,
the the pograms against the Hindus, the
spillover into other areas, the fact
that the the Bangladesh India border has
been essentially
super poor for decades. That's also
leverage
the US has on India. The spillover of
the Burmese civil war into Manipur, the
occupation of more than half of Manipur
by foreigners, that's also leverage the
US has over India. The fact that in
certain states in India's far east,
northeast, India doesn't really control
much of the territory. Much of the ter
territory is controlled by the church,
that's American leverage on India. So
it's not just about Bangladesh.
It's about all these different points of
leverage the Americans have established
over India and India has allowed them to
do it. Right? the past 10, 12 years,
India could have shut these things down.
India could have stopped the Bangladeshi
infiltration into India. India could
have deported the the millions of
Bangladeshes. India could have taken
control of the situation in in India's
far east. India could have ejected the
foreigners who are squatting in Manipur.
India could have shut down the
industrial scale conversion mafia that
operates all across India. But India did
none of these things.
Right.
And that's why India is you could say
wherever it is today
I would say today the situation is that
there are four sovereign nations in the
world not five. Um Pakistan India who
cares about Pakistan India
Pakistan is a US asset. Maybe India is
on the verge of becoming a US asset
also.
How will this affect the India Russia
relationship?
um it will not be a good effect on the
India Russia rel relationship.
Obviously if India goes into the into
the US orbit the relationship with
Russia will suffer tremendously and not
tomorrow morning but over the next 5
years you will see
a change in everything slowly gradually
slowly gradually you will see of course
you you will keep up appearances
through words
nice tweets
so you will make the people believe that
nothing has changed through words
through tweets and all the wonderful
verbal actions and all that but things
will change behind the scenes the actual
actions on the ground will change so the
if India has chosen the side of the US
the relationship with Russia will suffer
tremendously slowly gradually you will
see it over the next 5 10 years
Rahul Ladu says India should should
India buy as much time as possible look
India from 2014 until now had the time
to change things
to reform India that's what people had
hoped
that India will be changed that India
will be changed properly reformed
now what time do you want to buy you
think there this government has any any
any any
does it really intend to reform anything
no
man's says, "Do you know about Jang's
lectures and about Pak Judika?" No, I've
not watched Jang's lectures. I've been
many people have been telling me about
Jang that he's fantastic and all. Um, I
kind of briefly saw some clips of Jang.
Yeah, he looks very competent. He looks
like he knows what he talking what he's
talking about. But there is something
more to him. There is something more to
him about Jang.
I have not seen about Pax Jana.
Okay. Deep learner says theoretically
if India has an alignment with USA and
Israel that the next Iranian regime
wouldn't be pro Pakistan then I don't
think it's a bad deal. All right sir
that is I'm I'm glad you don't think
it's a bad deal.
I'm glad you think that way.
Kick says so Rahul Gandhi is right
about whatever. Uh no comments no
comments. No comments.
Inferno says, "We have low standards. We
are nowhere near where we should be.
There's no hope for the country. We are
doomed. All that remains is that people
should reminisce about the past."
See when people are helpless
when people are helpless
they give them the sol they when people
are helpless they give give themselves
the some kind of solace by by
remembering the distant past that 1,000
years ago we were this 1,000 years ago
our ancestors did this and that or
whatever we keep on reminiscing about
the past when we are helpless today
other people of India help us today well
the people of India
What agency do the people of India have
today? The agency the people of India
have in a democracy is that you can go
and vote. So let's say you try voting
for so and so party for a few years.
Maybe they don't give you the results
that you wanted. So then you decide no
I'll change now I'll vote for this party
and you try that.
Once again you don't get what you want.
Then what do you do? That's the only
agency people of India have to vote this
way or that way. Beyond that, what can
the people of India do? You're helpless.
The people who actually decide the fate
of the country,
they are
essentially there's nothing you can do
about them. Whether you pick this lot or
that lot, things are things don't really
change much.
And when it comes to the people who
actually rule the country, the
bureaucracy and the other institutions,
well, they don't want things to change
either. And why does India have low
standards? It's because of these these
reasons. It's not the people who have
low standards.
Why do why does everybody want to leave
the country? Because they actually have
high standards, but this country is
keeping them down. Indians who go and
live abroad, you'll see that they have
the highest standards.
So the problem is not the country. The
problem is not you people. The problem
is the system that is entrenched in
power. The system
that's the issue and the system is here
to stay. So
Vihung Kuran says India had to choose
the side of the US right because the US
has too much leverage considering IT
industry in India heavy reliance on
US-based products like Meta Google US
presence in neighboring countries etc as
of today if you look at today let's say
we wake up today and we see oh my god
this is the situation so let's say I was
in a coma for 30 years okay completely
hypothetical scenario I was in a coma
for 30 years I woke up today
And then I looked around, I assessed the
situation. So I wake up today and I see
okay, India's IT industry is one of the
major sources of income for India and it
is completely completely dependent on
the on on the US. Uh India depends on
all these American technological
products like Meta, Google, etc., etc.
The US has a presence in all the
neighboring countries. They control all
the neighboring countries. Then if I
wake up today morning, I'll say yes,
obviously India has no choice but to
become an American vasal. No choice.
Otherwise, they'll crush us like a bug.
But let's say I was not in a coma for 30
years there I would have seen the last
15 years India India had the chance to
become genuinely sovereign by enacting
major reforms and addressing all the
weaknesses and deficiencies in the
country the past 15 20 years we had the
chance to do that but we chose not to do
that I mean uh we people didn't didn't
have the choice the government had the
choice India could have become
something more than an IT exporter of IT
services. India could have become a
producer
of intellectual property of of of not
just services but products.
India could have built up its own social
media platforms. India could have become
a major exporter of not exporter but
producer of software that the world
craves without which the world can't
can't survive. That's what India could
have done.
India could have 10 years ago, 15 years
ago decided not to to to phase out
American products like Meta, Google etc.
and to create its own products, superior
products that will that will serve India
and the rest of the world. India could
have chosen these things in the past
1015 years
because we did none of those things.
That's why today we are on a situation
where India has no choice but to choose
the US
and in the past 15 years India could
have done something about the presence
of foreign powers in neighboring
countries also. India has chosen in the
past 10 15 20 years to do nothing about
these problems and that's why we are in
this situation today where
where we are where we are.
Tintox says is it possible to change
regime only through air strikes? What
are what are the steps necessary to
achieve a regime change? How will the
people in Iran organize when the bombs
are raining?
Great question. Great question. How do
you actually
effect a regime change somewhere? How do
you do that? H
can you affect a regime change simply by
raining down bombs, air strikes? you
know, you send aircraft, it will rain
down bombs, it'll target milit military
installations, maybe the the um you
know, the the the homes of the people
who run the regime and so on. Is that
enough?
It's not necessarily enough because see
Iran, the government of Iran has been
expecting this to happen. They they've
been waiting, they've been expecting a
war on Iran. They have been seeing in
the past few weeks and months the the
gradual steady and massive buildup of
American military
power surrounding Iran. So they knew
it's coming. So it's not like they were
waiting for the Americans to throw to to
launch bombs to to launch bombs on their
homes. They would not have been sitting
in their homes. They would have moved
out the you know the the the key uh
powerful members of the Iranian
government. Kame's Kab's house has been
taken out. I'm sure he wasn't there. So
if the regime's top leadership is not
taken out, then even through bombs and
air strikes, you can't change the
regime.
So air strikes aren't enough. The air
strikes will be enough to decapitate the
regime and make it ineffective only if
then they can take out the top
leadership, the top 100 people or so.
But even if you take out the top 100
people, the top 100 people would have
made
would have taken precautions.
They would have made contingency plans.
They would have designated survivors
that okay, if I die tomorrow morning by
the if I'm killed by the Americans, you
three next three people are the next in
line. If I am taken out, you guys take
over and continue.
So even if you take out the the top 100
people, the regime can still survive.
So what are the steps necessary to
achieve a regime change let's say in
Iran?
First step is to take out the top
leadership. Second is to is to take out
the um air defenses. Third is to take
out the Iranian offensive capabilities.
Fourth is to take out the Iranian army
if they or or induce them to surrender.
While these things are happening and the
bombs are raining down, the people in
Iran can't organize.
Once the Americans have taken out the
top leadership, top 100 or 200 people
and they have taken out the air defenses
and and missile offensive systems and
all that and they have also taken out
the the the IRGC and all that
significant portions of that then the
nation is in chaos and that's when they
can put boots on the ground
because eventually they're going to have
boots they will need to have boots on
the ground eventually you will have
American military in Thran for this to
happen.
Okay.
Um so what the Americans are hoping for
is to achieve chaos in Iran as soon as
possible. A situation where there's
nobody running really running the
country. That's when the situation is
ripe for um giving a last ultimatum to
the Iranian armed forces who are now
leaderless to to surrender.
The Trump already said that in his
speech, right? He said to the IRGC and
the Iranian government, put your weapons
down and you will be given amnesty. If
you don't put your weapons down, you you
are guaranteed death. That's what Trump
said. So eventually through military
means they will
hope to create a situation where they
can give one final ultimatum and where
it will be very likely that the
government of that the Iranian military
will put their put their arms down. So
regime change is is not possible through
only through air strikes. It's a
combination of all these factors
and eventually the regime change will
happen only when there are US boats on
the ground. The people of Iran won't be
able to just randomly organize a
government out of thin air. That would
be very unlikely. It will it will need
professional support for a new
government to be set up
and the Americans already have the plans
in place. So yeah,
Sanscar Vas, thank you very much Sanscar
G. Thank you so much sir.
Ricky says is there any country in the
past that came out of vasalhood?
That's an interesting question. So many
countries have come out of vasalhood.
Now typically how does how do you come
out of vasalhood?
See one example is Germany.
1930s Germany. 1930s Germany's economy
was devastated.
Yeah. It was dependent on on the US and
other countries
aid from those countries.
But then somebody an ex-p painter became
the leader of Germany and in just five
years the whole country was transformed.
Yeah. Germany came out of vasalhood. It
did. That's one example. I'm not I'm not
saying it's a fantastic thing what the
Nazis did. There were obviously monsters
and so on. No question about that.
There's no question of glorifying Nazi
Germany. I'm just saying it's an example
of a country that transformed very
rapidly. H
um right
so that's that's an example and
obviously when you have uh
when you have an empire that slowly
disintegrates
see all empires rise and fall right
don't they so when for example the Roman
Empire started slowly losing losing its
its capabilities and and contracting
that's when all there the the the
various nations they had occupied
various kingdoms they were occupied they
became independent again they came out
of Vasalhoud didn't they so there are
many examples like that
okay let's uh see some other questions
okay Dad Chat says why is our missile
department good but other defense
research has no visible impact did they
do something different or was it just
one man's vision?
Um,
yeah, that's a good question. We we have
one of the best missile programs in the
world, don't we? Whether it's ballistic
missiles or cruise missiles,
some of the best missiles in the world,
whether it's air defense systems like
the Akash system, we we are tremendous
in that. So we are world class in
missiles
but other defense research has no
impact. Uh what's the cause for that? Is
it one man's mission? It's not one man's
mission. A missile program is not one
man who does it. Maybe someday in the
past one man had a mission vision that
India will will be a world-class missile
power. But that's a vision right the
execution takes hundreds maybe thousands
of people. And it's those people who
make the difference not the person with
the vision. We need vision. We need
execution.
So somehow India is great at at
missiles. We produce some of the best
missiles in the world. But when it comes
to aircraft
so what's the reason? One of the reasons
I'll tell you what
one of the reasons is that nobody is
willing to export worldass missiles to
other to other countries. Let's say
India was in the market for buying
ballistic missiles. Do you think anybody
would sell ballistic missiles to India?
Nobody sells that. Let's say India was
in the market to to purchase
Mac 5 cruise missiles. Do you think
anybody gives that technology? Do you
think anybody even sells that? Nobody
does. So because there was no
scope of importing these things, that's
why India had to develop it on its own.
When it comes to tanks, when it comes to
aircraft, you can import these things.
And that's where the import lobby comes
into the picture.
And allegedly there's a lot of money to
be made in these things. But there was
no money to be made in missiles
because nobody sells you missiles.
You see that's why we are so far behind
in jet engines because you can buy jet
engines from other countries.
So when you can buy jet engines and make
a nice piece of money for each jet
engine that's purchased, why would you
allow the Indian research programs on on
on in jet engines to succeed?
When you can buy extremely expensive
submarines, why will you allow an Indian
submarine program to to do very well?
When you can buy lots of very expensive
fighter planes, why will you allow the
theas fighter plane program to do well?
That's why it was delayed for decades.
Right? So understand the missile
department. There was no scope of
purchasing missiles from other
countries. Nobody sells ballistic
missiles. Nobody sells hypersonics.
Yeah. There's one example the Brahos the
Brahos program. India and Russia have
worked together on that. Well, there are
strategic reasons for that overall.
Yeah. So that's the deal.
Alka Shikhar. Thank you very much. Alka
Shikari. Thank you. Thank you.
Yuko K says sir, why do you think we
have become assal? Uh I I'm not saying
we are
it's not one thing, right? It's hundreds
of things.
Does India have sovereignty over Manipur
and Nagaland? 100%.
Is the government of India in control of
what's happening in at least 50% of
Manipur and 50% of Nagaland?
Does India have sovereignty over these
over the when you have tens of millions
of Bangladeshes in India
and you are not doing anything to deport
them don't you think something is wrong
when you are
allowing foreign technology to to
penetrate your country to the deepest
levels and you're actually facilitating
that don't you think this is a big
problem in India? There's so many
examples if you stack them together
become very clear where we are.
If we are a sovereign country, will we
give into other countries another
country's dictats and and pull out of
Chabahar?
Right? If we are a sovereign country and
we have uh commercial interests in Mali,
will you pull out because we are working
with the Russians there?
So many examples. Yeah. So many data
points.
Wishnav, thank you very much, Vishnav.
political zack. Thank you very much,
sir.
Abai Singh says, "The scary thing is
that the majority of our population
don't even know that we are in such a
dire situation." That is the beauty and
utility of the education system.
The education system dumbs your brain
down. It prevents you from being able to
think.
So that is the act the virtue. That's
the utility of the education system. If
you want to do things and you don't want
the people to realize that, you need a
population that's really dumbed down by
the education system.
So the education system is actually
great for the for that purpose to keep
the people of India unaware of what's
happening to ensure that you have a
population who is completely clueless
of where the country stands. That's why
the education system is a great asset
for those
for whom this is beneficial.
If you had all been educated properly.
Okay, let's say if you had all been
taught what the national interest is,
then you would see the world
differently.
If you had all been taught what is the
difference between sovereignty and
vasalhood,
then you would see the world
differently. If you had been taught
properly how to how to differentiate
right from wrong and to do something
beyond surface level analysis
then you would see the world differently
right but that's not the case
all right
says good to see you sir have you ever
seen Dr. Soi Dr. Dr. Ankit Sha's talks
or tweets on deolarization. One of his
many wild predictions many have come
true is that Iran will become a
Christian nation thoughts. Uh I am not
aware of Dr. Ankit Sha's pronouncements,
statements etc. I'm not aware of that.
Uh I don't follow him and on Twitter I'm
blocked by him so I don't know about
that. Uh his predictions that Iran will
become a Christian nation. I have been
saying that Iran will become a Christian
nation. Seems that uh me and Ankit Sha
agree on that one thing.
I have been saying this for you can look
at my past episodes I have said that
Iran see today also on Twitter many
people are in India celebrating Iran
will become a Zoroastrian nation what
are they
what are they consuming is the question
right Iran is not going to become a
Zoroastrian nation when the Americans
take over Iran and install a puppete in
Iran one of the first things the
Americans will
is
is pushing
thousands of missionaries into Iran.
Okay?
And Iran will be turned into a Christian
nation.
Take the example of South Korea. South
Korea is under US occupation. Iran once
a regime change happens, Iran will come
under US military occupation.
The US will then have military bases in
Iran
including northern northern Iran Caspian
Sea region.
So Iran will come under permanent US
military occupation. That's the future
of Iran. If this war concludes the way
we expect it to conclude with a US
victory
and once that happens, you will have
Christian missionaries all across Iran.
Iran will become a Christian nation.
That is the future of Iran. Iran is not
going to revert to be being a Zoroastran
nation. It's not going to happen.
Zoroastrian will be Zoroastrianism will
be allowed to remain or maybe even exist
a little bit more as a boutique religion
in in in Iran by the Americans
but Iran will be turned into a Christian
nation in a few decades.
So I don't know if what Ankit Sha has
said but I I myself have been saying
this that the future of Iran if there is
a regime change by the Americans it's
Christianity.
Swastik says, "Is Yogi the only hope to
reform India? Explain." Well, he is one
politician
who actually gives me hope.
So, yeah, I'm I'm not saying he's the
only hope, but he is one politician who
does give me hope.
Yeah.
So, yes, I I I I
when I see Mr. Yogi, when I see Yogi
Adit G, I I still feel a sense of hope.
I do.
Aglivana says are we back to pre-1947 if
not when will we become? No, we are not
pre 1947. No, pre 1947 India's life
expectancy was 3132,
right? Um, India's GDP per capita was
incredibly low 1947. Pre1947 India was
under foreign military occupation.
Pre1947 you had foreigners ruling India
directly directly ruling India.
uh today we are not in that situation.
We're in a very different situation.
Let's say hypothetically India becomes
the US wasal. It will not be a pre1947
situation. It will be a situation that
India has never been in where India is
technically an independent country but
is actually being controlled by somebody
living by by a bunch of people who exist
on the other side on the other side of
the planet.
So it's not a pre-1947 situation. It's a
very different situation. It's a
situation India has never been in.
Yeah. So it's it's different. It's very
different.
Past time says so what can we do now? We
are becoming powerless. Our lives here
are degrading. Going out of India is not
that easy for everybody. Do you see any
chance?
Well hopefully India's GD GDP per capita
rises. India hopefully keeps growing at
67% whatever it is the next 20 years. So
by 20 uh 2047 or wherever it is India
becomes a 10 12 trillion economy
perhaps. Yeah. So people's lives will be
better. You will have more purchasing
power.
Um
the pollution I don't know about that
living standards I don't know about that
but you will have more purchasing power
and all that. And if India does become a
vasal then maybe Indians will be allowed
to the good you know the high quality
Indians may be allowed to still im
immigrate to the US that's a possibility
u as a nation you become powerless if
you are a vasal uh as a nation if you're
a vasal and the in the and the foreign
power allows a bunch of politicians to
rule the country then they will not
reform the country for sure so your
lives the living standards won't rise so
if you are a high quality Indian then
you may be allowed to immigrate outside
of India.
So that's kind of where you are if you
if you are a Wasal state.
What can we do now? There is nothing the
people can do.
There is nothing the people can do.
The people can't change the country. The
government that you have elected is
supposed to change the country. The
people can't do a thing. Please
understand in a democracy the people are
powerless.
The only agency you have is to vote.
But that doesn't guarantee any outcomes.
That guarantees nothing.
So in a democracy, the people are
actually completely powerless. You have
not become powerless. You are now seeing
that you are powerless, but you were
always powerless.
Okay.
Um
yeah, it is what it is.
Um, Sarak says, Sarak Pande says, "Is
the world moving towards a Christian
Islamic war?" No. Nope. Nope.
Agniv says, "If we are a US vas, should
we buy the F-35?" Yeah. Yeah. Please go
ahead and buy that. The US would make
some good money and you will acquire a
fancy toy that does nothing.
Buy it.
P. Shukla says, "Abi G, Namaste." Thank
you sir. Namaste. Wikipedia is extremely
anti bharat and anti- dharma
anti-sanatani. Does the west have it
cell where they control all the
Wikipedia articles especially pages of
arian picnic theory and sanskrit
language.
This IT cell thing is very Indian. The
west doesn't have an IT cell. The west
owns the platforms.
Wikipedia is not an Indian platform.
It's a western platform.
They they own the platform itself. So
they they determine what what is
allowed, what's not allowed, right?
Wikipedia, as I've been saying for
years,
you know, it is not a reliable source of
information about India. It's not a
reliable source of information period
for anything. But especially when it
comes to India, it's very strongly
biased against India, against uh Dharma
and so on. That's the case. It's been
the case since the very beginning. So
the west owns and operates these
platforms and of course there's a bunch
of people who are Wikipedia uh
administrators or what moderators
administrators whatever it is and they
kind of gatekeep Wikipedia. A bunch of
these people are Pakistanis by the way.
Okay.
So the government of Pakistan has
Pakistan has invested in these things in
what you could call you know open-
source cyber warfare gatekeeping
Wikipedia articles and so on. The
government of India has never bothered
with this is called the propaganda war
the narrative war. So Pakistan takes the
narrative war the propaganda war
seriously. They have dedicated people
who work
whose whose entire job is to put forth
Pakistani propaganda on social media.
The Chinese have millions of possibly
not millions but maybe tens of thousands
of of of social media warriors who are
on the payroll of the government and
whose job is to put forth Chinese
propaganda on social media. India has no
such thing.
whatever pro- India
uh stuff you see on social media is done
by individual volunteers who are not
supported by the government of India. So
the government of India has just dropped
the ball when it comes to propaganda and
counter propaganda nothing whatsoever
and that's why everything on social
media and Wikipedia and so on is just
openly anti-barat anti- dharma
anti-harma and all of that because the
government of India has just ignored it
doesn't take this matter seriously at
all
okay sabesh pande says why does the US
take help from Israel especially Israel
is taking hits from Iran. US is fully
capable of executing the operation on
their own.
The US isn't really taking help from
Israel.
The US is doing it on its own. But
Israel also wants the operation to
happen. So they're also participating
and they're also very capable. You see,
so it's not like if US doesn't take help
from Israel, this operation will not
succeed. The past several like we are in
February, right? the past month and a
half
and even before that the Americans have
been assembling
a major military force in West Asia,
right? They they they've sent they've
had hundreds of aircraft sorties, you
know, those big giant galaxy, you know,
those big transport aircraft coming in,
hundreds of aircraft sorties bringing in
arms, ammunition,
material, personnel.
you have all these aircraft carrier
strike groups that have come and
positioned themselves in the region.
Um, so the US doesn't need Israel to
defeat Iran,
but Israel is America's number one ally.
The US offers unconditional support to
Israel and Israel sees Iran, the regime
of the Ayatollas, as an existential
threat. And that's why they want to to
affect a regime change in Iran. So you
have a situation where the interests
of both countries, the US and Israel are
completely in convergence. So why will
they not cooperate?
They'll work together from when it comes
to this matter. Uh Israel will take some
hits. In a war, you take hits. What do
you expect when there is a war? Do you
expect a war in which your soldiers
won't die?
your ships won't be shot down where
missiles will not fall on your cities
where your aircraft will not be shot
down. There is no war in which you don't
take casualties.
So in in countries like India, Indians
expect that you know you will have a war
and fight a war in which no aircraft
will be shot down, no Indian soldier
will die. We will win without taking a
single casualty. That's what Indians
actually seem to imagine. That's not how
it works. Trump said in his speech today
that the US will take casualties.
That's what happens, right? So both
nations their their
interests align perfectly and that's why
they're working together.
Teen talks says Shivaji's situation was
also hopeless but he turned the tide.
Boo's situation was also like that but
he prevailed. I have faith in Bharata
spirit.
So, Chhatrapati Shishwaji Maharaj is the
founder of the Marata Empire.
But during his lifetime, the Marata
Empire was that much or maybe this much.
It was
the great work he started was take was
carried forward by people in the empire,
Marata Empire
after the death of Chhatraat Maharaj.
and see when does when did Chhatrapati
Shivaji Maharaj pass away? Let's see.
Okay.
Chhatraati Shivaji Maharaj. Um he passed
away in um 1680.
Okay. Now let's see this. 1680 he passes
away.
Maratha Empire.
Okay. The high tide of the Marata Empire
1759.
So it's 80 years after the death of
Chhatraati Shivaji Maharaj that the
Marata Empire had essentially liberated
India much of India. 80 years it took
80 years for this to happen. Do you
understand?
Chhatraati Shivaji did not turn the tide
in two weeks. It took 80 years. Do
Indians have the patience to wait 80
years.
Do you have the patience to wait 80
years?
Bose's situation was like that but it
prevailed. Excuse me. Where did Bose
prevail?
Where did Subasandra Bose prevail?
Subashandra Bose failed in ach to
achieve what he wanted to achieve. He
wanted to liberate India from the
British militarily through military
force. He wanted to gain Indian
independence on India's terms. What we
got was a transfer of power from one set
of crooks to another set of crooks. In
on British terms, India was never
liberated.
India remained colonized. India is even
more colonized today. Bose failed.
He was the last great patriot we had.
He failed.
And he had to hide the rest of his life
until he died in 1985. You think he
prevailed?
He did not prevail. Unfortunately, if he
had prevailed, India would not be where
it is today,
right? He wanted dictatorship for 20
years. Did we get that? He failed.
Please let us not
lie to ourselves.
Right?
Then when Chhatrapati Shivaji died,
Orurange was still alive and Orurange
ruled much of the subcontinent.
Let me show you.
Um, okay. Muggal Empire.
Okay. So, Orurange dies in 1707.
1707. This is the Muggal Empire.
So do you think it was all nice for
India when when Chhatraat Shivaji died?
No. It was still a terrible time for
India. But in 80 years we turned the
tide. Do we have do you people have the
patience to wait 80 years?
That's the question. So when you are in
a bad situation, it takes decades, maybe
centuries to change things.
The Spaniards when they reconquered
their land their their country from the
Arabs and the Moors that process took
800 years the reconista.
So yeah I also have faith in the Bharata
spirit but I don't see things changing
in the next two weeks. It's going to
take decades if not centuries for things
to change.
All right,
just being realistic here. Be realistic.
Dark side of the moon says, "This day
was always coming. History repeats. We
as a civilization fell at the cost of
incompetent elites. That personal
ambition who put personal ambition ahead
of collective prosperity."
Well, most people are mediocre. You see,
most people are mediocre.
And when you have a system that that
prioritizes mediocrity
then this situation happens
in the Indian system whether it's the
education system or the whatever the
overall Indian system the setup the
governance setup and everything
what do they distrust the most
patriotism and talent
they distrust that the education system
seeks out talent and destroys it and the
education system promotes mediocrity. It
loves that and the rest of the Indian
system is the same thing. So when you
have a system that promotes mediocrity,
hates talent, hates patriotism,
then what kind of elite are you going to
have? Ask yourselves.
So if you want India to be a great
nation
again,
we're going to have to do something
about the system.
The system will have to be reformed.
Without that it's guaranteed that India
will go backwards
be juices. Do you think India is putting
on a mask for the US?
Well,
tell me something. Have we allowed the
entire nation to be penetrated and infil
in infiltrated with American technology?
Yeah. No. Do you have government
officials who use Gmail for official
work?
Yeah, maybe some things have changed
but a lot of things have not changed. Do
you have government officials from top
to bottom who have family members who
are citizens of foreign countries, US,
UK, etc.?
Yes. Do you think this is putting on a
mask? No. This is taking off all the
clothes.
The Chinese call such officials naked
officials.
It is not putting on a mask. It is
taking off all your clothes.
Financial adviser says is this the right
time for India to free
is it the right time for India to free
Baljasthan next part of Bangladesh
important for national interest.
Yeah. What about PK? You should have
asked that also right?
See India is not getting getting
Balojasthan anytime soon. India is not
freeing Balojasthan anytime soon.
Bangladesh nothing is going to happen.
Forget about taking part of Bangladesh.
We are losing Manipur. We are losing
whatever else
um if India gets P or whatever it will
only happen if the Americans permit that
to happen if they give us a go at take a
jaw do it take it otherwise nothing is
happening nothing
okay
says who in the deep state takes the
call on attacking Iran how much of this
is actually is Trump Trump's decision no
I I will not venture and and put forth
any theories about that because I don't
know right obviously look first of all
we don't know who is in the deep state
the deep state seems to exist but who is
the deep state who are its members do we
know obviously we don't I at least don't
know nothing I know nothing
I can tell you that the deep state does
exist that is true so the American
entrepreneur of Sri Lankan origin Chamat
Palihapitia he once said that there's
150 men who rule the world, who decide
what happens and control everything. He
said it's 150 and he said it's men, no
women. So that apparently is the deep
state. The people who actually run the
world. So who takes the call? I don't.
How much of this is actually Trump's
decision? But Trump, I would say 50% at
least is Trump's decision. See, let's
understand Trump's interest and rule in
all of this. Trump is a super
egotistical person. He wants to be
remembered in history as the greatest
American president, greater than
Washington, greater than Abraham
Lincoln, the greatest president of the
US. That's what he wants to be to be
remembered for.
And great American presidents do war.
That's the nature of the US.
That's the kind of empire the US is. So
Trump wants to be remembered as a as the
greatest president, a president who won
so much that people got tired of
winning. So he this would be great for
Trump, right? If changing the regime in
Iran and winning a war in Iran,
something presidents for the past 45
years have not been able to do, he'll do
it. So at least 50% of this was Trump's
decision. And Trump is completely
aligned with the deep state. He has
kissed the ring. There's a lot of ring
kissing happening these days, isn't it?
So, he has kissed the ring and
definitely he'll be 100% on board with
the decision. But who takes these calls,
I can't say.
Short Story Studios says, "Longtime
follower." Thank you very much, sir.
Thank you indeed. I was on my way to
from Germany to India with Etihad Leor
in Abu Dhabi. Okay.
Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. Before my second
flight, I got a missile warning. Was
scary. stuck here trying to help people
here. Well, the good thing is that being
stuck in Abu Dhabi is not necessarily a
bad thing. It's a pretty good place to
be in. Uh
you may have to be given a transit visa
or whatever, but that's fine. You not
your fault what's happened. So, there
was a missile strike in Abu Dhabi today.
At least one person has sadly lo lost
their life. That's what I've heard. I
haven't seen the latest.
Um
so, you had an Ethi layover. Okay. So
you have will have a transit visa or
whatever whatever way it works at the
other layover. Um and I suppose if you
have certain visas on your passport then
you don't need a visa for the UE and so
on. Yeah. So before your second flight
you got the missile warning. Yeah. Which
happened in the afternoon I suppose for
afternoon India time. Morning UAE time.
So you're currently stuck there trying
to help people there. Yeah. Do you It's
okay. I I I am pretty hopeful this will
not last very long. Yeah. Just take care
of yourself. be stay safe uh follow the
government uh instructions the
government there and yeah help out
whoever you can all right sir all the
best take care stay safe and uh looking
forward to to have you back in India
soon thank you
the Praep Kumar says once Iran's
military capability is degraded
sufficiently whence do you think the US
will launch its land forces to capture
the Iran that's a great question let's
take a look at the geography of Iran to
try and guess what could happen.
Let me uh launch the map.
Here is the map. Now,
cafe. So, we have Iran here.
The question is once Iran's military
capability is degraded sufficiently from
where does the US launch its land forces
to capture Thran? So I'll tell you what,
Iraq is a nation that is essentially
under US control and occupation. The US
has withdrawn to a large extent from
Iran, from Iraq, but it still has forces
in Iraq. So it could happen from Iraq.
One possible candidate is Iraq. Another
possible candidate is Turkey. Turkey is
a NATO member. The US could possibly be
quietly, you know, setting up, you know,
a military post posture just west of the
Iran border. That's possible. Turkey is
possible. Iraq is is a possibility.
Another possibility is Pakistan
because Pakistan is a US vasal.
You could have perhaps even Pakistani
forces going into Iran on behalf of the
US. That's also a possibility.
Turkmanistan maybe not that likely.
Azarbaan probably not that likely.
Turkey is a great possibility, very
strong possible candidate. Iraq is a is
a big candidate. Pakistan is a very
strong candidate for that. Uh you could
also have you know this happening from
Iranian ports. Maybe Bundar Abas u maybe
Bushahar.
You have the port of Bushahar here right
that's a major Iranian port. Another
port is major port is Bundar Abbas.
So if the Americans can sufficiently
degrade the Iranian naval and military
capabilities, they could even launch
incursions into Iran from the ports of
Iran. So the ports is possibility is a
is a possibility whether it is Busher or
Bundarbas or wherever else. Uh using
Pakistani territory to to enter Iran is
a possibility including with Pakistani
troops. uh Iraq is a possibility and
Turkey is a possibility and they could
also send in paratroopers or whatever to
do temporary work. So the Americans have
multiple options. Yeah. Of how to uh put
boots on the ground to set boots on the
ground in Iran.
Okay. Really now M Patel says
so our non- selected system is a huge
termite eating us from inside while the
elected one is unwilling to cure or
perhaps
incapable of curing that or enforcing
reforms with an iron fist
essentially correct what you're saying
what you're saying Mr. Essentially what
you're saying is
is accurate
India also has a deep state the
unelected establishment and maybe key
people within that possibly
and if the system serves you why would
you want the system to be changed why
would you want reforms you don't want
reforms right so it's kind of a
parasitical organism
that prevents a reform and and and
acts as a rent seeker.
Um and whoever is elected even if they
try they won't be allowed to change
anything and eventually they will give
up I suppose.
So yeah so to transform India to reform
India is is really really difficult
really difficult because the system is
so vast and so many people benefit from
it.
and they control all the levels of
power.
That is the situation. So, Miss Patel,
whatever Miss Patel is saying here is
pretty much accurate.
Vihung Kuran says, "How are you?" I'm
good, sir. How are you? How can India
leverage its farmer industry prowess in
general considering India's significant
pharma exports to the US and many other
countries?
See,
India
exports a lot of pharma products to the
US. Maybe about 50% of the American gen
generic drug imports probably come from
Indian from India. Let's let's let's uh
fact check that. Let's fact check that,
shall we? Before before we actually
address the question. So the question is
what percentage
Okay, it's not working. Okay. Uh what
percentage of
US generic drugs
are imported
from India?
There we have it. 40 to 50%. India
supplies approximately 40 to 50% of the
gen of of all generic drugs consumed in
the US
la yeah so about 50% possibly yeah so
does it mean India has leverage over the
US it doesn't mean anything leverage
works only if you have other forms of
leverage that work together so let's say
you are
very militarily powerful then you can
make this leverage this kind of leverage
count but if you are militarily weak and
economically weak then even If you have
this leverage, you can't do much with
it.
Because if you try to use this leverage,
then the more powerful nation will will
squash you like a bug. Yeah. So if you
are a weaker nation, even if you are
supplying critical things to to the more
powerful nation, you can't use that as
leverage.
There are many countries that supply
things to the US,
right? For example, the Dutch uh company
ASML, it is it controls about 95% of the
photo lithography market in the world.
Do you think they can arm twist the US
using that? They'll be squashed like a
bug if they try that.
So, if you are a weak nation that is a
node in the supply chains of a powerful
nation, you can't leverage that because
you're weak. You can't. If you try to
play some some of these games, you're
going to pay a very big price for that.
Uh so yeah
so India can't really leverage these
things in all India can do with it is to
earn some cash which it does every year
right it's one of the one of the
cash generating mechanisms India has
it's it's pharma exports
but without hard power none of this
translates into actual leverage
inferno number one says we must seek
help from superpower Nepal to aid us.
Maybe we should. Maybe we should. Yeah.
Vic Post says,
Vic Post says, "My cousin was rescued in
Dubai by the Indian embassy by a naval
ship after Iran retaliated. Will this
escalate? I feel Israelis are
extremists."
Um, well, I'm first of all, I'm glad
that your cousin is safe. The government
of India does a tremendous job of
keeping its our citizens safe. Even in
in situations like these when there's a
war going on. So great job government of
India and I'm glad your cousin is safe.
He or she is safe. Um will this
escalate? Yes, this was this will
escalate. See the war has just started.
Trump has made it very clear in his
address in his address in his post on
Twitter that he seeks a complete change
regime change in Iran.
This will end with a regime change in in
Iran.
Israel's Prime Minister Finan Yahuji
also has put out a Twitter post in which
he also has made the same statement that
this will end with a regime change in in
Iran.
So this is just the early early
exchanges in the war. There's going to
be much more. This is going to escalate
significantly.
I expect unfortunately way more of this
to happen. And I wonder what's happening
right now in real time. But okay, we're
not looking at that right now. So this
will escalate definitely way more than
than what you are seeing right now. You
feel Israelis are extremists. Well,
I I don't see it quite that way. See,
Iran has been saying since 1979 that
Israel does not have a right to exist.
So what do you expect Israel's response
to be to that?
Israel will say we have a right to exist
and if you seek to destroy us we're
going to destroy you I mean
yeah
so I don't see it that way
chai says if we become vasal can we
become like Japan or Europe no we don't
have the standards of Japan and Europe
see in Japan
in Japan even after the destruction of
Japan by the Americans in the two atomic
tests over Japan the people of Japan
already had those standards
Why did the people of Japan have high
standards that they maintained even
after the American occupation in 1945?
Because from the mid 1850s onwards the
entire Japanese education system was
reformed
and Japan it it brought Japan's
standards to a incredible
degree of excellence scientific and
technological excellence and they all
always had this this culture of
excellence because they were not under
foreign occupation before that.
So Japan's people were very high quality
people.
Okay. Japan had a very high quality
population with great standards because
of a very high quality education system.
So after Japan became a vasal, the
Americans allowed Japan to rise on its
feet again and Japan became the most
technologically advanced nation in the
world because the people were genuinely
educated. Not book education but they
had the skills and they had the
standards. That's why Japan became one
of the most excellent countries in the
world. Europe once again they had a
great education system and a very highly
qualifi not qualified very high quality
population.
India has one of the worst education
systems in the world and the people of
India don't even know how to think
clearly.
So if we become a vasal we're going to
become a lowquality vasal.
We will not become like Japan or Europe.
We won't be allowed to.
Financial adviser says met an Israeli
today. He was stranded in India with his
family in Israel. He was stranded in
India and his family is in Israel. Okay.
He was cursing the US saying bad thing.
All bad things on in the world are the
doing of the United States. Well, you
see
in any country you will have people of
who have all kinds of different
opinions. Some people if they are
individually personally going through
some inconvenience they will blame the
government or they blame the US or
whatever. I would say most Israelis
support the US because the US
unconditionally supports Israel.
So that's normal that you will find
people with who have all kinds of
different opinions in any country.
Sumesh Pandya says what kind of
vasalhood India gets. So if India
becomes a vasal country what kind of
vasalhood does India get is the
question. Um India will get some
benefits. India will be able to buy oil
from Iran. India will get even more
benefits of American technology. In
Indians will find it somewhat easier to
travel to the US. Maybe the US will
still still allow high quality Indians
to move to the US because the US needs
talent and so on. Um apart from that,
India will see no reforms. India's
education system will not be reformed.
India's bureaucracy and other
institutions will never be reformed.
India's GDP growth will remain 67%.
India will remain dependent on other
countries for arms imports. India will
never become a manufacturing power
but India will remain IT power services
exporter. India will become a big market
that the west exports to. That's kind of
the solid you'll get and mediocre little
nation.
Kunal Desai. Thank you very much sir.
Thank you sir.
McLeivven says will we lose lose nukes
and dharma under Vasalhood
we will be allowed to keep our nukes
yeah but we will never use them dharma
will be wiped out over time maybe 50
years maybe 100 years we'll lose it all
says I am a first year mechanical
engineering student I was thinking okay
I'm not taking um I'm not taking these
questions today we are discussing war
we're discussing Iran we discussing
geopolitics
I I anyway I'm not the right kind of
person to ask answer these questions I
don't know about finance and all that I
don't know
says reports say Chinese satellites
helped Iran
bomb a base it's possible that that kind
of help China will be happy to give Iran
so China will not get involved
militarily in this conflict but they
will give some intelligence and that
that sort of aid
to Iran possibly. Yeah, the Chinese have
been putting out.
Give me a second. Let me let's let's
find this. Give me a second.
Um
right.
So
let us see. There's this Chinese
account, okay, on on on on Twitter on X
and they have been putting out this
stuff on Twitter. So, take a look. It's
called Mizar Vision.
And there we have it. They putting out
realtime satellite imagery about what is
happening. Satellite images show thick
smoke billowing from the Iranian port of
Karak, which was attacked by the US and
Israel. Oh, well, when did that happen?
Looks like it's a more recent event.
Okay. Okay.
Okay. We are seeing thick smoke blowing
out because you can see the shadow of
the smoke. Actually, can you see over
here? If you can see my mouse pointer,
you can see that. So, and what is this?
Higher resolution satellite imagery
shows multiple US KC35 refueling
aircraft deployed at Bengurian airport
in Israel.
Right. Right. So they are putting out
all of this information and they will be
passing on more such information to
Iran.
U maybe better information to Iran. Uh
okay.
Establish refueling positions. So the
military operation is very much
underway.
Very much underway. Israeli refueling
aircraft also took off from their home
territory and established refueling
positions in the Mediterranean.
Right. So you can see
this satellite data coming in from these
Chinese sources. High resolution
satellite images captured damage to
buildings in Iran, the Iranian capital
following attacks by the US and Israel.
You can see that there is damage to
buildings in Iran. Do we have something
else of note?
Um, okay. US
Gerald Ford aircraft carrier in the
Mediterranean Sea.
So the Chinese have been supplying have
been putting out this this satellite
imagery in the public domain and I
suppose they are also supplying that to
Iran maybe maybe higher quality
satellite uh intelligence maybe they may
be supplying it to Iran okay
says what can we learn from China and
Xiinping
the Chinese approach to geopolitics is
completely different from India India's
approach they have ended whatever
penetration American technology had in
China completely.
They have cordoned off the internet.
They have the great firewall of China.
They don't allow any American um
platform to operate in China or to
provide services to Chinese citizens.
They don't allow any officials to be in
power in high positions who are
compromised in any way potentially
potentially by the Americans of the
West. For example, people who have
family family members living in the US,
children studying in the US, they're not
allowed to be in high positions. The
Chinese approach is completely
completely different, diametrically
opposite compared to the Indian
approach. All those things I suppose we
can learn from China if we still want to
learn something.
Right? Teen Talk says, will the US
deploy boots on the ground in Iran? The
last time it was a disaster, Operation
Eagle Claw or any other nation's
military will be used.
The last time it they attempted to do
this in a clandestine manner,
quietly.
This is an open war. It will culminate
with the deployment of US boats on the
ground in Iran. This is the guarantee if
if the Americans succeed in this and
they win the war. The US doesn't lose
wars, right? and they lo they they lost
Vietnam but there was a there was a
there was last century
um they are determined the Americans to
do a regime change in Iran and most
likely they will succeed. I I don't see
Iran having too much of a chance against
the US. So the US will definitely deploy
some boats on the ground in Iran and
like I discussed a while ago if we once
again go to the map it's possible
Turkish boots could be on the ground.
It's possible Pakistani boots could be
on the ground in Iran. Maybe even
Israeli boots, maybe even boots from
Arabic countries. The Americans would
like to make it look like a multil
multinational effort, right? So, it's
possible. It's possible.
Dur Durji says, "Namaste from Nagaland.
Loving this episode. Thank you very much
and namaste G. Namaste to you and
namaste to everybody in Nagaland. And
thank you so much for for commenting and
and being a viewer. Thank you so much,
sir.
Summerr Slider says in 20 to 30 years as
the older generation fades an 80year-old
would be born in 1976
as hence as the orthodox die India
rises. Does this make sense or not?
So for a for a culture for a
civilization for a n or a nation to to
rise
you need the death of orthodoxy. Is that
what you're saying?
I was born in 1976.
Am I one of the orthod one of the do I
represent the orthodoxy of India? I
don't know.
I don't know.
In any nation, you need
all kinds of people. You need some who
are orthodox. You need someone who are
liberal. You need someone some people.
So, you need you need a bunch of people
who are orthodox. You need a bunch of
people who are liberal. You need a bunch
of people who are whatever.
In any population, you you're going to
have a natural and harmonious
balance of different kinds of people.
You need them all.
You need them all. Why do we need the
orthodox to die away? I don't see myself
as orthodox, first of all, but you seem
to be implying that somebody who was
born in 76 is going to be naturally
orthodox,
which I would not agree with. Right. Um
and if all the orthodox die then the
nation becomes unorthodox then we rise.
No that that's not how it works.
Yeah. Um India India is not known to
rise this by by it's like saying kill
kill off a certain section of society
then everything is fine. That seems to
be a lot of the thinking in India today
right?
that that that's not how it's going to
be. Sir
D with Pregosian says what about Iran's
nukes? Don't they have nukes? I don't
know if they have nukes. If they have
nukes, then if they do have nukes and if
they're at some point in this war going
to go down, I have a very very bad
feeling about that.
I have the feeling that if Iran does
have nukes
then at some point in this in this war
they may be they may be used.
Yeah, that's a bad feeling I have.
So yeah, I obviously am not in favor of
any nuclear weapons ever being used.
Yeah, but if Iran has nukes then they
may use it before they go down.
Ankur Das says India I think most
competitive exams are BS just to reduce
competition. these competitive exams and
all that they are a waste of everyone's
time and life and energy and years
that's not
yeah it's a it's a rotten system India
has rotten
um praradana says this is last
pro-Israel US population new generation
Americans are indifferent and even hate
that Israel has so much influence in
decision-m in the US uh you know what
you are you may be right about
Um, you may be right. You are definitely
right about the new generation Americans
being either indifferent or negatively
inclined towards Israel.
A lot of these new generation Americans
kind of are not so favorably inclined
towards Israel. Um, you're right about
that. Uh, but will it make much of a
difference
in the relationship between between the
two countries? Maybe not. Maybe not. But
yes, what you are saying overall is
correct on the ground over the over the
years over the decades the the
population the attitudes and worldviews
of the people of America have changed
gradually.
See, 1950s, 1960s, you saw this the the
takeover of American academia and
education by the left.
And over time, they have, you could say,
indoctrinated
newer student, newer generations of
Americans into their leftist worldview,
leftist ideology. And uh that is very
much the norm in in in American campuses
today. So a lot of new a lot of younger
Americans are negatively predisposed
towards Israel. That's true. Yes. Mystic
comrade says is it possible that the
Indian
is it possible that the Indian may have
given some hints about this operation
during his Israel visit? What are you
asking sir?
Is it possible that the Indian may have
given some hints about this operation
during his Israel visit?
Are you talking about Prime Minister
Modi
and his Israel visit? Because I don't
know what the Indian is.
U if you ask him about Prime Minister
Modi
whether he would have been told about
the operation during his visit. Yes,
most likely yes. Angal says who is the
most calculative leader in the world
rather more angry like Kim Jong and
Trump? I think it's Putin and our
airspace closed cuz my mom is in Canada.
What's a calcul? Every leader makes
calculations.
Every leader leader does that. Um
maybe the the the word you've used is
not the most
appropriate word. Maybe are you saying
who's the shrewdest leader? Putin could
be one of them possibly. Yeah. Okay. Is
the airspace closed? My mom is in
Canada. Let's find out together shall
we? Uh let's find out about the
airspace.
All right, give me a second. Let me put
that on the screen and let's find out
together what is happening from an
airspace perspective.
Okay, let's zoom out. Let us zoom out.
Uh
right. Okay. So
you can see that the airspace over Iran
is definitely more or less closed,
right? As you can see, the airspace over
Iran seems to be closed. There's nobody
flying over Iran. At least no civilian
aircraft are flying over Iran. You have
a few aircraft in Afghanistan. You have
a few aircraft in Pakistan.
And nothing over Iraq, nothing over
Kuwait, nothing over Iran.
Even Syria, there's almost nothing. What
about Israel? Let's see. Yeah, not much
happening over Israel either.
Sorry, that's Lebanon. Uh, not much
Uh, yeah.
So, the airspace is closed, but if you
are traveling from Canada to India, you
could certainly make your way to India.
No problem there. What about the UAE?
Is anybody flying in the UAE right now?
Let me see.
Doha to somewhere. Okay, this is U
Katar Airways. Who is this?
Yeah, looks like there's not much
activity happening over the UAE either.
So definitely the air airspace is is
closed over Iran. But if you are in
Canada, you want to visit India, you can
certainly fly to India. That's not going
to be an issue. You may have to avoid
that airspace and avoid certain
countries. But yeah, it'll work.
Okay.
Aman Kumar Dhankar says how Jews went so
powerful in very short period of time. I
don't know
you know they are very well organized
people. Yeah. And they understand power.
I suppose that's why they're very
powerful. Abishek says can you explain
why you say people in India don't have
power in democracy as in why is voting
power not enough? also if not democracy
what are the pros and cons of a
benevolent monarchy in India okay listen
we'll not go too deep into this stuff
but I'll tell you what why do I say that
people in India don't have much power in
democracy why is voting power not enough
so let me give you an example let's say
you have a government that you voted to
power you voted for them they came to
power five years they did nothing for
you
they they did not do any of the things
they promised let's say you voted for
them because because the election
manifesto promised these these these
things and you you wanted that to
happen. So you voted for them. But five
years they did nothing. But maybe you
said, you know what, they've just come
to power. Give them some more time. So
you voted for them again. So now now
five more years they're in power. They
still do nothing. So 10 years of your
life you wasted voting for them, but
they didn't do anything you wanted
because once you vote and you see that
nothing is happening, you have to wait 5
years. So let's say you waited 10 years
of your life. Then you said, "Okay, I'm
going to throw them out of power. I'm
going to vote for the other guy, the
other party." So you vote for the other
party this time. And maybe this time
they come to power. But let's say they
also do nothing. Then what power do you
have?
What power do you have?
Yeah. The only power, the only agency
you have is voting.
But that guarantees nothing for you.
You're powerless.
You're utterly powerless.
Pros and cons of monarchy. We will not
go into that right now. I've spoken
about that for hours.
Right? A benevalent monarchy. I'll just
give you examples of bene benevolent
monarchs. Chhatraati Shivaji Maharaj,
the Marata Empire,
the Chola Empire,
the Gupta Empire, Rajendra Chula, Rajar
Chula,
Scandanda Gupta, Kumar Gupta,
Samudra Gupta. Weren't they not were
they great for India or not? Kaneshka
Kaneshka the great
right Chandra Gupta Moria
who was Lord Ram was he not a monarch
who was Shri Krishna was he not a
monarch that's enough examples that that
should hopefully give you the point
okay
uh Kshai Surya says going abroad isn't
great but is it lesser evil go abroad
who's saying it's not good individuals
should take care of their own decisions
indiv individually, right?
There's nothing wrong with you going
abroad.
Yeah. Nothing wrong with it.
Um, Sid says, "Don't you think India has
more problems internally than
externally?" I think so. Yes. Yes.
Okay.
Deepak dating coach.
Deepak dating coach. Okay. I'm a
longtime viewer of watcher of your
videos. Thank you so much, sir. Thank
you indeed. A few years ago you were
quite positive about India's progress
but now your tone is quite pessimistic.
I do agree with you actually love to
invite you on my channel for a podcast
in the future. Well, you see as times
change, you have to
change the way you look at. You see what
I do is I analyze what's happening and I
analyze the direction in which the world
is going, the country is going. When
things change, I have to be truthful to
my audience, right?
Or should I just keep pretending that
you know what, everything is great,
everything is fine.
There's there's plenty of people who do
that on YouTube, right?
But that's not me. I'm going to be
truthful to you all as things change.
I'm going to tell you what's actually
happening the way I see it. Now, it's up
to you whether you want to agree or not
with me. But, uh, things have changed
over the past few years. See, I first
became a came on YouTube in what 2021? I
think 2020, but I started doing the ask
show in 2021
and things were different at that time.
And things have changed since then. So
if things are changing, you will see
that reflected in the way I analyze
things. Um
yeah, things have changed a lot. But you
agree but you actually agree with me.
Well, I'm glad you do, sir. Thank you.
All right. If you want me on your
channel, I I can certainly consider
that. Please send me an email or
something. Uh my email ID will be there
in the description below. You can check
it out. All right. So sir, thank you so
much. Debaki
past snail says is Russia pausing
Ukraine supporting India a poss Iran a
possibility well theoretically it's a
possibility but if if Russia pauses
Ukraine then obviously they may
face the possibility that Ukraine may
make some advances and some gains in the
territorial gains or whatever right but
if you don't want to to allow Ukraine to
make territorial gains then you have to
keep your forces on the ground. Not just
keep your force on the ground, you have
to keep on doing whatever you were
doing. So
Russia pausing Ukraine
means no means nothing. Even if you want
to pause the war, you have to keep your
troops on the ground, right?
You can't withdraw your troops and say,
you know what, Ukraine, let's give it a
break of two two months. We're going to
move out. You stay where you are. You
don't take any ter any territory and
we'll be back in two months and we'll
resume fighting. Does it work like that?
It doesn't work like that. Right?
So, as long as even if you want to
freeze the the the conflict in Ukraine,
you have to maintain your force posture
there. You have to maintain your full
military strength there. Even if you
want to freeze the conflict and not have
any going back territorially, you still
have to keep your entire military
posture intact.
Right?
So if Russia wants to support Iran, it
will have to fight two wars at the same
time. Yeah, two wars at the same time.
Rajan Beir says, "Is Muslim unity in
this war possible or not?" I don't
really know what you're asking. Muslim
unity.
If there was Muslim unity in the world,
would you not have a single Islamic
nation?
Right.
So yeah
um I'm not exactly sure what you're
asking but Muslim I don't know if it
even exists. Yeah. Sergeant Skylin says
this attack explains why India let go of
Chabahar.
So are you saying India was aware of it?
Are you saying India was aware that this
attack would happen?
Yeah. Okay. Adit Chandra says, "Is the
combined military power of Russia and
China even a match for the US?" No. No.
No. It's not. It's not.
Even if Russia and China come together
to fight the US, they will still get
whacked. They'll still lose. That's how
powerful the US is. Okay.
Um, as long as you keep the mil the
nuclear factor out of the picture
from a nuclear perspective, Russia is
more powerful than the US from from a
nuclear warheads strength perspective.
But yeah, if you disregard the nuclear
angle, the nuclear factor, then Russia
plus China together, even if they're
combined, they are not strong enough to
match the US. Now, is Prime Minister
Modi's timing of his visit to Israel
coincidental or does it have anything to
do with the attacks on Iran?
It's not coincidental,
but it is not as such linked to the
attacks in Iran in the sense that India
had something to do with it. No,
but it's all part of the larger scheme
of things and the realignment that's
happening in the world.
It's very much part of the realignment
that's happening in the world. But it is
not related to the attack on Iran in the
sense that India had something to do
with India has nothing to do with it.
India is simply
essentially a nation that has to accept
what the more powerful nations are
doing. And the only choice India has is
do we stay out of it or do we support
them or do we oppose them? India
essentially stays out of it and you have
to eventually pick a side if you're weak
and that's what India seems to be doing
now. So India doesn't have anything to
do with the attacks on Iran but India
most likely would have known that this
was going to happen India most likely
would also have known when it was going
to happen.
Shriikand go says since India stopped
Chabahar funding don't you think it's a
minor step toward towards vasalage? All
these small small steps they are all
minor steps towards vasaj but if all if
you have a lot of minor steps towards
varaj happening together it's concerning
don't you think
h it's a pattern then
vdan vive says hexagonal alliance so
India plus UAE plus Saudi plus Qatar
yeah Israel said something about a
hexagonal alliance so who could those
nations
See India and Israel are together
even before all the vasalad stories
started. India, UAE and and Israel
are involved in a parallel competition
with Pakistan, Saudi Arabia and Turkey.
Okay.
So Saudi Arabia, Pakistan, Turkey are on
one side in West Asia and opposing in an
on the opposing side you have Israel,
UAE and India.
So in a hexagonal alliance, Saudi Arabia
won't be there. Qatar could be there
because Qatar
because Qatar is Qatar. So who could the
hexagonal alliance be? Israel, India,
UAE, US, that's four. If if Qatar is
there, that's five. Maybe Oman. I don't
know.
I don't know. I'm not sure exactly who
the hexagon who the different sides of
this polygon are, but Yeah. Yeah. Okay.
Now, before I take other questions,
let's quickly scan Twitter and see
what's happening.
Let's see what's happening, shall we? Um
let's let me put this on the screen so
that we look at this together and let's
take a look at what is happening right
now. Let's first look at the India
thing. India's ministry of external
affairs. Let's see what India has to
say.
5 hours ago we posted something. 1 hour
ago.
Okay. Our statement of the evolving
situation in West Asia. Let's see what
India's what stance India is taking.
India is deeply concerned
at the recent developments in Iran and
the Gulf region. We urge all sides to
exercise restraint, avoid escalation and
prioritize the safety of citizens.
Dialogue in diplomacy blah blah blah
blah blah.
Dialogue and diplomacy should be pursued
to deescalate tensions and address
underlying issues. sovereignty in terms
in the region are in touch with Indian
nationals and have issued appropriate
advisories asking them to blah blah blah
blah blah okay so India has nothing to
actually say in this India is saying
that everybody please deescalate don't
fight be good boys which means India
doesn't really matter in this matter
okay India is deeply concerned are you
doing something about that no we are
issuing a statement okay has Netanyahu
said something let's find out Has there
been some further news from Netanyahu?
No. His last statement was 6 hours ago.
Has the Department of War said
something? Let's see. Let's refresh the
page.
Okay, let's refresh. Refresh. Refresh.
Let's Okay, let's remove this. Let's
refresh. Okay, they have said nothing
since they said this. Operation Epic
Fury.
Operation Epic Fury. Now, that's what
colle what I call a distraction from the
Epstein files.
I'm attacking Iran because they have
nuclear weapons. Why don't you attack
Russia? Are you crazy? They have nuclear
weapons.
Oh, I love it. Very funny.
Okay. Okay. Okay. All right.
Yeah. So, there's a lot of skepticism
from the people, but yeah. Uh the
department of war of war of the US has
not tweeted anything since then 6 hours
ago as Shri Trump's Trump tweeted
something. Let's see.
Even his last tweet was from 7 hours ago
about the the war.
Okay. What does this account have to
say?
Anything interesting? Anything uh that
gives us updates? Okay. Breaking.
Iran says Supreme Leader Kame will give
a speech just hours after the US and
Israel targeted him in assassination
attempts. Just one hour ago, Israeli
media said that the odds survived the
strikes are slim to none. The world now
awaits the supposed speech. Okay, let's
see. So, Israel seems to be claiming
that KA may not have survived their
strikes.
Iran issues a response to the US and
Israeli strikes offering terms for
potential deescalation. One, Iran does
not have missiles targeting capable of
targeting the US, reaching the US. Iran
will not develop missiles capable of
reaching the US. Iran will not give up
the right to enrich uranium. Iran is
interested in deescalation. China and
Russia request meeting of the UN
Security Council on Iran. Iran says if
the US wants to talk, they will know how
to reach out. Um, it may be a little
late for all that. Okay.
What else is there?
Uh, Iran's foreign minister comments on
US and Israeli strikes getting Supreme
Leader Kam. He's alive as far as I know.
Iran may have lost a few commanders, but
that's not a very big problem. Iran's
defense minister and a commander of the
Iranian revolutionary revolutionary
guard have been killed by strikes in
Iran. Who's Iran's defense minister?
Let us see who is Iran's defense
minister
Aziz Nazir Zad.
Okay.
Um okay. So
this is what this account is saying.
What else do we have?
Do we have anything here?
Not sure.
Right. So Iran has not hit Israel yet.
They sent very few missiles. It seems
the focus is on the American radars in
their bases in Gulf countries. Iran
wants to blind the US first. They
started this process last time with the
strike on Alud. That's why Iran hit Gulf
countries first more heavily. The
strikes were on satellite and
communications installations and so on.
Okay. So, is there anything
else happening? UAE.
Okay. The UAE has put out a statement.
The Ministry of Defense announced that
the UA today was subjected to blatant
attack involving Iran ballistic missiles
and so on. Okay. Yeah. So, the war is
there. Allout war. Do we have something
in Thran? Any more any news?
Um,
don't know what that is. We saw flight
radar. That's fine. What's the latest?
What's the latest?
Let's see. Um,
okay. Second rocket hit Dubai. Really?
A rocket hit hit Dubai, apparently? I
mean, that's what someone's claiming
over here.
Okay. So, what is this? This is in
Turkish.
And there's what not going on. Iran
starts targeting US air bases. Where is
this? I'm not playing the video here but
okay
and so on. Nothing. So we don't know
anything. Okay. So uh that's kind of the
latest situation.
Um no major uptick in the war
but yeah let's let's keep an eye on
that. Okay. What's next? Yeah I dealt
with this question. Yes. Uh what is
next? Uh Kajor Betaththon says, "Did not
you predicted Christian Iran. He also
made the much crazier prediction of a
Jewish Saudi and Hindu UAE by 2040." You
mean okay idea of soldiers wear greater
Israel patches with Saudi in it. Saudi
is liberalizing Black Rockck by
um Okay. I do expect that if the US wins
and does a regime change in Iran, the
future of Iran is most likely Christian.
That's how I see it.
Jewish Saudi Arabia, Hindu UAE. Well, if
you look at the UAE, realistically about
40% or so of the UAE population is
Hindu. But that's not UAE citizens.
That's the population. The UAE does not
give citizenship.
They give you long-term visas, right? 10
year visas or whatever
uh if you want to reside there but they
don't give you citizenship. So you may
have 40% of the population being Hindu
but they are not citizens. So um Hindu
UAE well it's not entirely impossible
but uh okay uh Jewish Saudi Arabia I
don't see that happening by 20 by 2040
Jewish Saudi Arabia.
Okay that's interesting. Anyhow, okay.
Uh, IDF soldiers wear greater Israel
patches with Saudi in it. Okay.
I I didn't know that. Okay. Deep learner
says, "Do you think it's a sign? Do you
think a sign of this development
vasilization
is USA will push will try to push
alternative leaders India inside BJP
against Yogi? I I will not comment about
Indian politics. I never do that. So
yeah.
Um
but yeah theoretically
when you are vasalized
see what happens when you're a vasal
country when you are a vasal state the
overlord the master
re-engineers your internal system such
that you can never produce real leaders.
If a real leader is produced by mistake
that's it's a mistake it's an accident.
But they will re-engineer the system
such that you will never produce real
leaders. You will produce people who
look like leaders, who speak like like
leaders but who serve the foreign
overlord.
Okay?
No real person of substance will be
allowed to become a leader. They will
only allow people to rise to leadership
positions who are compromised. That's
what typically happens theoretically
when you have a state that is a vasal
state and is serving a master state.
That's what happens. I mean look at the
leaders in Europe all they do is talk
allegedly many of them maybe allegedly
possibly compromised in some ways and
yeah so theoretically that that's how it
works
says why wasn't Japan crushed even after
wasalhood what did they suffer from a
common man's perspective apart from
military bases and the constitution
being written by the US they resisted
Christianization as well great questions
great questions because that allows me
to explain how this works.
Japan was not crushed after Vasalud.
Japan
in 1945 came under permanent US military
occupation. But after that happened,
Japan was allowed to rise again. See in
1945 when the Americans took over Japan,
Japan was a bunch of smoldering ruins.
Two cities were full of radiation from
nuclear tests and all the industries
were destroyed.
Cities were flattened.
Japan was destroyed in 1945 when the
Americans took over. But by the 1960s,
Japan was on its feet. Japan was
becoming a technological powerhouse
again. Japan.
So Japan was not crashed. Japan was
allowed to rise.
Japan's industries were allowed to rise.
Japan was now allowed to become the most
technologically advanced nation in the
world. Why? Why? Because it served US
interests.
Okay.
Who who was consuming the that
technology? The US. They were consuming
it from a nation they owned. So they
were fine with it. And if the US wanted
the technology, the Japanese had no way
of saying no. So they allowed Japan to
rise. They allowed the Japanese people
to develop technologies, fantastic
technologies.
But today those technologies are all
across the US. The Japanese developed
the Look at this phone. It's a Look at
this camera I'm using right now. the
Sony camera. Sony,
Honda, Yamaha,
Mitsubishi, Seikko, Casio, all these
fantastic techn companies developed all
these fantastic technologies.
But today the Americans have better
technology
because all the technology was never
safe from the Americans. So the Japanese
were allowed to rise rise rise. By the
1980s they became the second most
powerful economy in the world. And then
the Americans did the Plaza Accords and
then Japan slowly gradually declined
declined in such a way nobody noticed
until now. It's only in the 2000s and
2010s that people started noticing that
Japan is now going backwards.
And today you have a situation in Japan
where Japan is no longer a high income
nation. It was one of the highest income
nations in the world. Today Japan is
like a middle- inome nation. That's how
far Japan has declined. Japan's economy
is stagnating. It's been stagnating for
decades now. and Japan's TFR has been
destroyed.
In a 100 years, there will be no
Japanese left.
That's how you destroy a nation in slow
motion.
Yeah.
And she says, "My god, it's depressing.
You'll be fine. Don't worry. We'll all
be fine individually.
It is what it is." See, there are good
times, there are bad times. You got to
deal with it.
Mr. Comrad says, "What will happen to
the Chabahar project? Once the Americans
take over the the nation of Iran, they
may invite India back into Chabahar."
Okay.
Enjoy Chabahar. Take take a couple of
terminals. Operate operate it. We'll
we'll allow you go.
That's what could happen to Javahar.
They may allow India to operate a couple
of terminals in Chabahar
after they take over Iran. It's
possible.
Vidi Mana says good to see you ma'am.
What's coming for India now? Will
businesses get affected? Will businesses
get affected? No. India will continue
the way it is right now.
India I don't see it becoming uh I'll be
very surprised if it becomes a major
manufacturing power like we have been
sloganering for the past 10 years
what's coming for for India India will
in India it'll be for everybody on the
streets of everybody all individual
people it will be business as usual
nothing much will change there'll be no
major changes in India
India will not become a gigantic
powerful nation by 2045 2050 India will
be at 10 12 trillion dollar economy
possibly
and um yeah it will be business as
usual. India will remain what it what
India is for the time being. I mean the
kind of nation and India has been since
1944 47 the kind of standards we've had
we're going to maintain that for the
next 20 30 whatever years long-term
we'll see. So nothing major no major
changes are coming to India.
Then our leaders will keep saying we are
doing great. All right. Prataradhana
says we should keep pushing for
education reform and spend money on R&D.
R&D spending must reach 2% of GDP. Sir
immigration is becoming more difficult.
Sir I agree with you but I am not in
charge of this.
I agree with you. I I could not disagree
less. I completely agree with you. We
need large scale top tobottom thorough
education reforms. We need that.
But the government is saying that we did
the reform. The new education policy
2020 is the reform. Enjoy it. It'll be
in force full force by 2030 or wherever.
So in India, you do a new education
policy, you bring it into being in
existence in 2020 and it actually starts
be becoming effective by the 2030s.
That's how slow things are in India. And
even that new education policy is
garbage. It doesn't address any of the
real underlying issues in the education
system. It addresses none of those
issues.
So yeah, we should keep pushing for it.
We should keep saying we need education
reform. I agree with you. We need it. We
should spend money on on R&D. I agree
with that too completely. I could not
disagree at all with this. R&D should be
like for a nation like India should be
at least 2% 3% of GDP.
But who will do it?
Who controls the money? Who controls the
funding? The government. The private
companies can also do it.
But they're not doing it right. They're
giving dividends to their shareholders.
low enjoy
enjoy the dividends they're not pushing
that money back into R&D they don't do
any R&D
so there is this entire
situation in India the standards are
such that
yeah they the people who are in charge
don't want any change
but you will say that young people want
change you will say that the people the
young entrepreneurs they want change if
you look at the people who are running
these new startups they are investing in
R&D whatever little money they have.
So there is this tremendous desire in
India for better standards for for
research and development for excellence
for success.
Young people they all want this.
A lot of young people want this. A lot
of intelligent people who are in India
they want this.
But but
Pranjal Bishra says, "Do you think that
despite all the talks about
multipolarity, we are headed towards a
more erup world?" How are Chinese
ambitions affected?
See, one thing I've been saying since 21
is ignore words and look at actions.
Talk is cheap. Talk talk. Everyone will
do multipolarity. Yay. This that
everything that's all talk. But where is
the world actually headed? The world is
indeed headed towards multi towards
uniolarity.
The world is headed towards uniolarity.
All this talk of multipolarity,
multi-alignment, multipolar world.
Um multipolarity is a is a is a
intermediate phase. It's a metastable
phase like you would say in physics and
chemistry. It's a metastable phase. It's
a temporary intermediate state step
between uh two outcomes. So you had a
uniolar world. You had a bipolar world
in the 20th century, the cold war. Then
the cold war ended, the USSR
disintegrated. Then you had a uniolar
world for about 20 years. 20 years or
so. That was the American unipolar
moment. Then the Chinese came up on the
stage. We are now a big deal. Yeah.
Yeah. We're going to be a big deal
because of our economic strength. And
that went on until the end of the COVID
era,
until the end of the Biden regime. Then
with the with the with with the
Americans pushing putting Trump forth,
they have decided that that that
signaled that they have decided to
completely shake the shake the world
order and show what real power is.
Real power isn't me necessarily economic
power. actual
military power and the the ability to
reshape the world order. That's what
they're doing. So, we are once again
going back towards
uh possibly uniolarity. What what does
China have that the US doesn't?
Nothing.
What advantages does China have? China
probably is is a very advanced
technological country. It's very
technologically advanced now. They the
Chinese probably have the best education
system in the world and they are
technologically almost as good as the US
in some sectors at least. So the only
hope China has of surviving a uniolar
world is if they get ahead of the US in
the key core critical technologies like
um AI etc. But um that's a long shot for
for China
and China is is is frightened of
military confrontation with the US as
they rightfully should be.
Yeah. So the world is most likely going
towards the uni unipolar world again.
The next 5 years will be the crucial
years. In 5 years we'll know exactly
what's going to happen in this century.
The next five years are critical.
Sergeant Skylan says PM Modi visited
Israel recently. He might have been
briefed. I am 100% sure that he was
briefed.
Ritik Yadwanchi says, "Hide your
strength by your time is the only thing
that India can do. I hope the next
leadership grows a spine and makes the
massive reforms we need."
I hope so. I hope so. Yes,
I agree with you and I hope so, sir.
Indeed.
P9057
S to you. Thank you sir. Thank you sir
ma'am. Thank you so much.
Pratarana says direct hit by a shahed
drone on a US radar in Bahrain. Well I
would not be surprised. Let's once again
take a look at um
give me a second. Let's re my only
source of information right now at least
is Twitter. Okay. So, we're going to
keep an eye on Twitter and see what's
happening there. From time to time.
Yeah,
here we are.
Um, what do we have? What do we have?
Okay, I'm not going into politics. This
is Dubai allegedly right now. What's
going on in Dubai?
Oh no, some kind of air strike, missile
strike possibly. What else do we have?
Dubai once again. Well, well, well,
well, well, well, well. Uh, Razabah is
saying something. What is Razabah
saying? Razabah, the pretender. My dear
compatriots, decisive moments lie before
us. The assistance that the president of
the US has promised and so on is
arrived.
Islamic regime is republic is
collapsing.
You have sworn an oath to protect Iran
and so on so forth. any message blah
blah blah sensitive hours and days
reclaiming Iran. So his ultimate goal is
to reclaim Iran
and follow messages and so on. Okay.
Okay sir, thank you for your message. We
get it. Uh what else is happening?
Thran, Dubai, DHA.
Um this is okay.
What else do we have? What's what's look
at the trending topics? Iran must be
there. Bourj Khalifa, Thran, Hifa.
Um,
okay. You are saying this a Shahed drone
on Bahrain. Let's see. Bahin. Bahrain.
What happened?
Iran just fired missiles at five
countries. That's okay. That's We know
that.
Bahrain. Let's see latest.
I don't see cats at this time.
Um,
let's see. Bahin, what's the
bah bahin? Maybe that will give us some
idea. Iranian shahed drone targets US
radar. Yeah, it looks like that. This
looks like a shahed drone. Yes.
So it's flying in and then it hits.
Yeah, that's a radar. Oh, well well
well.
Okay.
In Manama in Bahrain. Okay. Well, that's
the cost of war obviously. What do you
expect?
So this is about this happen seems to
have happened very recently
5 minutes 6 minutes ago.
Um this is the aftermath of that I
suppose.
Okay. Okay.
All right. So, this is an evolving
situation obviously.
So, yeah. Okay. Okay.
Right. Fast snail says, "Can India
really say with conviction it supports
Israel because regime change in Iran is
not really in its best interests?"
Well,
of course, it's not in our interests.
I've been saying that for a long time.
But the Americans, if they have started
the war, they will end it. They're just
too powerful for Iran.
Um,
so
what is India is not saying anything.
That's the point right now. If you look
at the Twitter account of the Minister
of Foreign Affairs of India, they're not
saying we support this or support that.
They're saying this is not a time for
war. We urge all sides to go and
negotiate and not fight like bad boys
and all. That's the sort of thing that's
coming out of the Indian Ministry of
External Affairs. This is
Yeah. So that's that's we not saying we
support Israel. We're not saying we
support Iran. We're saying stop
fighting. And we know no one's going to
stop fighting,
right?
uh regime change in Iran is not in our
best interests. Well, it depends. It
depends. If we have decided that we will
be part of the American orbit now,
then it will make no difference to us
whether there's a regime change in Iran
or not.
So, yeah.
Verdan Vivik says war started at the end
of US stock market closed. Oh, okay.
Okay.
Yeah. Okay.
Sloita says, "Has India lost its
sovereignty and become a vasal?" Yes/
no.
Um
I I I want
it's it's possible that there are four
vasal states in four sovereign nations
in the world now. It's possible.
Uh let's let's still wait and watch for
a few more weeks. Yeah. Indications are
India has decided is India has decided
to become part of the US orbit.
Indications are like that and if you are
a regular watcher of the channel I've
said this
I've been saying this that
there's a high chance that in within the
next 5 years India becomes an American
masal. I've said that right I've said
that multiple times.
Um maybe it won't take 5 years. See, I'm
I'm I'm hopeful it never happens. But if
you look at all the indications, it
looks like India is the government of
India seems to have made the decision
that it is safer for us to be part of
the American orbit possibly, but still
not 100% guaranteed, but the indications
are there.
Mr. Rohit says, "Is it good for Prime
Minister Modi to visit genocidal
Netanyahu?
What has he done to Gaza? Israel is an
important defensive partner. But what
about humanity?
This is geopolitics. This is national
interest.
You don't care about humanity in these
matters. See, geopolitics is amoral.
It's not immoral. It's amoral.
Mr. Modi's job is to serve his country
and the people of his country.
And if you have to deal, if you have to
be friends, let's say, with a nation
that's fighting a war against some
people, even if it's hypothetically an
unjust war,
it doesn't matter to us. Mr. Modi's job
is to serve his country and his people
only. Mr. Modi's job is not to serve the
world. This is the problem in India that
we imagine that we have to look, we have
to serve humanity. No, you have to s
there are there's a reason why the world
has borders.
Each leader has one job. Serve your
people and serve your country.
And you have inhuman nations next to us.
Pakistan is the world's biggest
terrorist regime.
That's one example.
So I from my perspective,
Gaza is not important for us. The people
of Gaza support Pakistan by the way.
And why is whatever has happened to
Gaza, why has it happened? Because of
what they did to the the terrorist
attack that carried out in October 2020,
what 24 was it? Whenever it was.
So,
Israel is an important partner for for
India. So, Mr. Modi is completely right
to visit Israel and he's completely
right to to strengthen India's
relationship with Israel to what about
humanity? What about the humanity of of
the people of India?
The people of Gaza support Pakistan
which has been fighting this inhuman
terrorist war against the people of
India. What about that? Why are we
concerned about the humanity of people
of Gaza but not the people of India?
We still have lacks of Kashmiri pundits
who are not able to go back to their own
homeland. Where is the humanity in that
but we are not concerned about them. We
are concerned about Gaza. I don't
understand this sir. Really
humanity doesn't matter in geopolitics.
Your national interest is all that
matters. That's just the way of the
world. It may sound very inhuman and
whatever but it is what it is.
The praepar says can Iran blockade Gulf
of Aan using Houthis? They can try.
They've tried that in the past. Uh the
Houthis
between 24 and 26, they blockaded the
Gulf of Adan, didn't they? They
blockaded the uh straight of Babal
Mandib
and they did not allow ships to pass
through the the straight. Let me show
you on the map.
So the Houthis did succeed. The Ansar
Allah faction in in Yemen. See this this
straight, the Babal Mandibra was
blockaded by the Houthis and the
Americans launched hundreds of air
strikes on the Houthis
and they were unable to destroy the
Houthi regime, the Houthi leadership,
the Houthi power. They were unable to
destroy that. So eventually the Houthi
said, "Okay, we will allow American
ships to pass, but we will not allow
Israeli ships to pass." and the
Americans could do could not do a thing
about that.
So, uh it is possible that there could
be something happening in this region
also right now that we are not aware of
possibly because you don't have any
western observers in this region
typically, right? You will have western
observers in this region but not there.
Uh so Iran can possibly
instruct the Houthis to blockade the
Gulf of Adan, the straight of Babal
Mandib. The Iranians still haven't
blockaded the straight of hormones yet
as far as I know. But let's see. All
these all the all of these plays are
very much possible in the coming days. A
blockade of the straight of hormones is
possible and a blockade of the straight
of Babal Mandib is also possible. That
could be happening now or it could
happen in the coming days. It's
definitely a possibility. Yes.
Um, Dvod Asputra says, "MBZ
in India,
Modi in Israel. Has India chosen a
side?"
Looks like India is in the process of
choosing a st a side.
Looks like that. Looks like India is
choosing the West.
Yeah.
Yeah. Looks like that.
If you look at all the different pieces
of indications and you put them
together, they are indeed forming a
pattern that India is choosing a side
and it's not Russia and China. It's not
bricks, it's the US,
India is just too compromised.
Ready always ready says India will
become 10 trillion in 10 years.
Why are you saying India will be a
vasal? Because economic size doesn't
matter. My goodness, do you people learn
nothing from me? Do you people learn
nothing from me? Japan was the world's
second largest economy in the 1980s.
It was almost neck-to- neck with the US
while being under US occupation.
Economy makes no difference whatsoever.
Will you people not learn anything from
me? Why am I doing all this?
Why do I spend all these hours talking
to you and explaining things? Don't you
people pay attention sometimes?
You can be a complete slave while
becoming an economic giant.
Okay, let's let's see the world's
largest economist in the 1980s. Okay,
let's see this
um
top five economies
economies in in the world 1985
the US was 4.34 trillion Japan was
second 1.43 43 trillion and the others
we don't even know. So Japan was
all the way at second spot while being
under permanent US military occupation
being a full-fledged American vasal. It
was number two in the world.
It's like being what 1520 trillion
economy today
while being a vasal. So please let's not
delude ourselves and imagine everything
is economic size economic uh strength is
everything.
The posture co says maybe it's time for
Yogi to take over ASAP.
Well it's time for a lot of change but
does the change happen? Will the change
be allowed to happen? I have been saying
it's time for lots of deep reforms in
India. It may be time, but will it
happen is the question, right? Shivanch
says, "Iran's defense minister has been
taken out already." That's what I'm
hearing. That's what I saw just a while
ago on Twitter. Apparently, the defense
minister of Iran has been um like you
say, taken out. This is war. This is
war. You see, war is nasty. War is
brutal. Anime Barati has gifted Barati
has gifted 10 memberships of the travel.
Thank you very much, sir. Thank you so
much. That's very kind of you. I thank
you on behalf of me and the 10 people
who have received this gift. Thank you
so much, sir.
Kajura Thornon says, "Scyroing debt,
crime, cultural rot, illegal
immigration, falling TFR. Does the
health of the US nation have no effect
on the US empire?
Skyrocketing debt that debt is entirely
constructed by the US itself?" I'm not
sure if even high call high caliber
economists fully understand the
structure of debt. A lot of the debt
that the US owes is to itself. Do you
know that a lot of the debt is owed to
itself
and of course there's the treasury bonds
and all that. That's one component of
the debt. So yeah, there is debt but the
debt is in US dollars. Do you understand
that? The debt makes no real big
difference. The US can wipe out the debt
by playing some some tricks.
So there is debt, crime, there is crime,
but the US has always been that sort of
nation where crime is just barely held
in check through the use of the police.
The US is a police state. Much of
Western Europe is is bunch of police
states. So you have that cultural rot.
Yeah, sure. Anyway, what's US culture
anyway? Does the US even have a culture?
Cultural rot. You look at immigration.
Now the US can smash it can squash
illegal immigration if it wants. So it's
not like India where India is completely
helpless in front of illegal
immigration. In the US the the US knows
exactly where each il illegal immigrant
is and they can deport them all very
quickly following TFR. Yes. So uh is the
US in in bad health? It's not in great
health but it's not in terrible health
either.
It's not in the same kind of rude health
it was in in the 1950s. It's not that
way. Yeah, the US has declined. The
standards have declined in the US. The
education system is terrible compared to
what you had in the 1950s, but still
heavenly compared to India.
Um,
so this all is going to have long-term
effects
on the strength and viability and
longevity of the US empire, but no
short-term effects.
Short-term, the US is great. It's in
great shape. Long-term, 50 years, 100
years, yeah, it's going to have an
effect, but not next 3 years, next 5
years, next 10 years. 50 years, 100
years, yeah, there's going to be an
effect of this. Not short term. Yeah.
Shubat Shukla says Shukla Shourat Shubat
Shukla says after BJP lost regime change
in Bangladesh Hindu genocide Bangladesh
Bahalgam attack happens after BJP lost
majority hence no big reforms coming did
USA pre-planeted I I don't know I can't
say uh BJP lost BJP lost majority yeah
BJP lost the majority in 2024 right it's
a minority government it's it's a
coalition government now um did the US
pre-plan it well there's definitely
going to be foreign interference in your
electoral matters. For sure. For sure.
India is so badly penetrated by foreign
social media platforms and so many other
things that there's going to be
electoral interference in India. Of
course, but if India decides to become a
vasal state, then you may not have that
much interference. You see
um
so yeah there there is definitely
foreign interference in our electoral
affairs no question about that.
Um IPK says bat bat gaja became b okay
instead of dharaja
no comments no comments I don't discuss
these matters but I think you all know
where I stand on this
polariz says if we get vasalized
is UT the economy that will be
controlled first UT
The econ is it the economy is it the is
it the economy it will be controlled
first?
No. If you are vasalized the first
control they when you become a vasal
what do they first control? They first
penetrate you thoroughly.
They control
the system, the institutions,
the political let's say parties. That's
what they control first. Then
controlling the economy becomes a
cakewalk.
You don't how will you control the
economy without controlling the the
entire system.
So when you vasalize a country, you
penetrate deep within.
You control all the people who actually
wield the levers of power at various
levels in the country.
Then once you have that done, once you
have once you have once you have full
control over all the institutions,
whether it's the bureaucracy, whether is
is whatever whatever whatever whatever
then
and you don't have to control it by
force. There are so many nice ways of
controlling people, right? And
controlling institutions.
So the economy eventually will get
controlled if you are vasalized. Yes,
Wenut. Thank you very much. Wenut
Ravitija. Thank you very much sir. Thank
you.
Honey Sharma says is if India is
allegedly a wasal, do you think the
Chinese are regretting it right now
because they have another US in their
neighborhood and they they never did
anything to make make peace with India
demarcating border.
Do you think China let's say India it's
a interesting question Honey Sharma is
asking very interesting question
actually
so let's say hypothetically in two weeks
time hypothetically of course
hypothetically in two weeks time India
becomes a US facile hypothetically will
the Chinese regret it that you know we
allowed this to happen because we were
not nice to India we never agreed to
demarcate the border and so on will the
Chinese regret it won't regret it why
because The Chinese haven't made India a
Wasal. The Chinese did not push India
towards Vasalhood. Let's say
let's say interesting question actually
multiple angles I can think of. Okay,
imagine that 5 years ago China agreed to
demarcating the border with India. Okay,
let's let's shake hands. Let's let
bygones be bygones. Let's demarcate the
border and be friendly. Now if that had
happened then ra could have happened
possibly it you would have a higher
chance of ra then bricks could have
become more powerful then India and
China would have been strongly
integrated even more economically.
So if China had agreed 5 years ago to
demarcate the border and normalize the
situation with India
then maybe there would be less of a
likelihood of India being forced to
become a US vasal down the line.
So if India does become a US vasal
hypothetically
and
that change that that changes things for
the worse for China, China will regret
it. Yeah.
So if China had in the past 5 years ago,
let's say hypothetically agreed to
demarket the border and normalize the
relationship with India, then it would
have been less likely for India in the
future to become a vasal. So China may
regret that behavior actually. Yeah,
that is entirely China's fault. Very
interesting question. Yeah, very
interesting, sir. Very interesting.
Hazy says your bets on the outcome of US
versus rest of 191 countries 190 is it
an if or a when that Europe joins the
rest of the world US hgemony for 100 200
years
but the US is not you know up against
191 countries most of the countries that
matter are American vasals
already
it's true that right now the US is
treating its vasals badly
but when you're a vasal you have no
choice. is right. What can I do about
it? Uh so the US is indeed treating its
vasals somewhat
badly right now. Trump is being very
nasty. Yeah. Uh but the rest of the
countries of the world can't really
stand up to the US. So is it a if or a
when that Europe joins the rest of the
Europe is already a bunch of vasals,
right? See there are two cate there are
there is Eastern Europe and there's
Western Europe. In Western Europe there
are two categories of nations. One is
the NATO nations and the other is the EU
nations. And a lot of NATO nations are
also EU nations. So if you're a member
of NATO, you are a US vasal. If you're
member of EU, you aren't fully sovereign
and you are indirectly controlled in
some way or the other by the US. So
Europe has already joined the ranks of
the vasals.
A long long time ago, West Germany came
under US occupation in 1945 when Germany
was reunified. The whole of Germany came
under US occupation.
Military occupation. Germany has been
under permanent US military occupation
since 1945. You may not realize it, but
it's the case. Same for Italy.
So, um, and if the US succeeds in the
current regime change operation in Iran,
it isolates China even more and China
will face massive problems when it comes
to energy security. The US can shut down
the tap
that of oil that flows to China.
on demand the US can now do it. You
understand this war is not just about
Iran, it's also about China.
So if the US succeeds here, which it
most likely will, then the US could rule
the world. If it wins the technological
race, AI race, it could rule the world
for the next 200 years. Very possible.
Yep.
Humanity survives. Thank you very much,
sir. Thank you.
Hanish says if India is now a vasal,
will you be allowed to speak like this
publicly in the future or you will have
to face consequences like Tommy
Robinson?
I don't know what Tommy Robinson says or
whatever. Um
I don't know what consequences he has
faced. There are lots of people in the
US who speak against US policies and I'm
not opposed to the US in principle as
such. The US is a fantastic country.
There's a lot to admire in the US. I am
for India's sovereignty
and I am not as such as an enemy of any
nation including the US. So I don't
think there'll be an issue for me. Yeah,
there are plenty of people even in the
US who speak up against specific
policies of the US. I don't think
there's going to be any issue if if
India does become.
Okay.
Anik says Putin visited India two months
before the um UA war. What's the UA war?
A Ukraine war. Okay. Putin visited India
two months before the Ukraine war and in
and Modi knew about the war. India
started buying Russian oil immediately.
That doesn't that make us you Russian
Wasal, right?
No, it does not make us a Russian Wasal.
It makes us a Russian partner.
It makes us you could say quasi allied
with Russia.
It doesn't make India Russian vasal.
Do you understand what vasalhood means?
It means remote control.
It means remote control of one one
nation by another country which benefits
from this remote control and it
victimizes this country. That's washood.
Vasalhood is a master slave relationship
in which one nation benefits and one
nation suffers. Sometimes you don't even
realize in what ways this nation is
suffering. Sometimes the suffering is
not apparent to anybody.
That is all. The India Russia
relationship is not vasal.
Okay.
Okay. I hope that clarifies the matter.
Understand what Vasal is about. One
nation benefiting and one nation
suffering.
Mr. Rohit says why Prime Minister Modi
has not done open press conference in
India. I I say and that's not a question
for me. You should ask Prime Minister
Modi with that question. And anyway,
this is a political question. I don't
deal with Indian politics, sir. Please.
No, no. Ask ask Mr. Modi. Don't ask me.
Pratik Kumar Royce is Russia Ukraine war
update.
It's it's um
it's a war of attrition. It's a frozen
conflict. You know, it's just going on.
There's nothing notable to discuss right
now. The lines on the map are mostly
holding. Uh Russia is in control of
roughly you could say 1/5 or 1/4 of
Ukraine of the earthwilile territory of
Ukraine including Crimea and the Donbas
region and uh right now it looks like
the war could end through non-military
um means possibly maybe some kind of
agreement or or something. So nothing
major to update or or discuss about the
Russia Ukraine war.
Uh Barat Barat M. Kulkarnney thank you
very much sir. Thank you.
Pratip Kumar Royce's Professor Jang
predicted US Iran war after Trump wins
two years back. Shock. Well,
look,
it was apparent at some point in time
the Americans will take out Iran.
Okay,
so it's not that big of a surprise that
this has happened. But okay, kudos to
Professor Young. Looks like he's a very
interesting guy. I have seen a couple of
his clips. I think it was either you
Pratit or some some other people who had
on multiple occasions in the past live
streams recommended professor professor
Jang's uh YouTube channel and his uh
lectures right so I saw a few of his of
his clips I've not seen any of the long
ones interesting guy definitely knows
what he's talking about he has a clear
understanding of history of the
structure of of the way the world is is
ruled
yeah but he also is an interesting guy
in other ways. So,
okay.
Saki Prattab Sina says, "Do you think
this war will extend or be shortlived?"
I don't see it lasting very long unless
Russia gets involved.
Unless Russia gets involved and Russia
getting involved is in my opinion very
unlikely.
So, if Russia doesn't get involved, then
how long can Iran keep fighting? They
don't have unlimited resources. They
don't have unlimited missiles.
Okay.
So, the Americans have essentially
unlimited supplies, like way more
resources than than the Iranians.
Of course, the Americans are fighting
far from their home, but they have a lot
of, you could say, allies in the region
who will support them. So, I think this
war will not last very long. Maybe a
week, maybe two. I don't see it lasting
six months.
Okay, I don't think it'll last that long
and the Americans have a very clear
agenda, right? Regiment change and so
does Israel.
So it is not in their benefit for the it
is not good for them if the war lasts to
the lasts too long. The longer the war
lasts, the weaker the Americans and
Israel will look and the stronger the
Iranians will look that they're
resisting. Look at them. They have been
resisting so long. So, it is in
America's interest to make this war end
as soon as possible. But obviously, it's
a it's not it's easier said than done.
Iran is a major power, a large nation,
much larger than Iraq. So, it may go on
for a while. Maybe few weeks, maybe a
month or two, but if it goes on for 6
months or so, it will not be good. It
will be bad for the US. So, I don't
expect it to last 6 months, maybe a few
weeks.
Hanisha says, "What kind of vasalhood
will India be assigned to? Will we be
like South Korea or Japan or since we
have our own nuclear weapons and means
to deliver them, will we be more like
the French coexist
sovereign?" So if hypothetically India
becomes a vasal nation,
India will be turned into a big market
for dumping American goods. That's one
thing. Second, India will not be allowed
to become a major manufacturing power.
India will be able to will be allowed to
be a major exporter of IT services and
other services. But no manufacturing
manufacturing whatever we're doing
whatever level we're doing that much we
can keep doing but we should import all
the nice stuff from the other countries.
So why do you need to manufacture things
import'll give you the best goods.
So we'll if we become vasal basal nation
we'll keep importing military uh
hardware.
We'll keep we'll become a big market of
consumers
and uh we'll never become a major
economy.
We will have nuclear weapons. Those will
be ceremonial nuclear weapons not to be
used for anything. And we will pre
pretend to be a very sovereign nation.
Our leaders will give speeches of
sovereignty
and most people will believe those
speeches and so on. That's the kind of
thing. So real vasalhood is where the
vasalhood is hidden. Yeah.
The best sort of vasalhood is where
people don't even realize that you
vasals.
Okay. Bat mulki says will India lose
Chabahar soon because of this war? India
has lost Jabahar. It's gone.
India lost it a few weeks ago. We gave
up our stake in Jabahar. We liquidated
our stake in Jabahar, which means that
we paid Iran a certain amount of money
and walked out of Jabahar. It's over. We
are no longer operating Jabahar or
whatever whatever terminals we were
operating. It's over. Before the war,
the Americans told us, "Get out of
Shabbah." And we agreed. We we said,
"Okay, sir. We'll we'll we'll leave.
Innocent USA says ah Clint Eastwood the
man with no name Modi yogi can stand
against innocent USA unless once in a
thousand year never before miracle man
appears
yeah
possibly you are right
possibly you are right yes
Singh says it's just hide your strength
bide your time by Modi I hope so sir. I
hope so. I hope so. One should always
have hope. I hope so.
The posture says the posture causes what
if China solves the border issue with
India in the coming weeks? Will India
decline to be a US vasal? In what
scenario India will not become a vasal
practically? That's a great question
and that we can not be a vasal even if
China I mean this is actually
independent of China but let's say China
next week says okay let's resolve the
border issue quickly that let's
demarcate the border and end our and
normalize our relationship
will that now make a big difference for
us probably too late probably too
Um because Vasalhood has other factors
too. If China if China normalizes its
relationship with India, will that give
India access to energy that America
doesn't control?
Yeah. See today we are in a situation
where all the energy we are buying oil
gas whatever it
most of it comes from other countries
and those countries are controlled by
the US most of them we are no longer
buying Iranian oil Iran will still be
controlled by the US so then all of our
sources of oil energy will be controlled
by the US even if China says okay let's
normalize our situation our relationship
that won't prevent us from being under
American pressure and leverage
constantly like
That's just one thing. Other thing is
that if even if China resolves the
border issue with India, India is still
deeply penetrated, compromised and so on
technologically, militarily and so on.
So that will not,
you know, save India from becoming an
American vasal.
It won't.
Um
is it possible
China resolves the border issue with
India
and India and Russia and China decide to
come together form RAIC and work
together. So India gets Russian oil and
then we stand up against the US. Is is
it possible?
It's theoretically possible. But Russian
oil comes to India through the Atlantic,
then the Mediterranean,
then the Red Sea and all these choke
points the Americans can stop the
Russian oil from coming to India and
China.
So again we are under there is a lot of
leverage the US has over us. So
theoretically it's kind of possible you
know 5% likelihood
but practically the US is just too
strong
and it's too late for India now.
Whatever measures India should have
taken
for us to remain sovereign long term
should have happened in the last 15
years and we have done none of those
things. So
Wun Vishal says, "Do you get existential
dread looking at the future?" No,
no, we'll be fine. I don't get
existential dread. I don't.
Ashtoh Katyal says, "With the US busy
with Iran and Pakistan, busy with
Afghanistan, what are the chances of
operation sindu soon?"
Chances are 0.5%.
Means there are no chances unless the
Americans tell India okay you have been
a good boy so now go and take Kashmir if
the Americans give us the approval then
it could happen otherwise there's 0%
chance of operation Hindu happening zero
zero nothing whatsoever
okay Pratep Kumar Royce says an Indian
guy was explaining in Ranir's podcast
how developed China is when compared to
EU or US let know let alone India how
are we so far behind
because we have not bothered to do
something to get ahead. Right? Why is
China so developed? Because they
invested tremendous amounts of time,
energy, and resources into improving
their standards. From the 1980s onwards,
just in one sector, the education
system, the Chinese government invested
trillions of dollars.
Do you understand how important
education is? The Chinese invested
trillions of dollars only in the
education system in reforming it.
Then they went all in on manufacturing
and they built up the biggest
manufacturing base in the world.
That took decades and so much hard work.
So they put in so much effort, energy,
money, time, all of that. in doing this.
What have we done?
What what has India done?
And all of this took deep reforms in
China.
China has become unrecognizable. That's
how thoroughly they have reformed every
single institution, every single sector.
It takes reforms to change.
What has India reformed? Tell me what
that's why we are so far be behind. The
Chinese have gone ahead in so many
sectors compared to the EU or the US.
The ch Chinese standards of living are
in some some parts of China better than
in the EU. Right?
But in 1990, India and China were
exactly the same level. So China made a
choice.
India never made that choice. India is
still making not making the choice.
Ready always ready says what are the
signs that India is on the path path to
wasalhood what percentage currently see
wasalhood
one of the symptoms of wasalhood is that
somebody tells you what what to do and
what not to do so let's say we are
buying oil from Venezuela uss don't buy
so we say okay okay we'll not buy let's
say we are buying oil from Iran uses
don't buy so we say okay we'll not buy
let's say we have a port we are
operating a port in Iran chabahar the US
says get out of the port we go out. So
when our policy decisions are being
dictated by a foreign power, it means we
are the vasal not 100% guaranteed but
yeah we can't make our decisions on on
our own. We have to first take approval
and when they are displeased we have to
move out of it. We have to stop doing
whatever we doing. That's one example
that could indicate potential vasalhood.
Right? That's just one example. Second,
when you're you are technologically
dependent on another country, you're
thoroughly penetrated by foreign social
media networks,
by by foreign um platforms, by foreign
services, when you use foreign search
engines, even if you use foreign AI,
when you use everything that's foreign
which belongs to one country, you are a
technological vasal. India is not a
techn technologically sovereign nation.
By the way, technological sovereignty
India's ranking India's India's score
from 0 to one
where zero is technological vasal and
and one is technologically sovereign.
India is like 0.1
technologically India is a vasal already
clearly.
So when you are technologically
compromised that's the issue. Then when
you are when your military depends on
foreign purchases that's a that's again
a red flag there there are so many red
flags like this when you are when you
are
um dependent on other countries for for
energy that compromises you. It is not a
you know necessarily vasal but it's it's
a risk fac major risk factor
when you
when your elites their their families
live abroad and have foreign
citizenships that's a risk that's a
major major red flag so that when all
these red flags come together
it tells you a story
Donald Putin
Donald Putin says what's the point of
ever even growing when soon that special
majority minority I don't discuss these
matters sir
sorry this is not the channel for this
these discussions.
Pratib Kumar writes about recent
Pakistan Afghanistan war.
Yeah, it's going on. See the Pakistanis
have been in this habit of launching air
strikes at Afghanistan targeting
civilians. It's the second time it
happened right a couple of a few days
ago. So naturally the Afghanistan
government will will respond to that.
They will retaliate when their civilians
are being killed. So that has led to the
current situation where Pakistan and
Afghanistan are at war. The Afghans are
dropping I mean they've taken out a
couple of Pakistan at least a couple of
Pakistani fighter planes. They are
targeting Pakistani military
installations with drones. The
Pakistanis are conducting more air
strikes. The Afghans have taken over
some Pakistani border posts and whatnot.
So yeah, that's the situation right now.
But overall the Pakistanis are way too
strong for Afghanistan.
Uh
so let's see how it goes. But it's it's
another destabilizing factor in our
neighborhood. We obviously stand with
Afghanistan.
We stand with Afghanistan. The
Pakistanis are a bunch of terrorists.
Yeah. So that's where it stands. The war
means says January 26, Venezuela.
February 26
next Iran. What next? Um
Cuba Cuba is they say it's like a
lowhanging fruit for the US. Yeah. So
yeah, the Venezuela is done. Iran is now
in process. Maybe it'll take a few weeks
for the Americans to to win the war
against Iran. What next? Could be Cuba.
After that, what is left? Russia and
China only, right?
I suppose Yemen. I suppose Yemen. They
could perhaps take out Yemen possibly.
But uh yeah,
so all the big major adversaries they're
taking out one by one. Maybe Cuba.
Maybe then they will go for Canada and
and and Greenland perhaps.
Okay. RJ Damiwal, thank you very much
sir. Thank you so much indeed. Reckless
says since Indian government doesn't
really care about its people or where
the country is heading and they had the
option to make things better and they
did not. What problem do we have in
becoming based from a normal citizens
perspective?
Short-term, medium-term, nothing bad.
Long-term, you may your descendants may
not practice the same religion and
culture as you.
That's that's a long-term problem,
potential problem.
Um,
uh, yeah. So, when you are a vasal of an
Abrahamic nation, you lose your culture,
you lose your identity.
uh all that is replaced by something
else long-term show slowly it happens.
So if India hypothetically becomes a
vasal you may see an increase in the
intensity and speed of the industrial
scale conversions to foreign religions
that are already happening right now in
the past 10 years. You may see more of
that. You may see more parts of India's
far east coming under foreign
occupation.
Manipur is at least 50% under foreign
occupation right now.
The government of India has no control
in places like Churachanpur. So you may
see more of that happening in India. So
slowly slowly you will lose whatever you
have. Eventually the nation may get
fragmented possibly.
But short-term things will be fine.
Possibly even medium-term things will be
fine. Yeah.
Aniket says
she's daughter lives in Australia by the
way. Very interesting. Let's let's I've
also heard about that. Let me fact check
that. Let's find out.
Where does Xi Jinping's daughter live?
Straa, US. She was in the US in the
past. Okay. She's in the US,
specifically Massachusetts, where she
previously attended.
That's really interesting actually.
That's really interesting.
I wonder what sort of arrangement this
is an indication of. You are right to
point this out. You're right to point it
out. Is Xinping himself compromised?
Is he himself compromised?
Yeah.
Coffee.
I wonder. I wonder.
Yeah.
Kabira says, "How would you characterize
Singapore's strategic strategic
positioning between major powers and
what might this mean for its future
sovereignty and autonomy?"
Um, it's called multi-dependency.
right? U you are dependent on other
nations entirely but you balance that
out in such a way that you kind of have
autonomy.
Um that's called multi-dependency.
So that's that's Singapore is a
reasonably autonomous nation. They've
done a admirable job at whatever they've
been doing in the past few decades. the
way they've risen from poverty and
whatnot and they are just too small to
be genuinely sovereign
but they really matter economically
and uh yeah so it's a it's a state of
multi-dependency balanced
multi-dependency
uh future sovereignty and autonomy well
if they continue
their policy successfully then long-term
also they'll be autonomous
and mostly sovereign
ringu. Thank you very much.
Thank you.
Ankuras says what will happen to us a
thousand years of slavery and misery?
Maybe not a thousand years, maybe 100,
200 and no maybe not misery,
maybe not.
So if we become a vasal hypothetically
then it's likely that you know in 50
years 100 years there will be no Indian
culture left and we'll our descendants
will be practicing a foreign religion
and culture and maybe they'll be happy
maybe they'll be happy with it maybe
Hinduism etc will be relegated to
museums and they'll go and see oh our
our backward barbarous ancestors used to
practice this primitive religion but now
we are free so maybe they'll be happy in
the future if we become aasal
Yeah. And maybe it won't last a thousand
years. No empire lasts 1,000 years. I
mean, no major empire has lasted 1,000
years, right?
At least in in in a way that's powerful.
Typically, empires last two 200 250
years.
So,
uh, Saki Prattabina says, "What are
India's options to evade or prevent?"
Nothing much today. Whatever we should
have done should have happened in the
past 15 years, 20 years. If we had got
that right, then today we would not be
in a situation where we have to pick a
pick pick a side. We would have been way
more
in a much better position than today.
Right? If we had become a major
manufacturing power, if we had become a
major technological power, that would
not have happened without major reforms.
So, we would have done those reforms.
And if you were genuinely a major
technological and
manufacturing and and industrial power,
that means some strong military power as
well, not dependent on others, then we
would not be in a position where we may
have to potentially hypothetically
accept mass
today. If you want to access it will
take 10 20 years to do that long process
right if we start today we are we
haven't even started today so yeah today
there is no India has no options
essentially
whatever work should have been done
should have been done in the past 15 20
years
today the what nothing
ranging says I think they will use India
as a meat grinder in a fight against
China as Japan population is declining.
So India will serve this purpose. Why
Modi allow so sad?
I don't see the Chinese going to war
against the US.
I don't see that happening unless
the Chinese are in a desperate
situation.
But if they go to war against the US,
the Chinese know they will lose it.
China is guaranteed to lose a war
against the US.
The Chinese don't want to fight a war.
Now, can the US use India? If India
becomes a vasal, the the Americans can
potentially engineer a war against China
with India. That's possible.
Uh will the US want to use India like
that? Well, it depends on multiple
factors. So, one possibility if India
becomes a vasal is that India does get
used as a meat grinder in a war against
China. That's that's a possibility. if
we become a vasal.
Um, yeah. So, the moral of the story is
never become a vasal. Don't allow anyone
to use you in whatever way. That's the
moral of the story. See, when we were we
were a British vasal, we were under
British occupation, we were used as a
meat grinder in World War I and World
War II, weren't we?
So, once again, if you are vasal in the
future, we'll be used in in whatever way
they they feel is best.
Yeah, Nishant Tari says, "If the US
captures Iran, which leads to energy and
oil problems in China, will it benefit
EU or Germany economically?"
So, let's say the US captures Iran.
This will lead to energy and oil
problems in China. Yes.
Will this benefit EU and Germany? Nah.
No. See the US will not really create a
shortage of oil or whatever in China. It
will simply dangle that on China's head
like a sword willing to fall, waiting to
fall. So when the Chinese will come
under this kind of dependency, their
behavior will change and they will their
behavior will be then you could say
dictated by the US to a greater extent.
So their behavior will have to be such
that it benefits the US.
Okay.
And the US will will determine the
parameters of China's behavior.
Um
so how does that benefit the EU or
Germany? Not sure how it does.
uh if the war in Ukraine ends and
there's a resumption of Russian uh
energy into into Western Europe that
could benefit the EU and Germany. If the
US captures Iran, maybe there's a deal
that that also ends the Ukraine war.
Then it could indirectly benefit
Western Europe, Germany and so on. So
everything you see is interconnected.
The Iran war that's happening right now
is connected to China. It is also
connected to the Ukraine war and all of
these things are also connected to the
economy in Western Europe.
It's all interconnected in multiple
ways. So, um I would say the Ukraine war
is more closely relevant to u the
economic situation in in Europe compared
to the Iran thing.
Shiraghawasti says, "What would happen
if Iran strikes aircraft carrier of the
US? What would it trigger? As that is
just about probability.
If the Iranians strike an American
aircraft carrier, there will be
the Americans will extract tremendous
amount of vengeance from Iran. They will
punish Iran for that. Iran could
potentially do that. Yes. If the Iranian
government is going down, they will
strike at everything
and then they will be punished
militarily by the US.
The US has all kinds of weapons at their
disposal.
Yeah. So if they if they strike an
aircraft carrier, maybe they disable or
destroy an aircraft carrier, that will
invite a tremendous amount of military
punishment on Iran. Yeah. What would it
trigger as that is just what will it
trigger? A huge military response from
the US like allout military response.
Devastating military response by the US.
the US may potentially use various kinds
of missiles that they typically would
not use otherwise. So yeah,
Harban Jud Singh says all this
geopolitics talks is just big boss if we
can't do something. No authority or
government is listening. So what to do
as citizens? As of now it's blood
boiling and we can't do anything. Just
shout at it.
What can we do as citizens? Nothing.
That is just the truth. Yeah. So, you're
right. It's like Big Boss. I I mean, I
I've never watched a single episode of
Big Boss, so I don't know how it goes,
but it's like watching um
some people fighting and and shouting
about it or whatever. And there's
nothing we can do. As citizens, you can
do something about the fate of your
country only if you rise to a position
of power at some level. Then you can
affect the the fate of the country in
some way. The higher in power you rise,
the more of an effect you can have on
the direction the country goes in. If
you are simply a voter,
you have you have going to have no
effect on what the happens to the
country,
right? There's nothing you can do about
it. Nothing. As a citizen, all you are
allowed to do is vote. And voting
typically often makes no difference. you
vote for them or they you know often
it's like that. So as a citizen the only
thing you can do is vote once in 5 years
or once in your local elections whatever
those things are but what difference
does it make is the question
right so yeah that's one way of looking
at it it's like you're watching big boss
or watching IPL or whatever
uh Goautam Gotham thank you very much
Gotham Goautam Wad Turi Goautam VM Tuli
thank you very much sir thank
Paris Rattor says, "How is cowing down
to the US as we are doing right now the
different from the doctrine of hide your
strength and b your time?" Good
question. Good question. Good question.
So
cowing down the U to the US like they're
doing right now,
how is it different from hire your
friend by? Great question. So Ding
Xiaoing had this policy for China. Don't
show what you're doing. You may be
becoming more powerful slowly but don't
show it. Don't advertise it.
Wait for the right time. Hide your
strength. Pretend to be meek.
So isn't that what India is doing? No.
Because while China was doing hide your
strength and bio time
they were ensuring that China doesn't
get penetrated by the Americans
they were keeping the Americans out from
specific sectors. They were building the
great firewall of China.
No American
social media platform will be allowed in
China. No American search engine will be
allowed in China. No American whatever
will be allowed in China. The Chinese
were walling off their internet.
They were ensuring there is no
penetration of China while they were
hiding their strength and biding their
time and whatever penetration existed
they were getting rid of it in sometimes
very brutal ways which you will not hear
about
that's what the Chinese were doing
now is India doing that or is India
allowing itself to get progressively
more and more penetrated by the US
that's the difference you see that is
the
Vir Kamat says why did Prime Minister
Modi visit Israel for the past week so
close to the resumption of these
strikes? Is it to agree to terms of
vasalization or something else? Well, it
was to take the relationship between
India and Israel forward
to new heights.
Well, let's let's ask Google what are
the outcomes. Okay. What are the
concrete
outcomes of Prime Minister Modi's
uh Israel Israel visit?
Let's see what are the deals and things.
Uh we have elevated our relationship to
a special strategic partnership for
peace, innovation and prosperity. Peace,
innovation, prosperity. 27 concrete
outcomes, 17 signed agreements, 10 major
strategic announcements, uh technology
critical and emerging technologies,
launch of a new initiative, AI,
semiconductors, quantum computing, cyber
security, center of center of
excellence, letter of intent was signed,
outstanding defense cooperation, joint
development and production of military
equipment under MIL in India, AI and
research, $1.5 million. My goodness,
such a gigantic sum of money.
Yeah. Okay. FTA negotiations will
continue. UPI integration of some kind.
Financial dialogue. Labor mobility.
Okay. India will export more cheap
labor. Very nice. Academic and cultural
exchange because India has a lot of lot
to offer academically to Israel. Um
innovation center for agriculture.
Fantastic water. Okay. All this stuff.
So this is why Prime Minister Modi
visited Israel, visited Israel to take
the partnership between India and Israel
to to greater heights to strengthen the
relationship between the two countries.
That's why Prime Minister Modi visited
Israel. He did not visit Israel to kiss
any ring. That's why he visited Israel.
Sunju says, "Would it have been
different if Kamala had won?"
um it makes no difference who actually
wins.
Okay?
Even if Kamala had let's say won, this
would have happened anyway because it
was time.
Whoever actually runs the US has decided
this is the time. So if Kamala had won,
she would have been giving that speech
and whatever it would have been no
different.
IPK1S says the great aim once said
Pakistan got army India got Babuam
Babuam which is not incorrect at all.
Yeah. See most nations have an army but
in Pakistan the army has a nation right
the army owns the nation in Pakistan.
Well for India it's the bureaucracy. In
most countries the country has a
bureaucracy.
In India, the bureaucracy owns India.
The bureaucracy owns and operates India
and even the politicians can't do a
thing about this. So what the Pakistani
army is for Pakistan
the exact same thing the bureaucracy is
for India. And I'm sure there are plenty
of very good bureaucrats who are genuine
patriots and all but that doesn't make
any difference. There are many very very
patriotic and honest bureaucrats
but that doesn't matter. There are lots
of highquality professors and teachers
too in the Indian education system but
the education system is rotten to the
core isn't it? So yeah there we are.
There we have it.
Kajor Bathon says we have been
technologically and energetic energy
dependent since independence. What is it
this moment that makes you feel it is
too late and Vasalhood awaits? Is it
just US belligerence? I believe time is
in our side.
Yeah, we have been technologically
independent dependent since. So let's
deal with tech tech and energy
separately one by one. I mean one by
one. Technologically we have been
dependent since independence,
right?
We depended on multiple sources for
technology
in the cold war. So in the cold war
during the cold war you had two sides
the USSR and the US and for some
technology we depended on the US
depended on the US and for some
technology a lot more we depended on the
USSR. So we always had options.
Yeah. when it comes to energy
even in the 20th century during the cold
war I don't know how much oil we bought
from USSR or whatever but we had options
today and and at that time we were not
forced by an overwhelmingly more
powerful nation to make a choice it's us
or them
right
I mean in
In the 20th century,
we had Bangladesh happen.
We we liberated Bangladesh despite US
opposition, despite the US being on
Bangladesh's side
because we had the USSR on our side. We
had the balancing power. We had the
balance in the world at the time. We
were a weak nation compared to Pakistan.
We were strong. But the US did not want
us to break Pakistan. But the USSR came
and stood stood with us. not just full
support verbal nonsense but actually
they came and stood with us militarily.
So that's why the world was balanced at
the time for us and we were not vasals
of anybody if you if you were to ask me
genuinely we were more on the USSR side
and quasi vasalized but not fully
vasalized by the USSR. We're more
dependent on them.
Uh so and energy also that's the same
situation. So today we are in this
situation where there is no balancing
force to the US. The US is is the only
superpower in the world. There's no one
who can offset American power. So
there's no way we can balance out that
we will do some things with you and some
things with this other guy. There's no
such thing. The only major economic
power is China who is also an enemy of
India.
So we have no options left today. You
see one option we could have done was to
make ourselves powerful in the past 15
20 years by reforming India thoroughly
but we chose not to do that not even
begin the process.
You understand?
So awaits when you when you run out of
options
awaits when you run out of options.
India is kind of running out of options
now.
Mclivin says, "Seems like Kim Jong-un is
the best leader in the world right now."
Okay.
Yeah. Kim Jong-un is is very clear,
right? He will vasalize his country to
China in certain ways while remaining
retaining full control of his country in
other ways. And that that keeps the US
away, right? The US can't do a thing
about North Korea.
So yeah, he's he's a very practical
pragmatic leader and that's a family
trait for him. His father and
grandfather also played the same game,
right? So
hyphen says, "Just came back from Rome.
People friendly compared to the UK. I
did not miss a single ask blockbuster
episode as always. Thank you very much."
Thank you very much, sir. Thank you.
Thank you. You did not miss a single
episode from Rome. Fantastic. Thank you.
Thank you so much, sir.
I really really appreciate that. Means a
lot all of you actually. Uh so you came
back from Rome. People are really
friendly compared to the UK. I agree.
The Romans and the Anglo-Saxons are very
different people. Very different. Very
different people in Italy in Rome are
like they're closer to us culture. I
mean not really culturally. I mean, but
overall the attitude and approach of the
Italian people, it's it's very different
from that of the UK. The Italians are
more expressive, more exuberant,
warmer. They speak more with their hands
for
so people are very friendly compared to
the UK.
Yeah. Very totally different culture.
Totally different cultural.
um Italy is and in Italy also you've got
different regions and people are
different in different regions. You go
to you go to the far north of Italy
people are different compared to the
people in the Rome region compared to
the people in Tuskan compared to the
people in Sardinia
um and so on. Yeah.
Yeah. Very nice place actually Italy
very nice.
Uh Shashidar says why did India have to
make a choice? Why not stay neutral?
Let's say some some very powerful guy
comes and puts a gun to your head and
says you can't stay neutral. You may
have to make a choice. What will you do?
You'll make a choice.
You don't have the choice anymore to
stay neutral. You are given the option.
You are either with us or against us.
You're going to make a choice now. How
will you stay neutral then? Tell me with
a gun to your head.
Kabira says, "Dubai's growing appeal as
a low tax global hub has attracted many
Americans. How might the US respond to
this trend over the long term? The US is
fine with it.
The US is fine fine with that. Yeah, it
doesn't really affect the US too much.
It does not. The US will will not really
do anything about this unless it starts
making a a genuine difference to the US
and it won't, right? It won't it only
attracts
certain kinds of Americans
the ones who the kind of Americans who
are like you know
people with a net worth of $5 10 million
which actually is poor people if you are
being very realistic
if you are if your net worth is 5 $10
million you are a poor person honestly
and what about the rest of us
anyhow that's the kind of people it
attracts Okay. It doesn't attract the
billionaires.
Billionaires may visit Dubai.
So it doesn't really affect the US too
much. So that's fine. The US is happy
with this. I am Dante says, "Namaste. We
have never been sovereign. We did not
gain our freedom through force in 1947.
We lost it."
The last time India was genuinely
sovereign was
for a for a while in the 18th century
when you had the Marata Empire
reconquering most of India from the
Turks. That was a time when India was
to a large extent sovereign. Then before
that India was sovereign maybe around
10,000 B 1000 AD
around 10,000 AD India was fully
sovereign.
That's around the time when the decline
begins
with
firstly Gandhar falling to the Turks
right
now in 1947.
Why did I say earlier in this episode
that Subashindra Bose failed?
Do I mean to disrespect the great man?
I have more respect for Subashindra Bose
than any other so-called freedom
fighter. He was the last great man we
had Subashindra Bose. But very
tragically, very sadly, he failed. Why
do I say he failed? Because he sought to
gain independence through force by
militarily defeating the British. That's
when India would have been sovereign.
What happened in 47 was a transfer of
power from one set of crooks to another
set of crooks. If the same system
continued, it continues till today. So
you are right. Actually from that
perspective, we have never been
sovereign. You're right from the
perspective we have never been so we are
still colonized and we're getting
progressively more colonized.
So my viewers my dear viewers consider
this very seriously what Ayam Nante is
saying actually
says that's what I was saying if Modi
knew about Ukraine war doesn't make us
Russian wasal then how knowing Israel
attack on Iran makes us vasal it does
not
it doesn't make us was if we know about
something
knowing or not knowing about things
doesn't make you a vasal
when did I say that knowing about the
Israel attack on Iran makes makes us a
vasal. That doesn't make us a vasal.
It doesn't
other things makes us make us vasals.
And I've explained that like multiple
times in this episode. What makes you a
vasal and what makes you sovereign?
So knowing that something is going to
happen is a privilege. It doesn't make
you a vasal. But you also have to ask
yourself that if I have this privilege,
why do I have it?
Uh Barat says best books on geopolitics
and history please come on man there are
no books on geopolitics the best books
on geopolitics are books on history best
books on history I don't know
there are you can't read learn history
from like three books or five books
you have to be okay best book on history
I'll tell you okay my personal favorite
which started me on my my on my journey
in history. I'll tell you that. Okay. Uh
will Durant the the
story of civilization?
This is a set of 11 books.
Okay. I read these books as a kid and
some of these I read as a as a kid, some
I read later. But this is the best
series of books about history and it's a
you could say it's obsolete or whatever,
but it's it's great. Read those.
Read those geopolitics. There there's no
books on geopolitics.
Do have you ever seen a textbook on
geopolitics anywhere? There are no books
on geopolitics. The best books on
geopolitics are books about history.
Okay.
Hyphen says, "Don't have any question,
but all we all need your live streams to
last forever. I know it's not human
possible, but all well, I'll keep it
going as as as long as I can." Okay.
See, you know, I
the one thing I've
the one thing that's been constant on my
channel, I've tried lots of things here
and there. One thing that's been
constant is these Askabad live streams,
right?
Why have I kept this going? This is
episode 334. It's been like four years
now or something.
I I personally have subscribed to many
YouTube channels. And one thing that
that I've seen is that YouTube channels
over time change. The things I used to
really enjoy, they are no longer there
on the channel because people need to
change. People need to evolve. So, so
and so YouTuber I used to follow no
longer does what what really made me
follow that YouTuber. Right? So over
time most channels lose what made them
originally so nice, so great.
But in my case, I promise you all Ask
Abij will go on, right? So at least that
aspect of the channel wants won't
change. We will keep doing these live
streams. So anyway, hyphen G, thank you
so much. Thank you so much.
Swastik says 150 men controlling entire
world are builderberg
group search. Let's search
builderberg
group.
Who's that? Bilderberg group. Annual
private of the record conference
established in 154 to foster dialogue
between Europe and North America.
Ah
Chaitam house rules. Very interesting.
Very interesting. Okay sir. This is very
interesting. I shall look more into it.
Thank you. Reddi always ready says how
can we prevent now? What's the chance?
Chances are low but not zero.
Okay. Chances are low not zero.
If you want to prevent vasalhood, what
you have to do is to reduce the foreign
penetration of a country,
reduce the the amount to which your
country is compromised, the reduce your
dependency on other countries and gain
the maximum options. That's what you do
to prevent that. That is a process that
takes 15 20 years.
If we start today, it will take us 15 20
years to to reach that position.
to be strong enough to prevent
vasalhood. But we are here today.
What's the chance? Low.
Like I said in the past few episodes,
there's a high probability India becomes
the American Wasal in the next 5 years.
So I stand by what I said.
The chances of India preventing
vasalhood are low. Low.
Dirj Kamat says lots of pessimism today.
Not the same pessimism or the same
realism. This is not pessimism. This is
realism. Do you want me to lie to you
all and tell you no everything is fine.
Do you want me to lie to you or do you
want me to be truthful to you? There are
plenty of YouTube channels where you can
go and listen to lies.
So this is not me being pessimistic.
This is me being realistic. You would
have seen that in my episode in 2024
after Trump won. You would have seen
exactly the same thing. I said it
differently at the time. I said that you
will see a situation where India and the
US relationship, India US relationship
will reach the pinnacle of its
relationship and India and and Trump and
Modi will be dancing hand in hand.
What I was alluding to was
so uh evidence I do the evidence. How
many times? How many times the past four
hours I've been speaking about that
actually a percentage the what's the
probability of India becoming American
masal maybe 80%.
Maybe 90%.
Yeah. Evidence
I spoke about it so many times in the
past 4 hours. It's been four and a half
hours now. Wow. Oo.
Okay. Shibam Chhataraj says relying on
services risks autonomy. Freedom
fighters, scientists, thorium gave their
life instead of personal life. People
who support this colonial arvinal.
I agree. I agree. Yeah. So many people
have given their life for India and what
have they got?
Okay.
Darendra Desh Pad says Trump talked with
Iran and mutually disc decided to
misguide the world by carrying out fake
strikes. Oh, what makes you say that?
How are you aware? Did you listen to the
conversation that Trump had with Iran?
How do you know this fake strikes? Have
you seen the damage in Thran? Have you
seen the the Iranians launching retali
retaliatory strikes on other countries?
Have you not seen that? You call these
fake strikes. At least one person has
died in Abu Dhabi. Is that a fake
strike? I don't know. I don't know how
how you've come to this conclusion that
these are fake strikes. And how do you
know Trump mutually decided with Iran to
do this? Come on.
Dave ch thank you very much sir. Thank
you.
Goautam verman dant vermma dantaluri
says how can the US or any other can
destroy our culture as Muslims and
British failed? See
good question. No how does it happen?
Tell me how culturally grounded were
Indians in 1947.
Let's say they were 80% culturally
grounded
in 1947. By 1980 the amount of cultural
drowning in India was less than that. By
2000 the cultural drowning was less than
that. In 2026 most Indians are super
dassinated.
Hindus in name only.
It happens gradually slowly. It doesn't
happen over the next two weeks. It will
happen over the next 50 or 100 years.
Slowly gradually they will teach you
through the education system, through
the media, through everything else to
slowly just distance yourself inch by
inch, millimeter by millimeter from your
culture.
In some cases, you you'll see it happen
on an industrial scale. The industrial
scale conversions that are happening in
various parts of India. you. It's
happening in front of your eyes, but you
don't see it. It's happening every day.
Thousands of your people are getting
converted to foreign religions on an
industrial scale every day, but you
don't see it.
Nobody can destroy our culture.
Everybody failed. No, it's happening
right now. It's happening right now. And
the and the more we move away from our
culture, the more deafenated we get, the
easier it will become for this to become
faster and faster. Okay? So within 50 to
100 years our culture could be gone
completely. It it will be reduced to
museum pieces.
Hyphen says I completely agree with you
sir and the main reason I feel keeps
your live streams fresh is the unique
knowledge you keep giving us for free.
Thank you again. Most welcome sir. Most
welcome. I wish I had
you know cheerful news for you all that
you know but
but I I have to be realistic. I have to
be truthful to you all, right? So, it is
it is what it is. With Iran falling,
there'll be way more leverage the US has
on India and other countries and so on.
So, yeah, it's just facts. It's just
facts.
Okay. Am Dante says, "A king gives
orders to ministers to run the country.
Unfortunately, we don't have one." Yeah,
we don't have a king, right?
We don't have a king today.
When we had kings, things were
different. Yeah, I know sometimes some
kings are bad. But when was the last
time India had a bad king? I'm not
talking about the foreign occupiers like
the muggles and the Turks. I'm talking
about Indian kings. When was the last
time he had a bad king who was Indian,
not foreigner?
I can't think of someone. Yeah,
right. So, you're right. Yeah. Stoic bot
says, "Big fan of your show, sir. Thank
you very much, sir." Thank you indeed.
Why have you stopped doing history AMAs
lately? This was supposed to be a
history AMA, but then the Iran war
happened.
I do history AMAs on typically on
Saturdays.
So, I I'll I'll tell you what. Um,
so give me a second. Give me a second.
I'll show you. Maybe you don't you've
not seen
this channel of late because a lot of
people don't they don't get
notifications anymore. A lot of people
are being are being automatically
unsubscribed or whatever. But the thing
is this. See uh the current episode is
334. If you see 332, it's a combination
of history and geopolitics. If you see
330,
it's history and geopolitics. If you see
328, you will see some geopolitics and
mystery. So it's like 50/50 or maybe
60/40. So I am indeed doing history
episodes or at least 50% history
episodes. Uh but maybe you are not being
notified or something. I don't know. So
yeah, I do this. Today is an emergency
episode. This was supposed to be a
history and geopolitics episode, but the
war happened and that's why I've turned
it into this right now.
Anyway, sir, thank you so much for being
for for being a viewer. Thank you so
much.
Dave CH, thank you very much indeed,
sir. Thank you. Anonymous scientist.
Good to see you. New Illuminati joint
chat chat. Bohemian Grove members are
mind-blowing.
New Illuminati, Bohemian Grove. I've
heard about these things, but um I
haven't dug too deep into these matters.
Right. Anyway, thank you, sir. Mosh,
good to see you always. Black Panther
says, "The US have aircraft carrier in
Iran region.
Why can't Russia China give anti-hship
missile to target carrier? Its potential
loss from US will reduce power
projection.
Do you understand what the US does will
do? If somebody takes out an aircraft
carrier, the US has I don't know 12
aircraft carriers, super carriers or
something. If someone takes out one of
their aircraft carriers, they will
destroy that country.
Russia and China don't need to give Iran
missiles. Iran has very capable
missiles, hypersonic missiles that can
take out aircraft carriers. Iran has
that. They don't need to borrow that
from China or Russia.
But does Iran dare to do this?
Iran may dare to do this if the regime
is going down. Then we'll see what
happens. But if Iran takes out an
American aircraft carrier, they will pay
a big price for that because the US is
just too powerful. Right? Understand
that.
Okay. Anik says if we were vasals we
would already had trade deal with the US
plus why would we have softened our
relations with China in 2018 we stopped
buying Iran oil because of US then we
didn't become vasal at that time
yeah so in around 2010 we stopped buying
oil from Venezuela because of American
pressure right
in 2018 or whenever 20 whenever it was
we stopped buying Iran Iranian oil
because of American pressure so You see
those
individual data points don't point to
was
ask yourself what are the terms of the
trade deal we have with the US
are we importing any agricultural
product products
maybe we are not importing agricult
agriculture products for human
consumption are we importing
agricultural products for animal
consumption
for the consumption of maybe by cows
are any of
agricultural products genetically
modified.
See, you have to look at vasalhood from
a multi-dimensional perspective. One or
two things don't mean vasalhood. It
means pressure, but not vasalhood.
Vasalhood means one nation starts
controlling another nation in a way
that's detrimental to the this nation's
interests.
Right? So, one or two data points don't
make you a vasal. A combination of
multiple factors all coming together
they all form a pattern that shows
something that's hoody
padar says um oh it's a new member thank
you very much sir thank you very much
sir indeed welcome to this channel's
membership thank you Dave CH says so
we're going to be seeing the fall of
Iran unfortunately most likely that's
that's the logical outcome the US is
just too powerful yeah
and see
um
let's go to the map. Okay.
So if the US was fighting Iran alone, it
would be a different story.
But if you see here,
the US is not alone in fighting Iran.
Israel is fighting Iran. Israel launched
the first strikes. Israel is very
powerful. But Israel is far away. What
about the other countries?
Saudi Arabia is on America's side.
Kuwait is on America's side. Iraq is an
American possession. Syria is an
American possession. The UAE is on
America's side. Bahrain and Qatar are on
America's side. Pakistan is a US.
Afghanistan is not strong enough to do
anything about this. Iran is encircled.
The America The Americans have multiple
military bases in the region.
Iran is isolated. It has no friends in
the region. Turkey is a US ally. Okay.
Russia is not very far away, but Russia
is already embroiled in a war in
Ukraine. Can Russia get can Russia risk
getting embroiled in in another war? Now
China is too far away. So you see all
the odds are stacked up against Iran.
It's very unlikely that Iran survives
this. Yeah. Very unlikely.
I'm Dante says, "We fought for a
thousand years. We can fight for another
1,000 years. Dharma will rise. One
should not lose hope. One doesn't lose
hope, but one should also be realistic
that that dharma faces an existential
crisis today. If we uh disregard that,
then we will lose. We can only prevail
if we are being practical and realistic
and actually recognize the threat we are
facing.
I'm not saying lose hope. I'm saying
first of all recognize what we are
facing. Recognize the full magnitude and
nature of the threat. The dharma may
possibly be if if we don't do something
about it may may not last 100 years. We
have to first be aware of it. We have to
recognize it. We can't we can put our
head under the sand like an ostrich.
Only then can we do something about it.
So I'm not being pessimistic. I'm a very
very optimistic person. But I am simply
hopefully making people aware of the the
threats we're facing. That's it. Nothing
else. So yeah, we fought a thousand
years. We can fight a thousand years
more. But if dharma no longer exists,
what are you fighting?
Right?
Mac four says, "Scared for my dharma.
It's falling and no one cares."
No, people do care, but people no longer
are even aware of what dharma is today.
Most people are destinated.
Our education system doesn't teach us
our own culture.
So every new generation people know less
and less about their culture and
eventually people will know nothing
about that culture. That's the problem.
Anyway, let us be optimistic. Let us u
hope everybody realizes what's what's
being done to India by our own our own
people.
godliness says at least the spectacles
and narratives points towards India
being on the US side on this also if
Trump succeeds can we all call out those
so-called geopolitical experts who are
writing of the US I don't know what
other geopolitical experts have been
saying uh Trump
the US is winning this
right they have not put up this entire
massive military hardware in West Asia
to force Iran to the diplomatic
negotiating table. Iran was already at
the negotiating table and Trump has
explicitly say stated that this is a
regime change operation and so has
Netanyahu.
Uh so it'll be it'll be very surprising
if Iran is able to survive this. Yeah.
So I don't know who's been writing of
the US but yeah um
the narratives in spect everything
points towards India being on the US
side of this. Yeah.
Yes, if is if India is with Israel, it
is also with the US.
That's just one one data point. By the
way, YOLO donkey band says implanting
everybody with neural link. Does this
give us world peace?
Well, it can give everybody world it can
give you world peace. But on whose
terms?
on the terms of of whoever owns
Neuralink, right?
So the question is, yeah, peace is
great, but peace on whose terms is the
question?
Whose terms?
I I would not want to be to have a peace
on which everybody is a mentally loized
zombie.
That's not that's not the kind of peace
I would want. Right?
godliness says who will be next for the
US or it ends here perhaps Cuba
perhaps Cuba
and then it's Russia and China that's
left so do they make Russia accept some
kind of deal for Ukraine some kind of
peace deal or and then will they focus
on China so
yeah pro next could probably be Cuba
actually but the the big objective of
the US is to make make the world a
uniolar place and uh
and deal with China and Russia.
Robinson John says you said Trump kissed
the ring. Does that mean that he had
full judiciary backing? Then why did
courts oppose the traffic rules? His
traffic rules. I did not ever mean the
US judiciary when I said kiss the ring.
No, not the US judiciary. The US is not
India.
Trump. This is nothing to do with
judiciary backing.
Kissing the ring means
means aligning yourself with someone who
is more powerful than you.
I mean the unelected establishment of
the US. What the the entity that the
world calls the deep state. That's what
I meant. Not the judiciary. Not the
judiciary. No.
Sid Dav says B2 bomber was actually
designed by an Indian party who is in
jail.
Um so the B2 bomber was actually no he
developed stealth we'll look into that
B2 bomber was actually designed by
Indian Parsy American who was
unfortunately then caught selling that
to Israel, China, Germany etc. Um
Parsei gentleman who became a US citizen
who
let let's see not the entire stealth
bomber but yeah uh Indian par
stealth
uh
fighter
jailed. Okay, let that hopefully that
Yeah. Noir Gualia
he designed he he he played a key role
in designing the propulsion system for
the for the U B2 cell bomber. He did not
design the entire bomber. He designed he
was he played a key role in designing
the the propulsion system and then he
was caught passing on American secrets
technological secrets to other nations
and that's why he is in prison now is in
prison now I suppose he is
yeah yeah yeah industrial espionage so
gotham says I know conversions are going
on at industrial scale but we have much
like shingari and kanchi so I still have
hope But we should be aware. My point is
let's not give up hope. I'm not saying
ever to give up hope.
But we should know what is happening.
Not just know. We should let others make
others also know about this. It's very
important to know what is being done in
India.
We should know what's happening and yeah
then then we can do something about it.
I don't know if we can do something
about it. But I mean the government is
supposed to do something about it. We
have elected them to power, right? Are
they doing something about it? I'm not
sure.
Sid the way says I think Israel has
tough on Trump western leaders through
Epstein fires and Ivanka is also married
to a Zionist Jared Krishna Israel is on
the cards
that's a pretty legitimate strategy in
geopolitics
right
you need if you are if you want to
succeed you should have cards on
everybody
you should have you should have stuff on
everyone and we know Trump is in the
Epstein files is all over the all over
the place.
Uh his daughter is married to I don't
know Jared Kushner is Zionist or no I
don't know but yeah
he's definitely Jewish. I know that. I
don't I don't know about Zionist
but Trump is definitely all over the
Epstein files. Yeah. And so many of
these American politicians are all over
the Epstein files. That guy Lutick
Lutnik Lutnik is in the Epstein files.
Everyone is in the Epstein files
and Yeah. So,
one of the legitimate
tools in geopolitics is blackmail.
Yeah, it is leg. It's a legitim
legitimate tool to have in your toolkit.
If you have dirt on a world leader and
and you can blackmail the person, it's
fantastic for you, isn't it? So, I'm not
saying if Israel has or doesn't have,
but blackmail is a legitimate tool in
geopolitics.
Hyphen says, "Israel, sorry, Iran is
retaliating to US strikes. Does
deterrence still work or are both sides
sliding towards wider war?" See, the US
has a very clear objective, regime
change.
If the US comes closer to changing the
regime in Iran, Iran will lash out with
everything it has got. There is going to
be a much wider war. Iran, I don't see
it just giving up and saying, "Okay, you
take over." They won't do that. They'll
fight till the end. That's that's the
sense I'm getting for Iran. Which means
a much wider war. Much wider much wider
much much bigger war. Iran could strike
at
neighboring countries, oil refineries,
oil wells.
before the Iranian regime goes down.
They may
they may even destroy their own oil
production facilities and burn them.
If they have nuclear weapons, they may
even, God forbid, use those. We are this
situation will go towards a wider war.
That's the sense I'm getting
because the US and Israel are very
clear. They want a regime change and
regime change is an existential threat
for the Iranian government. They Yeah.
So wider war is very likely. Pratep
Kumar Roy says what is this neural link?
No detailed information on the internet.
Was Epstein a rose shield puppet? Rosh I
don't know about that.
But what's neural link? Neuralink is
this um technology developed by a
company called Neuralink
which is owned by mostly by Elon Musk.
And the neural link technology is this
chip that is implanted inside your head.
It's got these um
it has got these probes or electrodes
that that are implanted inside brain
tissue
and it is used it can be used for
multiple purposes. It can be used to
give a person who's paralyzed control of
their arms and legs and limbs back. Uh
it can allow a paralyzed person person
to communicate with the internet without
moving
without without physical contact. Um you
can control a mouse cursor just through
your brain.
Um
in the future you could potentially
access the internet directly in your
mind and so many future possibilities.
It can also be used for controlling
people. I suppose you know technology
has good and bad bad uses. So that's
what Neuralink is.
It was first tested on pigs. Now it has
been implanted in various people and it
has apparently had very positive
improvements in their life. So that sort
of thing. So that's what neural link is.
The the core concept is that look when
we try to communicate with the internet
we have to use our fingers for typing
and all right and that's a very slow
speed of communicating with the internet
or with a computer. Today we can
communicate with with uh our devices
through voice also but eventually but
but this speed at which data flows is
still very limited right so through
dural link you can just simply download
entire movies into your mind I suppose
right that sort of thing so that's the
overall deal with mural link
anish says big fan of yours appreciative
work thank you so much sir thank you so
much Anishi thank you and Anish is a new
member thank you very much once and
thank you and welcome to the channel's
membership. Thank you sir. Sid the way
says what do you think about conversions
in Punjab Kalan movement sick separatism
really hurt culturally? Many think of
Hindus as enemies. It's terrible. It's
terrible.
It's terrible. This is all detrimental
to India's interests. This has been
going on since the 1980s and it still
exists. this new thing has come up of in
the past 10 years or so. This industrial
scale daily conversion activity that's
happening in Punjab.
Yeah.
And the objective is to
you know re-engineer India's cultural
and re and religious demographics.
That is an existential threat to to the
nation but nothing is being done to
address it. Are we already a vasal
state? It's terrible. That's what I
think about conversion in Punjab or
everywhere else. Look, I have nothing
against any specific religion. If you
tomorrow morning want to convert to some
religion through your own choice, you
have 100% the right to do that. It's
your personal choice what religion you
want to practice. I have nothing against
that. My issue is with
my I have an issue with using religion
as a tool to re-engineer demographics of
a country.
If you if someone wants to conver
convert voluntarily
well well and good what's wrong with
that but if someone is coming to India
with billions of dollar with the
objective of transforming and
re-engineering the demographics that's
an issue that's a war against the nation
and why has the government of India
failed to do a thing about this
so it's it's disaster actually what's
happening it's happening right now
happening right now and the government
is doing nothing about this I maybe
India maybe I'm wrong. Maybe India has
been a vasal for the past 20 years. Who
knows? Who knows?
Bharat Kulkarnney says, "Why doesn't
India buy oil from Oman? Why Russia when
it's far? Why and Saudi? Why the
vulnerable hormones? Oman may be cheaper
as it's closer.
Oman does India not buy any oil at all
from Oman? Uh why Russia when it's far?
Russia gives you cheaper oil in large
quantities. So if it's it may make
economic sense and also India
did not want Russia to get isolated and
become a Chinese vasal that's why also
India bought Russian oil but mainly
because it's super cheap it was
significantly cheaper that's why
when it comes to hormones it was not
vulnerable it was when has the state of
hormones ever been blockaded until now I
can't think of any time when this
happened
right so hormones looks vulnerable that
way. Even the Babal Mandibra is
vulnerable. Even the Malaka trade is
vulnerable. It has the same geographical
characteristics, right? These are choke
points. But hormones when was it closed?
It has not been closed. Uh so that's why
India buys oil from Saudi Arabia and so
on. Oman, I'm not sure why. Does India
buy nothing from Oman? Let's find out.
Let's find out. Does India uh buy oil or
gas from from Oman?
By by see we import significant amounts
of crude oil and LG from Oman. So
um it's 38% of India's imports from
Oman. Uh crude oil and petroleum gas and
so on. So yeah, India does does buy it
from Oman. Okay.
All right. Sid the way says, "Lots of
Iranians have nostalgia of pre-Islamic
past and blame Islam for their problems.
This is true of the diaspora. Not sure
about the Iranians in Iran." Yeah,
that's what one what I hear. A lot of
the Iranian diaspora is like that. Many
of them are either Christians or
atheists. None of none of them practice
zorastrianism as far as I know. The
Iranian diaspora in Iran in India who
have been here for centuries. I mean
when it comes to India there have been
two waves of of uh migration from Iran.
One was after one was about 1300 years
ago after the Arabs took over Iran. A
large number of Iranians fled to India
because India was the only place they
could that where they would give where
they would get refuge without having to
give up their culture. Uh and then there
was there were there was another wave of
migration to India of Iranians about 230
years ago. the Iranis. So these are
Zoroastrians.
But when it comes to the Iranian
diaspora in the west, they are mostly
atheists or Christians. No Zoroastrians.
And some may still be Muslims. Um and
yeah, many of them blame the the Islamic
government for all the ills of Iran and
so on. And many of them have some kind
of nostalgia for for the pre-Islamic
past.
But I don't see Iran becoming a Zoraspan
nation again.
If the US religion change succeeds, Iran
becomes eventually long-term a Christian
nation, not Zurastrian.
Pratip Kumar Roy says, "After Mr. Modi's
visit to Israel, I have seen many
Israeli YouTubers talking about
historical people-to-people connection.
I don't did not even know about Jews
from 10 years ago. Shillock from Venice,
Merchant of Venice was my only info."
Okay. Um,
right. So, I I have not seen these
YouTube videos or whatever. uh
people-to-people connections between
India and Israel historically very very
insignificant I'm sure uh I mean there's
been a small Jewish presence in India
dating back to the time about 2100 years
before today
um Jews were shipwrecked in India and
the Kochin Jews or whatever it is
and there have been multiple subsequent
migrations of Jews to India including
Sephodic Jews about 500 years ago after
the reconist a of Spain and the
expulsion of Jews and and and Moors from
Spain. So a bunch of them them came to
India and Jews have never faced any
persecution any discrimination India in
India ever. Zero anti-semitism of the
only place in the world where Jews have
um you know been treated as equals.
Um yeah so that's the deal and of late
obviously various people on YouTube will
speak about this because India and
Israel are strengthening the
relationship.
Black Panther says, "We are seeing
democratic nation makes weaker leaders.
Does second half of the century.
Can we expect more communist countries?"
Um, no. Communism is a failed ideology.
Communism is a failed ideology. You
think China is a communist nation? China
is an imperial system. It's communist
only in name. It's actually capitalist.
there a it's more capitalist than than
communist China today right it's a state
controlled economy with with capitalism
with Chinese characteristics and all no
communism today I don't expect communism
any more communist countries if there
will be more communist experiments those
would be disasters so I don't see it
that way no
if you became the prime minister of
India what would you do in 20 years to
fix internal and external issues would
you would that make India a superpower
is abandoning democracy the only path
20 years nothing will make India a
superpower.
India will work hard for at least 50
years to be a superpower. So my advice
is let's stop using the word superpower
and vishuru.
If I become the PM of India, what would
I do in 20 years? First of all, I will
appoint myself dictator.
What will I do in 20 years? I will
reform the education system. That's
number one. Number one, number one
thing. Education system has to be
reformed. Secondly, all the institutions
have to be reformed.
everything.
So look without going into specifics 20
years fullcale deep reforms will be
needed in India. It will cause
short-term pain actually. Do you
understand that?
It will cause short-term pain 20-year
pain probably in India for a lot of
people who are benefiting from the
current system.
Uh is abandoning democracy the only
path?
Well, there's no real democracy in the
world to be very truthful. Do you think
the US is a democracy?
The US is the two party state which is
one step just one step ahead of
of the one party system of China and
North Korea. There's no real democracy
in the world anywhere. Democracy doesn't
empower people at all.
Democracy gives gives
unelected powerful people a facade
to keep doing what they do.
Um abandoning democracy around see
eventually the world reorients itself.
Democracy is a passing phase. It's it's
the objective of democracy is to hide
where the real power lies.
Right? It it it masks where the real
power of innation lies.
Um,
so it's it's the best system
historically has been monarchy. That's
what's worked for for for humanity.
Monarchy.
Anyway, yeah. Ankita G. Good evening,
ma'am. After Iraq, Libya, Syria, and now
Iran, India will be on direct US radar
sooner or later. In that case, whose
side will India Israel stand? Israel
will stand on Israel's side.
Israel doesn't need to take a side.
Israel doesn't need to take a side. Why
does Israel have to take a side? India
will choose the American side, right?
Most likely
India will most likely choose to be in
the American orbit, which means it is on
the Israel's side.
So yeah, we know Iraq is gone, Libya is
gone, Syria is now ruled by an ISIS
terrorist. Now Iran will be taken down.
It doesn't mean the Americans will next
launch an invasion of India. No, why
launch an invasion of India when you can
control the country from outside? Why do
that?
I don't see the Americans launching any
even threatening any military operation
against India. Nothing. It's all going
to very going to be very peaceful.
So, Israel will stand with Israel and
India will stand with Israel in the US
most likely.
The scorpion king says Christianity is
declining
uh with the US being the last western
Christian nation in next 2030 years
Christianity will be associated with
poor African nations which will lead to
its declining to its decline its
association with the west led to its
growth. A long long story of
Christianity Christianity is a political
religion. Christianity
was it it grew artificially
in the west through state support
because various emperors saw the utility
it had in controlling
their people and so on and that's why it
it grew and today you're absolutely
right that Christianity is declining in
the west absolutely right when I was a
little kid when the pope used to visit
some European nation millions of people
would line the streets to see to get a
glimpse of the pope. Today the pope goes
to some country nobody turns up. Not
even one person turns up. Christianity
is is almost done in the west. The US
says the you are right it's the last
major western Christian nation the
United States and you are right in the
next 20 30 years Christianity will be
associated with with third world nations
which is why and see
the people who run Christianity want
Christianity to rem to continue to exist
and to be relevant somewhere that's why
they are targeting nations like India so
in Africa yes there are only two major
religions left in Africa all the
indigenous cultures and religions have
been destroy Right. It's either
Christianity or Islam. And the next big
target of Christianity is India.
Yeah. And it's being given red carpet
treatment in India. Industrial scale
conversions.
So I I I
agree with you. Scorpion King.
Shibam Chhataraj says don't fear for
Dharma. They will balconize India. All
right.
Galliwor says China shared the YJ21 the
the missile blatantly with Iran. While
we are fully against another angle VCCL
in Iran to share YJ21 puts us on our
toes. Long range advanced surf SHM says
a high long range
advanced.
What's LSM? Once again,
L R A S H M.
Okay. Long range anti-ship missile.
Okay. Fine. So, YJ21 is an anti-hship
missile, right? Y21.
It's an hypersonic anti-hship ballistic
missile. Okay. Um, what's ang
SxN
V SSL? What is that?
What
India? What? What is this? I have no
idea what that is.
Okay. So, has the chi has China shared
why Jon went with Iran? Maybe they did.
Okay, fine. Um,
don't underestimate understand the
severely non Nash
game move by China. You don't understand
why China possib Okay, let's assume. So
I don't know if China has shared the Y21
with with Iran. Let's say they have
shared it. Let's say they've given Iran
Y21 missiles.
How is it a severely non- Nash move by
China? You're obviously talking about
games, Nash equilibrium, all that. But
how is it a non logical and
and and bad move by China? By giving
Iran a better chance to defend itself
against American aggression. Why is it
how is it a bad move for China? by
China. It's a good move for China,
right?
And um
long range anti-hship missile. Okay. All
right. I'm not exactly sure what you're
saying, but this makes sense for China
to do, right? China's adversary is the
US. Iran is a Chinese strategic partner.
The Chinese the and China stands to lose
nothing if Iran gets this technology.
Iran will never use it against China. So
it makes sense for a channel to do do
this, right? Ashai has become a new
member. Thank you very much, sir. Thank
you very much. Welcome to the channel's
membership. I really appreciate it.
Okay. Black Panther says, "Does India
become a US vasal deal in table of P?"
I even if India becomes the US Vasal, I
doubt if the Americans will allow India
to take P.
I think it's still unlikely.
HR devices. Please tell me why illegal
Bangladeshi issue is not a big issue in
national politics. Don't they compromise
over national safety?
It is an existential threat for India
but somehow it's not an issue in
national politics. No political party
seems to be seems to regard this as a
big issue in India.
Yeah. I I I don't have an answer for
this. I don't have an answer. Millions
of illegal Bangladeshi infiltrators
staying in India for decades, having
children in India. How is this not an
existential threat for the nation and
civilization of India? How is it not a
threat?
It's it's it's an existential threat for
India for our national security. Why is
it not a big issue? Possibly because the
people of India don't seem to be to
consider it a big issue.
If everybody is is aware see because
Bangladesh is look look like Indians
most Indians don't think right they see
a Bangladeshi and they see that they
hear the different accent most Indians
don't think only with everyone un
everything knowing about this will this
become a political issue if all Indians
become alarmed and they say that if you
don't fix this we will not vote for you
then only it will become a political
issue
quicks quicks says if we don't forget or
for fors we won't convert all right sir
all right
pratip kumar roy says west is developing
neural link India is fighting for
reservations sir how do we connecting
and exploit people like shall you I
don't know anything about that but yes
you see the west is going forward in
developing technologies AI neural link
whatn not and we are on a race to the
bottom who is more backward and who gets
backward class or whatever reservations
that's that's the problem in India
that's the
Mao Sutong says, "What do you think of
my legacy? I think she is doing a good
job and will China ever benefit from
this US Iran war? This US Iran war will
be detrimental for China's interests if
Iran loses and Iran will most likely
lose? Iran is not powerful enough to
withstand the American onslaught for too
long. Right? So, China will not benefit
from this. China will this will be
detrimental to Chinese interests. He is
doing a pretty good job, sure, for his
country. What do I think of your legacy?
What do I think of your legacy? Well,
you set the stage for your policies were
terrible. Your policies were terrible
for China. You did a great job by taking
Tibet from India. India didn't give a
India didn't care.
Um, but yeah, you expanded Chinese
territory. So, that's good. That's been
good for China. And overall, your
policies were terrible afterwards. They
took China backwards. The great leap
forward, the green, all that stuff was
terrible. The the famines you caused and
all. So overall and still you are
regarded as one of the great people in
China as the founding father of Chinese
Communist Party. So your legacy is
mixed. Your legacy is mixed. On the one
hand you without you China would not be
what it is today. On the other hand you
could have done much better. Yeah.
Sid d says Carlson says India will be
Israel's big new greatest ally and
Israel will slowly move away from the US
as too much negative sentiment around
them in the US. It could happen long
term. It could happen longterm that way.
Yeah.
Um
but short to medium-term the US and
Israel will remain very closely
together. Long-term, yeah, it could be
that way if India actually becomes a
nation of some kind of substance. Then
it could be of much utility to a nation
to a great powerful and advanced nation
like Israel possibly.
Pratipik Kumar Roy says, "World's oldest
bank, Medi Family Bank, similar to
Roshial's ruling class." Yeah, I haven't
looked into these things, sir. I I
really haven't looked into these things.
I know what you're talking about. I
You're trying to be You're trying to say
that the Jews are behind all of this,
but I haven't studied this matters,
right? So, I don't know. Sid says, "Why
did Hindu kings never try to liberate
West Punjab?" Sind from Islamic rule
after beating Gaznavids at battle of Bah
in 25 lost opportunity.
Um we resisted we fought. Papar Raal
took back v various parts of India
liberated various parts of India from
from the Turk occupation. We fought but
we were never unified at the time. That
was the only only problem.
And eventually see don't let's stop
blaming our ancestors for these things.
They fought. They tried their best. What
the problem was that we were not unified
at the time. Unification is not that
easy. You need a superman to unify
subcontinent sized entity, right?
Um
so if Priti for example had not lost to
Guri
then he could potentially have unified
India. But we lost. He lost right the
second battle because he let let Gori go
with the first battle of Tarin. So there
have been lost opportunities and all but
the main problem was was that we were
not politically unified under a single
emperor. If there was a case history
would have been different. History would
have been different indeed.
My point is let's not blame our
ancestors. They tried. They did what
they could. They resisted Turkic
attempts to invade and occupy India for
several centuries. Several centuries for
at least 500 600 years. Imagine how much
they suffered and how much they paid
with their own blood. Right? Sid says I
think so-called liberal leftist Hindus
are the worst traitors in world history.
Even after partition they don't seem to
get Yeah. I will not comment about
religion sir. I will not comment about
any religion. I stay out of these
matters.
Mahesh Kanan. Thank you very much, sir.
Thank you indeed.
Alita Kachab says, "We are digitally
colonized, technically dependent,
culturally alienated, education system
rotten to the core. No sign of major
reforms. Is there any hope? Possibility
of rising as a civilization.
There still is hope. There is still the
possibility
of rising. It will take time. It won't
happen next week. It will not happen
next 5 years. It may not even happen in
the next 20 years. But if we start now,
even if we are vasalized, we can still
in 20, 30, 40 years rise up and become
completely sovereign and a great power
again.
But we will need great leadership for
that. We will need the kind of leader
that comes up once in in 500 years or
maybe once in thousand years with 1.4
billion Indians. There's somebody around
who can do that, I'm sure.
So I am still very optimistic. There is
still hope. There is still the
significant possibility of us rising
again. But it will not be a short-term.
It won't happen very soon. It's it may
take several decades for this to happen.
I mean think about it. Chhatraati
Shivaji Maharaj after he died it took 80
years for the Maratas to reconquer most
of India and liberate most of India. 80
years is a long time right? It's too
long for one human being but for us as a
civilization it is not a very long time.
So on those time scales yes there is
hope. Of course there is hope.
But it will take time.
Jalaj Gaba says with US debt rising to
all times high do you think the US that
US can trigger a world war as during a
war US security economic booms?
Um
most much of this debt that the US owns
is owed to itself.
Okay. It's owed to itself.
Much of the debt is owed to American
banks and American fed various you know
governments at various levels and all
that's that's the the structure of the
debt. Some of it is in is owed to other
nations in the forms of treasury bonds
and so on. But the US owes this debt in
US dollars. The US controls the dollar.
The US can make this debt evaporate
through various magic tricks. So the US
doesn't need to trigger a world war to
get rid of its debt.
Okay? And a world war is good for nobody
because it destroys the world. So I
don't think that's on the cards.
The scorpion king says, "Is China still
a Buddhist nation or culturally
Buddhist?" CCP seems to have a soft
corner of a Buddhism. Chinese diaspora
in the West is converting to
Christianity. China is not a Buddhist
nation. It has got about 200 million
practicing Buddhist. The largest
Buddhist population in the world. And
China doesn't have a CCP doesn't have a
soft cord of a Buddhism. It wants to
appropriate Buddhism.
Okay? It wants to appropriate it. steal
it from India. China says that Buddhism
is a is a Chinese religion because it's
been in China for 2,000 years. So now
it's a Chinese religion. It's trying to
steal Buddhism from India. And China
showcases its cultural,
you know, heritage much better than
India.
So China is not a Buddhist nation. Most
young Chinese don't know the first thing
about Buddhism. They say, "Oh, my
grandmother practices that that worships
this God that you have here." Yeah. And
so China is not a Buddhist nation. It's
not culturally Buddhist, it's culturally
atheist
and the CCP simply wants to appropriate
Buddhism. You give them the chance, they
will even appropriate yoga and
everything else.
Mahesh Kanan says by attacking Gulf
states and closing the state of foremost
Iran
pulling leverage quickly. It looks like
they want to stop the war at any cost.
What's your view? Will the war stop
before removing regime? Unlikely. The
way I see it, the Americans will succeed
in the regime change operation. They are
just too powerful.
The Americans are simply too powerful.
Right? So has Iran blocked the state of
Hormuz? It obviously will attack Gulf
states who are handin glove with the US
from their perspective.
Has hormuz been been been closed.
Uh let let us let's see quickly see
what's happening. I'm going to take a
quick look at Twitter for a few minutes
and we'll let's take a look at this
together.
Um so my timeline best accounts and all
air India cancels flights to London
Toronto Frankfurt Paris Chicago flights
for 1st March list all so forth so
Dant's a and Mr. Modi is talking about
something else semiconductor stuff um
somebody is talking about Mr. Xang,
Professor Jang, Dubai has shut down. Al
Maktum International Airport has been
shut down. Emirates grounded. Okay. A
lot of AI slop you'll see. But it it
still gives you information this AI
slop.
Um what else? JD Vance.
You see the politicians doing their
flip-flops.
Uh Dr. J. Shank has a telecon with
Iranian foreign minister say basi this
evening.
shared India's deep concern about
whatever developments and so on. Okay.
Um
what else do we have? Bizarre discovery.
Okay, that's fine. Iranians soft Gulf
targets etc. What's Okay, what is
trending? Let's see. World War II is
trending trending.
Um what is this here?
Iranian drones strike Ira building in
Bahrain.
Oh, that's terrible visuals. What else
do we have? I don't know what that is.
What's What's happening in Thran? Okay.
Are you saying Hormuz has been shut
down? Let's see. Hormos.
Let us see. Has hormuz been shut down.
Iran warns Hormuz passage unsafe.
So, the straight is practically closed
with the IRGC warning vessels. It's
unsafe to transit. Okay.
Um,
okay. That will that will make oil
prices shoot up obviously.
Official closure. Okay. Hormones has
never been closed. We know that. Um.
Yeah. So, it's not officially closed
yet, but Iran is warning countries now
that hormones is dangerous. Essentially,
they are announcing the closure of
hormones, the straight of hormones.
uh that is going to be disastrous for
the global economy. It's going to make
oil prices shoot up massively. It's
going to be bad for India. It's going to
be bad for consumers in India. The
prices of your tomatoes and potatoes
will go up now.
Yeah.
So, um see Iran doesn't want to stop the
war at any cost. The government of Iran
wants to survive at any cost. Of course
they will, right? What do you expect?
Yeah, that's just natural. Uh, so will
the war stop before the regime is
changed? I think that's unlikely. Of
course, I could be wrong and good if I'm
wrong, but I think it's unlikely.
Kuru Renugu Renoku says great leader
came after 30 years India will be too
late. Great India coming after 30 years
for India will be too late as the world
order will stabilize by till then ne
past 15 years and upcoming five years
are crucial and we lose
uh
maybe it's a realistic way of looking at
things. The crucial time was the past 15
years. Crucial time is the next 5 years.
You you're right from you're right.
The crucial time is the next five years
and the work we should have done to
strengthen India and make India immune
to vasalization has not been done.
Let's see how it goes sir. Let's see how
it goes. Let us still be optimistic.
Ashtoh Nak says it's clear
you're a true expert in this niche. Your
confidence and knowledge make every
episode must listen. Thank you sir.
Thank you very much. I really appreciate
your very kind words. Thank you. Which
part of the United States are you living
in? I am not living in the United
States. I'm not. So, not in the US.
Okay.
All right. I'm living in India. I think
it's not some big secret that I'm living
in India, not in the US. Anyway, sir,
Ash, thank you very much. Thank you very
much indeed.
The Scorpion King says we should allow
dual citizenship so that the diaspora
does not lose connection with India.
with dual they their children will
always be connected with India. Look if
India hypothetically becomes a vasal.
I think we should welcome dual
citizenship
uh inner wealth hub. Thank you very much
sir. Thank you. Uh Gallor says hold on
we're talking about Y21. Y21 long range
anti-hship missile sircon happen to be
three novelties. US is incapacitated why
by defensively as well as offensively
can't retaliate sir they in their
infinite wisdom will continue dejà vu
polabber
um
the US is kind of behind in hypersonic
technology yeah we know that the tiron
is way more advanced than anything the
Americans have that is a frightfully
fast missile
right
is like Mac 9 12 I don't know
frightfully fast. It's It's not ramjet
technology. It's scramjet technology.
Um
yeah. So the US these these are some of
the things that that uh the US doesn't
have. That's it's kind of behind in
that.
So they in the infinite wisdom will
constru Pearl Harbor.
I'm not sure um
what the connection to Pearl Harbor is,
but I agree with you that the US is kind
of behind in these tech in especially in
hypersonics. Let me see. I think the
Americans do have some hypersonic
missile. Let's find out. Okay.
Does the US
US have hypersonic
missiles?
It does not have fully operational
fielded hypersonic missiles. But that's
that's yeah that's uh a drawback for the
US. Okay. So forget about intership. It
doesn't have any proper hypersonic
missiles. They are in the process of
developing and testing several programs
expected to be deployed by 2526. Well,
we are in 2526. We're in 26 now.
So yeah, that that's where the US is
behind. And I it's it's perplexing they
have allowed themselves to fall behind
in this manner. But yes, they are behind
and that's one of the you could say
Achilles heels of the US possibly. But
when it when it when you consider the
full
spectrum of the offensive capabilities
of the US, it is not that big of an
issue because they can still take out an
nation without having hypersonic
technology.
Okay, Pratiparo Roy is signing out for
the night. Thank you sir. Good night to
you as well. Thank you. Gira TV says,
"Sorry for the weird question. Why do US
missile explosions look like fireworks
while others just appear as dirty
fireballs? I've noticed this difference
in recent strikes in Venezuela and now
now Iran. So the strikes in Venez the US
hardly used any firepower in Venezuela.
I think they used some um
the US the firepower the US used in
Venezuela was mainly machine guns from
helicopters and maybe a missile or two
you know anti- anti-personal kind of
person kind of missiles one or two from
helicopters that's it the US basically
took Maduro without firing almost a
single shot
and the kind of explosions and and
visuals you see also depend on the frame
rate of your camera. If you use 24 frame
rate, you see it a certain way. If you
see 60 framework, 60 frames per second,
you're going to see, you know, um
explosions and and u
and and and the muzzle flashes of guns
very differently. So, it all depends a
lot of it depends on the kind of camera
you're using, what frame rate you're
using. um explosions look way richer
when you're using 24 frames per second.
They look very different with with atif
at 60 or 120 frames per second.
Um so there's a lot of factors that go
into this. It's a it's not a weird
question. It's a really interesting
question actually. Right. So it it
depends on on the cameras, it depends on
the frame rates. It depends on who's
filming it.
Uh a lot of people see a lot of these
videos they come out on social media.
And a lot of people when they use phones
they put the frame rate at 60 or
something. They believe that the higher
the frame rate the better the image you
get. And maybe some people use it for
shooting slow motion videos or whatever.
So that's why they keep the frame frame
rate at 60 or 120. Depends on the phone.
Some phones can't do 120. Some can. So
maybe a lot of people are are keeping
the frame rates very high. And maybe
that's that's causing um you know that's
affecting the the way the video turns
out to be very interesting question
actually. Dir Kamat says I think the
lack of proactive aggression by
idealistic kings of India after the rise
of nonvedic ains ideologies is something
we should blame them for. Why are we
always on the defensive?
Yeah. I mean ainsa see we have to
understand what is the relevance of
ainsa?
What is the relevance of a hinsa in
culture and society? A hinsa is relevant
when it comes to interpersonal
um interactions. Let's say you have a
dispute with somebody who is a citizen
of your own country. You don't want the
dispute to devolve into fighting and
killing, right? So when you have a
dispute with a with a citizen of your
country or with a member of a family,
you will use a hinsa obviously. But when
it comes to having a dispute with a
foreign country, you know, you don't
you're not under any obligation to use a
hinsa. So let's say you have Muhammad
Ghi invading your country and doing all
kinds of nasty stuff to your people. Do
you use a hinsa for for that person? Do
you say that the rules of warfare say I
cannot do these things? No. You kill the
guy. You you you deal with him. Your
objective is to win. But when you have
artificial rules that you use in warfare
that will put you at a disadvantage,
then you're stupid.
So um some of these issues have crept
into India into Indian society into the
mindset and worldview of Indians that we
I mean people ask me about humanity.
Mr. Modi should not have visited Israel
because of humanity. Who cares about
humanity in geopolitics? Does anyone
care? Does the US care about humanity?
Does China care about humanity? Why
should we take the contract of of of
worrying about humanity? We our prime
minister our leader has one job to look
out for the national interest of the
country and to look out for the
interests of the Indian people. That's
it.
So this ainsa thing and all these
matters they they have really messed up
India's mindset. Big problem.
Goautam
Goautam Verhma Dantaluri says despite
having great institutes with like with
brilliant doctors
why are we not contributing
significantly to research output because
we don't have great institutes most of
our inst institutes are great on paper
but they're actually trash
go to an IIT
the budget for IIT must be very high
right go to an IIT I'm not naming this
society or that I go to an IIT
visit the washroom to take a leak you
will see washroom is wonderful very
nicely maintained washroom very high
quality
glassware and whatnot go and see their
conference room very ultraodderern
conference room with air conditioning
the best projectors and expensive
equipment and all now go to the lab of
the IIT the equipment only 30 years old
that's the kind of approach we
That's an issue that plagues our
so-called great institutes. They're
great on paper. They have many eminent
scientists and re researchers. What
imminent work have they done? Actually,
I wonder. It's all on paper. India is a
nation of things being fantastic on
paper, but actually there's nothing of
any value that's happening there. The
majority of the these brilliant
so-called brilliant and eminent
scientists and doctors and whoever are
pedestrian mediocre people. The majority
of them some are great. Some are
brilliant. I'm not saying all are
mediocre. But those who are brilliant
and great, they are like fish out of
water because the environment is not
conducive for their their brilliance.
So there are these deeprooted problems
in India that are not being addressed at
all. They're all being overlooked,
brushed into the carpet and that's why
India remains a mediocre nation.
Ma sadong says take this as a token of
gratitude. I know many of the questions
are repeating and annoying but you
answer each one with equal enthusiasm.
Thank you so much Maong. Thank you so
much Ma. Okay. Thank you sir. Thank you
very much. Ever Joel Amin says share
some of your favorite books currently. I
currently I don't have any current
favorite books. I
I I don't know. Um favorite books
currently I'm not reading any current
favorite books. I may I'm thinking of
reading PG Woodhouse.
Should I? I don't know. What am I
reading right now? I'm reading Sherlock
Holmes
books. I it's not a good idea to ask me
out book recommendations unless I come
prepared because I have read so many
books in my life that they all get mixed
in my head and and no book stands out
for me as such. So currently I'm reading
Sherlock Holmes just revisiting it after
many many years that's one yeah
says is it bad for me to remind you to
watch Tumbad? Maybe it's a good
distraction for me to watch Dumbad
perhaps
based on how things are going and what's
happening in the world. So thank you for
the reminder sir.
Adita Aditia R says since the UAE can
bypass the straight of hormones blockade
using Fujira's port on the Gulf of Oman
do you think Iran will actively target
Fujira to ensure an old oil choke hold
is actually effective? They could. They
could. Let's let's take a look at the
map and let's figure out what exactly is
happening with Fuj.
It's one of the uh emirates, right?
Fuja. So here we have this.
This is the UAE
al is up here. Then you have Sharad, you
have Dubai, you have Abu Dhabi. Uh where
is Ajan?
So where is Fujay?
Pujira is here. So yeah it kind of uh
you can
you can bypass Hormos itself the state
of Hormones itself if because Puja is
out here in the Gulf of Oman
and yeah so you are correct
geographically it is not u it is kind of
not affected by any blockade of the
straight of Hormos but any military
action that's happening in the straight
of Hormos will most likely
you know affect
Fujira at least directly or indirectly.
Uh but let's say Iran wants to
completely blockade the state of H for
Hormos and ensure that there's no oil
coming out then they may definitely
target Fujira because Fuja is first of
all not very far away from Iran. It's
definitely within Iran's range or within
the range of Iran's navy missiles and so
on. Definitely. So they could do it.
They could do it. I'm not saying I'm not
advocating for this to happen, but Iran
could do that possibly. Yeah.
Okay, Black Panther says, "Energy, CM,
energy comes from oil and gas until US
spur power superpower." Your thoughts?
Energy come from oil and gas until US
superpower. My thoughts?
So, are you saying that the US will
ensure that as long as it's a
superpower, energy only comes from oil
and gas?
I don't know about that. It can't
prevent other nations from developing
new technologies, right?
So it's it's not a guarantee
and it oil and gas could be a finite
resource, right? Eventually the world
world may possibly run out of oil and
gas. It's a possibility.
Um so as long as the US superpower,
energy will only come from oil oil and
gas. It's not a guarantee. It's not a
guarantee.
Okay, looks like I have run out of
questions from the super chat. So let's
one more time take a look at what's
happening. Let me just take a look at at
Twitter. Give me a second.
Okay, let me open a new Twitter tab
fresh and let's see at what is
happening.
Give me a second. Is there something any
new development? Okay, we have highrise
in Bahrain.
Uh some controversy about Modi's Israel
visit. Okay, that's fine. Social media
backlash.
Joy Shankar World War II is being is
trending. Some cricket stuff is
trending.
Let's see. Thran, what is there?
Okay. Um,
yeah, nothing
very new.
Okay, maybe there'll be some more
developments later on, but I think we
can now at this time
call it a night for now.
So, let me end this live stream here.
Thank you very much everybody for your
questions and uh
let us see maybe I will do another
emergency live stream tomorrow depending
on how things go whether there are new
developments that affect us and so on.
So let's see about that. So all right
let me end this live stream over here
tonight. Thank you very much. It's been
five and a half hours blue. Thank you so
much for your questions. Keep learning.
Keep raising your standards and I'll see
you very soon in the next one. Take
care. Good night. Good day everyone.
Bye-bye.